Fugitive! Though the Republic
has won many decisive battles
against the Separatist army
in the Outer Rim,
the Jedi have failed
to capture the elusive General Grievous.
After specifically targeting members
of the Jedi Council, a trap was set,
but following a fierce confrontation,
the droid general managed to escape
to the surface of the planet Saleucami.
Now the chase is on
as General Kenobi leads a squadron
of clone troopers
and closes in on his desperate target.
We must find a way off this planet
before they find us.
Kenobi! We need to hurry
and find an escape pod.
Instead of scattering our troops
looking for all the escape pods,
we shall head towards the wreckage
of the landing transport first.
Contact the fleet.
Sir, our transmitter is destroyed.
There is only one escape pod
that survived.
We must get there as quickly as possible.
Let's hope the transmitter is still intact.
Now, find me some transportation.
General Kenobi!
Sir, the cruiser's returned to orbit.
- Any sign of Grievous?
- I believe we've found Grievous' ship.
Power low.
The power is...
I can't go on.
Sir, we need to get our power recharged.
Not this again. How could your power cells
be so depleted?
You would not let us ride
on one of those creatures with you, sir.
If you would allow us to close down
for a few...
Any more complaints?
- No. Nope. No.
- No. I don't think so.
That's what I thought.
Now, let's find that pod.
Yikes.
Thermal housing intakes are still warm.
This couldn't have happened too long ago.
The crew compartment's
almost entirely destroyed.
We'll split into teams.
Rex, take Jesse, Hardcase and Kix
and search those wetlands.
Yes, sir.
Crys and I will pick it up
from here.
And, Rex, if you get a visual on Grievous,
contact us before you engage.
- Rex is a smart man.
- Indeed. Always thinking on his feet.
These droids are too gone
to give us any good intel.
Here's one!
Take the shot.
Protect the Captain!
Commando droids.
Jesse, you better get back here.
What do you have?
We've broken the access codes and
powered up the droid's guidance system.
According to his memory logs,
he fired the emergency thrusters
on the escape pod
to avoid a midair collision.
- Collision with what?
- Another escape pod.
There was no time to correct
for the steeper glide path,
which is why this droid's pod crashed.
Can you pinpoint the landing zone
for the other pod?
I can put us
within two to three clicks of it, sir.
Alert the men. We've picked up the scent.
- How bad?
- Pretty bad.
I need to remove his armor
to see the full extent of the damage.
Those snipers might have called
for backup.
Unless we want
to start getting picked off one by one,
- we should find better cover first.
- Mmm-hmm.
Wait a minute.
Those critters are domesticated.
- Sir?
- I think we're on farmland.
And where there's a farm,
there's usually a farmer.
Let's find his homestead.
We want no trouble here.
Easy with that weapon, ma'am.
We're here as friends.
- State your business.
- Our captain's been hurt. We need...
- I'm no doctor, so just...
We have a medic, ma'am.
We just need a place
to tend to him overnight.
- Mommy, who's...
- Get back inside, both of you!
Oh!
Mom!
Look, there are some benches
out back in the barn.
- It's the best I can do.
- That'll be fine, ma'am. Thank you.
What... What happened?
Commando droids took a potshot.
That would've gone straight through your
heart had it been two inches to the left.
- I can't move my arm.
- You have some nerve damage.
Understood. Now patch me up,
and let's get on with it.
Sir, you're in no condition.
It will heal, but it will take time.
We're getting
underway, Kix.
- That's an order.
- Sir, as the team medic,
when it comes to the health of the men,
including you,
I outrank everyone.
So I respectfully order you, sir,
- to get some...
- Excuse me.
- If there's not enough...
- That's plenty. Thank you, uh...
Suu.
I told you to stay in the house.
I couldn't help it, Mom. It got away.
- You look like my daddy.
- Shaeeah, don't bother the soldier.
- Now get inside with your brother.
- Yes, Mom.
My husband is away
delivering our first harvest.
- Do you require anything else?
- No.
- Thank you, Suu.
- Mmm.
Resume the search without me.
Jesse, you're in command. I'll be fine.
There's our escape pod.
- Any sign of Grievous?
It looks deserted.
He must be heading
to a second escape pod.
- Captain Rex, come in, please.
- It's Jesse, sir.
- Rex was injured.
- What's his condition?
He'll be fine. But we had
to find him shelter for the night.
Grievous is on the move.
We're headed to the west.
Swing around and we can meet up
at the final escape pod.
We're going to need all the firepower
we can muster.
Roger that, sir.
We're speeding towards you.
No, no, no, no, no.
We should be there by now.
We are, sir,
there almost.
You had better be interpreting
the coordinates correctly.
Oh, no.
We're almost there, sir. One click out.
Straight ahead.
I'm losing power.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
You're a clone.
So, I see the war has finally made its way
out here.
And I guess I can expect a visit
from some droids soon.
What's your number and rank?
My name is Lawquane. Cut
Lawquane. And I'm just a simple farmer.
You're a deserter.
Well,
I like to think I'm merely
exercising my freedom to choose.
- To choose not to kill for a living.
- That is not your choice to make.
You swore an oath to the Republic.
You have a duty.
I have a duty. You're right.
But it's to my family.
Does that count,
or do you still plan to turn me in?
Do I have a choice?
Daddy, you're home!
Look what I drew you, Dad!
Well, well, well.
That's great, Jek.
I see you two have met.
He looks just like you, Daddy. I told him.
Oh, you did, huh?
I was just making our guest, Captain, um...
What's your number?
Rex. I also have a name, believe it or not.
He was injured. His men brought him here.
I told them he could stay just for the night.
Course he can.
We never turn away those in need, do we?
No, we always help anyone we can.
Right. You, um... You look hungry, Rex.
- No, I'm fine. I'll stay here.
- No, you have to eat with us, please!
- Please! Please!
Please!
They're never gonna stop till you say yes.
All right, I'll join you.
Yes, well, you and I may be clones,
but we're still individuals.
You have a name rather than a number,
Captain. Why is that?
Perhaps our leaders feel it's
a more efficient way of distinguishing us.
More efficient than a number?
I doubt the Kaminoans think that way.
Still, a name has to make you feel unique.
Especially in an army where everyone
looks like you and talks like you...
Actually, I've never really thought about it.
- Yes, you have.
- Well, how would you know?
Because I am as close to you
as any life form can be.
I've seen how you look
at my family, our home...
Come on, Rex, admit it. You've thought
about what your life could look like
if you were to also leave the army,
choose the life you want.
What if I am choosing the life I want?
What if I'm staying in the army
because it's meaningful to me?
And how is it meaningful?
Because I'm part of the most pivotal
moment in the history of the Republic.
If we fail,
then our children and their children
could be forced to live
under an evil I can't well imagine.
If you were to have children, of course.
But that would be against the rules,
wouldn't it?
Isn't that what somebody
programmed you to believe, Captain?
No, Cut, it's simply what I believe.
It doesn't matter if it's my children
or other people's children.
Does that meet with your approval?
Perfectly. To each his own.
That's what I always say.
What does that mean, Daddy?
It means you can do anything
with your life that you want to.
- How are you doing, Jesse?
- Closing in, sir. We have a visual.
Very well, we'll meet you in the middle.
- Is your transmitter working?
- I don't know. I haven't used it yet.
All right, I'll check on it.
Stupid battle droids!
Sir, you made it.
Get back in the pod
and send out a distress signal
to what's left of our fleet.
We need to get a shuttle
down here immediately.
Roger, roger, but I must inform you, sir,
there are multiple life forms approaching
from the east and west.
Battle positions!
Good move. Very good move.
- So what was it?
- What made me decide to leave the corps?
Shortly after the Battle of Geonosis,
our troop transport got caught
between two Separatist gunships.
They fired on us with everything they had.
We crashed.
Most of us were either dead
or severely injured.
So when they started working their way
through the wounded, killing us off,
I knew there was no hope. I ran.
It still haunts me.
I'm sorry.
It's the day I felt
my life didn't have any meaning.
Everyone I cared about,
my team, was gone.
I was just another expendable clone
waiting for my turn
to be slaughtered in a war
that made no sense to me.
Can you understand that, Rex?
I've been in countless battles
and lost many brothers.
They were my family, my home.
Daddy, we finished our chores.
Can we go outside and play?
Please.
- Okay, only for a few minutes.
- Thank you, Daddy! Come on, Jek.
Okay.
- And keep the house in view.
We will.
You have wonderful children.
I know you think I'm a coward, Rex.
But believe me, I'll fight to my last breath
to keep them safe.
Fire!
Tank two! Port side!
Great shot!
Where is that ship?
Shaeeah? Where are you?
Shaeeah, where are you?
Stop fooling around.
Boo!
- You're not funny.
- Am too!
- Look. In the field.
- What is it?
It wasn't there before.
It's some kind of spaceship, I think.
Hello?
Do you think
somebody's in there?
Uh-oh.
I didn't do it. You did it.
Run!
- Run! Run! Run!
- Monsters! Run! Run!
Monsters!
- Shaeeah? Jek? What's wrong?
- Monsters! They're chasing us!
What monsters, honey? Where?
They hatched from the big egg in the field!
Ah. This is not good. I count 20.
- Cut, what's out there?
- Commando droids.
What are they doing?
- Suu, get the kids upstairs.
- Come. Come, children. Come now!
What weapons do you have?
We can catch them in a crossfire.
You take that corner.
No, Captain.
With respect, you're not in charge here.
I can be useful.
Sir, you're injured.
You have only one good arm.
- But I can fight.
- So can I.
Rex, I need you
to be the last line of defense for my family.
- I'll take care of them.
- Thank you.
Finally!
General Grievous, sir. We see you
below us. Are you ready to depart?
Concentrate your fire on that ship!
Hey! They're shooting at us!
Coming back around.
Sir, that ship's coming around
for another landing attempt.
Keep firing! Don't let that ship land.
- The guns are overheated!
- Always something.
Cody, Jesse, cover me.
General, behind you!
Rex, they're coming for you!
Daddy? Daddy?
I'm okay. It's over.
No!
Forget trying to land.
Fire the engines.
Jedi scum!
- Are you all right, sir?
- No. We're right back where we started.
Call the cruisers.
See if they can stop that ship.
Right away, sir!
And tell them to send someone
to pick us up.
All right, that should do it.
Captain Rex, are you going
to turn in my husband?
I'm sorry, Suu, it's my duty.
But in my condition,
I probably won't remember any of this.
Thank you.
You're still a deserter, Cut,
but you're certainly not a coward.
Captain Rex,
are you still with us?
Yes, General Kenobi. I'm still with you
and thankfully on the mend, sir.
That's great news.
We certainly missed you at the party.
Sorry, sir. I had to attend one of my own.
Can't wait to hear about it.
We're standing by.
- You're welcome to stay, Rex.
- This is your home, Cut.
My family is elsewhere.
- Goodbye!
- Bye!
- Bye-bye!