Battle for Ringo Vinda.
Republic forces are locked in
heated combat with the droid armada
on a massive space station
that encircles an entire planet.
Anakin Skywalker valiantly
leads his men against the onslaught,
which has lasted several rotations,
with neither side gaining any ground.
Aided by the twin sister Jedi Masters,
Tiplee and Tiplar,
the Republic now mounts
a desperate offensive
to break the deadlock.
Push forward!
Stay to my left.
- Fives! Watch out!
Thanks, brother, I owe you one.
You owe me a lot more than one.
Tighten our flank!
- Shields up!
- Yes, sir!
Don't get too comfortable.
This battle hasn't been won yet.
Master Skywalker,
we must get to the command post.
Admiral Trench has sent
for reinforcements.
We must take this post
before they arrive.
It's time for phase two.
We're at this position.
Tiplar, you'll take your men
down this passageway.
Tiplee, you'll move along here.
They'll have to divide their forces
to counter us.
And when they do,
Rex and I will press through the middle.
If we time it right, we'll all converge
on this spot at the same time,
and the droids won't know
what hit them.
If we're
making a run, we'll need backup.
My men are severely depleted.
Fives, you and Tup take
ten of your best men
and support Master Tiplar.
We're on it, sir.
Hey, you all right?
Yeah, I... I just...
Come on, this is a textbook battle.
We've run through this
a million times before in training.
Yeah, I know... I just...
I don't feel like myself.
What do you mean?
Follow me.
Jedi.
Tup? What's the matter with you?
Uh, no... Nothing. I'm fine.
Come on, brother.
Don't want to be left behind.
Increase our defenses.
We must hold them here.
Don't fall back! Push forward!
Tup! Hey!
This is not the time to freeze up!
Pull it together! We're almost
to the finish line! Come on!
Jedi...
Good soldiers follow orders.
Hey, Tup!
On your right!
Tup! No!
Sister!
Hold your position!
Destroyers!
We've lost our momentum! Fall back!
Fives, I don't know what's going on,
but you are responsible for Tup now.
Get him back to base. I want answers.
The Jedi
have withdrawn their forces.
Contact Count Dooku immediately.
I have something
he'll be very interested in.
Count Dooku,
the Republic forces are in full retreat.
But this is not why
you have contacted me, is it?
No, Count, in truth the Republic had
pushed my droids to the breaking point,
when they suddenly turned
and fell back.
It seemed that
at the height of the conflict,
a clone turned on his Jedi General
and executed her.
Intentionally?
I saw it with my own eyes.
I have studied clones and fought
against them in many battles.
This action is unlike anything I have
witnessed in their behavior as soldiers.
So, there is a traitor in their midst.
It's rare, but such things
have been reported in the past.
Not a traitor, this was different.
It seemed...
Yes, Admiral?
It seemed as if the clone
could not help himself,
as if he was entranced.
Thank you, Admiral.
I will take this under advisement.
Why? Why would he do this?
I'm about to find out.
How's he doing, Rex?
I'm not sure, General.
It seems like he just snapped.
Tup, can you hear me?
- Yes, Captain.
- What happened?
What do you mean?
Do you have any idea
what you've done?
Good soldiers follow orders.
What is he talking about?
I have no idea.
Kill the Jedi.
We have to get him back
to the medical bay
before he hurts anyone else.
My Lord, I have received a
report that leads me to conclude
we may have encountered
a grave complication
with one of our assets.
Assets?
Yes, sir. A clone trooper has
executed one of the Jedi Generals.
And you believe this is indicative
of our programming?
I do, My Lord. But I cannot be certain.
It is pertinent we ascertain
if this is an isolated event,
a failure in this particular
clone's programming.
Otherwise my plans may be ruined.
Seize the clone immediately.
Yes, My Master.
Fives, what's happening to me?
You don't remember?
No.
You murdered General Tiplar.
What? No, that's not possible.
I would never... I could never...
Tup, you did.
I don't... I don't understand.
How could this happen?
What's happening to me, Fives?
Ahh!
No! No! No...
What do you think happened?
Did you check all of his scans?
Well, all of his scans are clear.
As far as I can tell,
this is a combat-related stress.
It's seems he's had
some sort of breakdown.
Kix, you should know better.
We were designed
to withstand any stress.
I agree.
We've been through a lot together.
He doesn't seem
to remember what happened.
It's like he's sick, or drugged.
Well, it could be a virus, a toxin.
I can't be certain.
Let's talk outside.
You mean the enemy could have
made him do this?
It's a possibility.
There have been rumors
that Separatists have been trying
to develop an anti-clone virus.
Biological warfare.
Listen, we aren't equipped
for this type of situation.
He'll have to be taken back to Kamino.
Only then will you have your answer.
Wait! Wait!
Tup, it's gonna be fine. I promise.
They'll fix you up real good.
We'll be having
a drink together in no time, eh?
Good soldiers follow orders.
You are a good soldier, Tup.
It's time to go now.
Be careful.
Yes, General.
We are tracking clean, calculating
hyperspace jump in five, four...
- Oh, wait! Wait!
Scanners indicate incoming craft.
Abort jump!
Mayday! Mayday!
The enemy cut us off!
They must have
circled around behind us.
We're being overwhelmed. Ahh!
Can't let 'em in here!
Hold that line.
Here they come.
Blast them!
General Skywalker,
you are nearing the coordinates
where we lost contact with the shuttle.
We can see it now.
It doesn't look good.
Looks like some buzz droids
got on the hull and opened her right up.
Hmm, strategically, this attack
doesn't make any sense.
Unless they were
after something specific.
- Tup...
- I'm going over there.
We're coming with you.
Over here.
This is Tup's gurney.
The restraints have been cut.
The clankers took Tup? Why?
They must be responsible
for whatever's happening to him.
It's possible.
All I know is they went to great lengths
to capture him.
And that means something.
We have got to get him back.
Don't worry.
We'll find a way.
We have captured
the clone, Count.
- Good work, Admiral.
Send him to me immediately,
and under all circumstances,
keep him alive!
Yes, sir.
Get him on the next shuttle out of here.
But the Republic blockade...
See to it personally, Commander.
It will be just the three of us going in.
The shuttle will drop us off
just short of the main hanger,
then we spacewalk from there.
Are you picking anything up
on Tup's locator?
I've got a faint signal,
but it's hard to track. It's moving.
Then we better hurry.
I've got a better signal.
Tup is heading this way.
They're moving him
to the hangar.
Are your scopes Jedi-issue, sir?
- Stay focused, Fives.
There he is, sir.
We'll have to work fast.
There must be a hundred
droids in that hangar,
not to mention the starfighters.
This is stretching it, even for you, sir!
Rex, you're beginning
to sound like Obi-Wan.
You got a better idea?
Look, I don't doubt
you could pull it off,
but I'm just not sure Fives and I
would be around to see it happen.
- I've got an idea.
- Well, let's hear it, quickly!
Grappling gun. Good thinking.
Get ready to hold on.
That's why he's the ARC Trooper.
Is there a problem?
We were experiencing some
drag but the sensors are stabilized now.
You were experiencing drag
in the vacuum of space?
Yeah, strange.
But it is gone now.
Scrap them!
Hey, now we're
experiencing turbulence.
What's going on?
What do you know about this clone?
I am programmed to resist intimidation.
Fine.
How's he doing?
Not well. Not well at all.
I think he's dying, sir.
We have to get him to Kamino.
I'll want a full report
from Kamino.
If Tup is the victim
of some Separatist plot,
we have no idea
of how widespread it already is.
Permission to
come with you, sir.
He's my best friend.
You may need help.
But everything must
be done by the book.
Understood, sir.
You're to stay by his side at all times.
I don't want any more slip-ups.
- Yes, sir.
- Good. Let's go.
Medical frigate 517,
you are cleared for departure.
Good luck, boys.