Mystery on Bardotta!
An oasis of peace
during the Clone Wars.
The galaxy-wide conflict now threatens
the ancient ways
of the Bardottan people.
With their spiritual leaders
mysteriously vanishing,
the foundations of order in its system
are near collapse.
In desperation, the Queen of Bardotta
has called upon the Republic Senate
with a puzzling request, to help save
her people from certain doom.
I have humbly come before you
to ask for assistance
in our time of need, Chancellor.
Queen Julia, the Republic is honored
that you have come to us for aid.
We are always happy to support
the neutral systems in a time of crisis.
If I may introduce
two of our best ambassadors...
With all due respect, Chancellor,
there is only one person
in the Republic I will meet with.
Representative Binks?
Why would the Queen of Bardotta
request the presence of Jar Jar Binks?
I'm afraid
she would not say,
but she impressed upon the Senate
the urgency of their situation.
And what exactly is the trouble
on Bardotta?
Several of the ancient mystics,
the Dagoyan Masters,
have disappeared.
A strong connection to the Force
the Dagoyan Masters have.
Yet, unlike the Jedi or Sith they are.
Warriors, they are not.
Intuition, knowledge, the harmony
of the universe is what they sense.
Passively they connect with the Force.
I wonder why the Queen doesn't want
a Jedi sent to solve this mystery?
Long ago inducted into the Jedi Order
Bardottan children were.
However, thieves the Jedi
were named by the Dagoyan.
The Dagoyan Masters believed the Jedi
took the children against their will,
we were labeled as kidnappers.
Chancellor, am I to understand
the Queen requested.
Representative Binks
go alone to Bardotta?
I'm afraid she was quite specific
on that point.
I think that course of action is unwise.
If there is trouble on Bardotta,
I'm afraid Representative Binks will be
out of his depth.
I agree, which is why I came to you.
We await your decision.
Are you volunteering to undertake
this mission, Master Windu?
If the Council agrees, yes.
Do not touch anything.
Oh, Mesa not doin' nothin'.
Representative Binks,
I do not mean to be presumptuous,
but are you sure you are the delegate
the Queen spoke of?
Yup! The Queen is mesa pallo.
Mesa knowin' her for a longo time.
The Queen did not request
your presence, Jedi!
Your lightsaber please.
Mesa Representative Binks
of the Republic Senate
and hesa with mesa.
Representative Binks, you are an
honored guest of the Queen. Come!
Representative Binks of the Republic,
you were requested to come here alone,
why have you brought this Jedi
to Bardotta?
Oh, Great Queenie Julia,
please forgive mesa.
Disa Jedi is mesa pallo,
hesa comin' here to be helpin'
mesa solve your troubles.
He is your servant, then?
Umm...
Yes! Yes! Dat is the truth,
Masterin Mace is mesa humble servant.
Very well. Jedi, because
Jar Jar Binks vouches for you,
I will allow you to stay here.
For now, you must wait
in the antechamber.
Jar Jar, we are in danger.
An ancient prophecy is coming true.
Our beloved Dagoyan Masters
are disappearing one by one,
and if they are not returned,
a darkness will arise
that will engulf the galaxy.
Mesa not lettin' that happen, milady.
High Seneschal Peteen, I must speak
to Representative Binks alone.
It's been a long time, my love.
Come, meditate with me,
so our minds may be as one.
There is a great disturbance
in the Force here, that much is certain.
- I can sense it all around me.
- Hmm...
Difficult to see, such disdain
for the Jedi there is on Bardotta,
a good place for evil to hide it may be.
Yet remember, drifting within the flow
of the living Force,
the minds of the Dagoyan Masters are,
essential this connection is, whether
friend to the Jedi they be, or not.
Hmm. If you are looking for a friend
of the Bardottan's,
look no further than
Representative Binks.
The Queen has been alone with him
for quite some time now.
The innocence of a child
this Gungan has,
perhaps appealing
to the Dagoyan his mind is.
Well, my mind will be more at ease
if I knew what they've been up to.
I am here to see Representative Binks.
The Queen said no interruptions.
Jar Jar, I asked you here
because I trust you,
because I know you will be able
to help me in ways others cannot.
Mesa hopin' so, milady.
You will let me inside.
You should know better, Master Jedi.
That will not work on a Dagoyan.
I have discovered a terrible secret
buried within the rippling waves
of the Force.
Uh...
Maybe itsa best to get
Masterin Mace to hear this?
No, Jar Jar, only you. I must tell you,
I cannot trust the Jedi with this secret.
When the Dagoyan Masters
started disappearing,
I meditated to try and discover
their whereabouts,
but what I saw was shocking.
I stumbled upon a terrible plot.
- Excuse the intrusion, Your Majesty.
I will not excuse you, where are
the guards? Who told you to enter?
The guards had other business
to tend to.
We apologize, Your Majesty,
the Jedi slipped past us.
You see, Jar Jar,
these Jedi are deceptive, as I said!
Julia Queenie,
but yousa let mesa handle dis,
I promise da Jedi Masterin Mace
will besa no trouble for you.
Very well, Jar Jar,
take him out of my sight,
I will wait right here for you.
Oh! Careful!
What do you think you're doing?
Where were you last night?
Doing? Mesa love da Queen Julia.
Whatsa wrong with dat?
You are jeopardizing the mission.
No, no, Masterin Jedi!
Mesa love for beautiful Julia
is da only thing startin' the talks.
Shesa trustin' only mesa.
Oh, and now yousa, a little.
You must understand, Jar Jar,
the Force is strangely
out of balance here.
Did the Queen
tell you anything important?
Dats what she was tryin' to do
before yousa come in all hot like.
Take this. Since they seem to want
to keep us separated,
contact me if you learn anything useful.
Okie-day, Masterin Mace,
but only if Queenie thinks
it's all right to tell you.
Masterin Mace, come quickly!
Shesa gone! Queenie is gone!
Calm yourself, Binks.
Disin bad, very, very bad!
She has disappeared. Like the other
Dagoyan Masters before her.
But it's not possible, no one could have
left this room without our knowing it.
I will convene
the Bahk-tov council, come!
Guards! Bahk-tov toil.
There can be no doubt!
The prophecy is being fulfilled,
as it was written.
First the Dagoyan Masters disappeared
and now the Queen.
If she does not return in three rotations,
I'm afraid she will be gone forever
and an era of Darkness
will rise throughout the galaxy.
Distinguished Council if I may...
The coming of the Jedi was a sign!
It was a sign! Harbinger of doom!
Harbinger of doom!
Council! Oh, great Bardotta Council.
Please, yousa must listen to mesa.
Queenie Julia was me bombad pallo
for many years.
Shesa knew there be troubles here.
Dats why she callin' mesa,
to helpin' in your time of need.
Mesa takin' my loyal helper
Masterin Mace,
and we findin' da Queenie
and bringin' her backin' to yousa!
Ask them the origin of the prophecy.
Now, let mesa askin' yousa
where dis prophecy comin' from?
They are the words
of the Frangawl clan,
who worshipped Malmourral,
the ancient demon of our faith.
Their ancient shrine is located
under our present-day Temple,
far beneath the surface.
It is a cursed place, an evil place,
no one who enters those caverns
ever returns.
Then that is where we must look first.
Den dats where we be goin' first!
Oh, boy, disin gonna be
bombad trouble, mesa knowin' it.
Um, uh, are yousa sure
disa the right way?
Yes, but ahead there is only darkness,
and evil.
Then yes, Jar Jar,
this is the correct path.
Okay. Mmm...
Here's your weapon Master Jedi.
Let us hope you do not have to use it.
The Frangawl ruled Bardotta
with an iron hand
for most of its early history.
They were warriors.
Some would call them barbarians,
but in fact they were men
and women of spirit.
Mesa no likin' this place, no way.
Look! A piece of the
Queenie Julia's headdress!
Oh, no! Mesa disappearin'!
Mesa disappearin'!
Masterin Mace!
Help! Masterin Mace!
Masterin Mace, help!
Jar Jar!
He's been taken just like the Queen.
You go back and get help,
I'll go after him.
Put mesa down,
put mesa down!
Wheresa yousa taking me?
Put mesa down!
Thanks goodness.
Mesa can see mesa self again.
Whosa yousa, sir?
I am Joseph.
Dagoyan Master of the Royal Council.
The others you see with me
also have been disappeared
and brought here.
You'll never free yourself.
We are doomed to be sacrificed
to Malmourral.
This is bombad trouble.
Jar Jar! Where are you? Jar Jar!
- Oh!
Masterin Mace! Masterin Mace!
Mesa found the disappearen
Daba-boy-boy-ogans.
I'll follow your signal.
Wherever you are, don't move!
Datsa no problem.
Mesa not goin' nowheres.
Uh-oh.
Mesa movin'! Mesa movin'!
I told you not to do that, Jar Jar!
It's not mesa fault!
Masterin Mace!
Quiet!
Hmm.
Julia!
Jar Jar!
Mesa here to rescue yousa!
Jar Jar. They are stealing the Force.
They are stealing the Force within us.
Now shall
the demon of war,
Malmourral, be sated!
Now shall the Frangawl clan
steal your essence!
No!
Whosa you? Let mesa go! Let mesa go!
Let mesa go! No!
Let mesa go! Let mesa go!
Nosa tickling! Issa cold!
Blasphemer!
Uh, Mesa not big with the Force.
Yousa got the wrong Gungan.
The Force resides
within all living things.
What little you have will be ours.
Jar Jar!
Huh?
Get him!
Stay back. Mesa bombad warrior.
Get mesa outta here.
Look out!
Grab my hand!
Mesa need to
save the Queenie!
Go!
The demonic cult of
Malmourral is active once again.
If they steal the essence of the Queen,
darkness will fall across the stars.
Mesa no bombad warrior, but
mesa swearen to find yousa Queenie
with the help of mesa bombad pallo
Masterin Mace!
Jar Jar, maybe it's this place,
but you're starting to make sense to me!