War in the Inner Rim!
Rebel leader Steela Gerrera
has joined forces
with General Tandin
after boldly rescuing.
Onderon's former king from execution,
evading a trap set
by Separatist ally King Rash
and the droid general Kalani.
Amid growing public support
and rising unrest,
Ahsoka continues to monitor
the rebels' efforts
as they rally around Ramsis Dendup
to restore his reign
as the rightful king
and finally put an end
to the Separatist occupation
of Onderon.
I'm picking up
an electromagnetic field.
Roger, roger.
It's coming from there.
Whoa!
My fellow subjects,
I appear not as your king
but as a servant of Onderon.
We are in the midst
of a great struggle.
The Confederacy has used
the recent attacks
as an opportunity to tighten
their hold on Onderon.
They have accused me of leading
these so-called terrorists.
It is a lie they have engineered
to further restrict your independence
and use deadly force
against our people.
The truth is, I have never
met them before now.
I have come to know them
as the true sons of Onderon.
They are unwilling
to surrender our freedom
to those who conspire
to take it from us.
Our destiny is tied to them
and this planet.
We must all rise together
to protect it.
Uh-oh.
Why are they looking at us that way?
Hey!
What the? Blast them!
Ahh!
Uh-oh.
The people are
turning against the droids.
There's rioting in the streets now.
That's a beautiful thing.
We need to keep the battle
to the outskirts of the city.
Less structures and people.
But less clankers.
Their main force is in Iziz.
We should join the fight down there
and take it straight to King Rash.
We all want victory, but not
at the cost of innocent lives.
If we fight door to door,
no one is safe.
This is war, Steela.
She's right.
I agree.
The more you draw the droids
from the city to the highlands,
the safer the people will be.
My men await your command, my Lord.
I believe there is a new contender.
You will lead our forces,
including the Royal Army.
Steela is now the commanding general.
A great choice.
As you wish, my Lord.
You and your rebels
renewed my faith in myself.
Now I'm putting my faith in you.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Let's ride.
Just in case.
We are losing the public.
If they turn against us,
I fear the outcome.
Fear will bring them back.
We must eliminate Dendup,
General Tandin,
and the terrorists
before the people
commit to their efforts.
General Tandin is weak.
His army will not withstand
the power of the Confederacy.
Neither will the terrorists.
General, our scouts have
located the main rebel forces
in the mountains to the east.
With the rioting in the city,
how can we spare the troops
to attack the rebels in the mountains?
Do not underestimate our means.
If the rebel army falls,
the citizens will lose their courage,
and order will be restored.
Your target lies
in the mountains to the east.
The army will follow.
Leave no survivors. Go.
By your command.
The droid army is almost here.
Everyone, get ready.
Ready.
Saw, begin your attack.
Yah!
Ahh!
No!
Where did that come from?
There.
Any ideas?
Yeah. Run!
Ahh!
I take it the rebels
have Dooku's full attention.
It's a full-scale war.
They need our help.
Please talk to the Council.
Even Master Windu
would be wary at this point.
The Council will not
engage or involve the Republic
in an internal affair.
The Separatists have a new gunship
with a powerful ray shield.
Nothing's getting past it.
I am sorry, Ahsoka.
They will have to find a way.
Do not stay there
if their failure is certain.
Evacuate who you can and return
to Coruscant immediately.
Do you understand?
Yes, Master.
We need to help them.
We will do what we can
to relocate the survivors.
Before they lose their planet.
We can't.
What difference does it make now?
The Separatists know we're involved.
I don't disagree with you, Anakin,
but to send in Republic gunships
defeats our purpose.
We must stay true to our intentions,
learn our lessons.
It doesn't have to look like
we're the ones helping.
What if another party was involved?
Another party?
Who in the galaxy
would be running around
with an extra batch of missiles?
Hondo.
Is the Republic going to help us?
No.
What's it going to take?
King Rash rules Onderon.
Unless that changes,
the Republic can't do anything.
They're pulling back.
Cover them.
At this rate, the clankers
aren't going to need reinforcements.
We have to regroup at the nest.
Yah!
Skywalker, my old friend.
You come alone?
For your service.
Oh, business!
Good, good, good.
That I understand.
I need you to make a delivery for me.
And that all I am to you, Jedi?
A delivery boy?
I know that if I need arms
shipped illegally,
you're the man I need to go to.
Illegally?
Now, why would a Jedi need
to deliver arms illegally?
How about I pay you well enough
that you just deliver
the missiles for me
and don't ask any questions?
Well, as long as you're not
paying me in credits,
I'm sure I could accommodate
your wishes, Master Jedi.
The highlands may slow down
the droids,
but they won't stop the gunships.
We have to move.
Any word from Master Skywalker?
Not yet.
We're not giving up yet.
Stagger our defenses to the camp.
Secure the approach.
Stay in small teams.
Make use of our training.
You really are
the best leader among us.
Couldn't be more proud
of you, my sister.
I learned from the best, big brother.
Let's go, General.
You have to help us.
I'll do all I can to protect you,
but I can't fight this war for you.
We wouldn't have made it
this far without you.
I wish I could do more.
Wait.
Looks like we have company.
Don't shoot!
Well, you could be
my new favorite spice.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Careful, pirate.
Hondo, what are you doing here?
Oh, no, no, no.
You should thank me, child.
I have brought you a gift
from Skywalker and Kenobi.
The latest from Sienar.
Rocket launchers?
Shoulder-fired. Very expensive.
Paid for?
Very handsome...
Oh! Oh, my, look at the time.
Well, my work here is done.
Ugh, they must have seen Hondo's ship.
It was only a patrol.
We have to get these
down to the others.
Load them up.
I hope they work.
There's only one way to find out.
We've tried everything,
but we're target practice
for those gunships.
Now it's their turn.
Thank the Jedi.
Saw!
I love this!
Distribute the rocket launchers
and take out those gunships.
Steela, they're attacking the nest.
They're after the king!
Come on!
She sure leads by example.
What good will that do us
if she gets herself killed?
Steela, hurry! Steela, come in!
Ugh!
Where is the false king?
I'll never tell you!
Ugh!
Find the king.
Help has arrived!
Are you all right, Your Majesty?
Thanks to you.
Fire!
Last one's mine.
Get down!
Look!
Hang... on!
Steela!
Ah!
I'll handle this.
I got you.
Your gunships have failed.
I need more reinforcements.
Really?
General Kalani, what is your
assessment of the situation?
They have managed
to penetrate our shields
and are using the cover
of the highlands
against our forces.
To defeat them will take time.
A prolonged war does not
interest me, General.
Their rebellion grows
with every small victory.
Then we are lost.
Salvage the remaining arms
and withdraw the army.
Bring them to Agamar.
What about...
Ugh!
It was my fault.
I shot that gunship down,
and it crashed into her position.
Saw, it's not your fault.
She knew what the risks were.
We all knew what it would take
to free Onderon.
This has been quite a journey
for our Padawan.
Steela will be a powerful
spirit in their lives.
Yes.
For all of us.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Thanks, but it's over now.
Let's just leave it at that.
Steela would be glad.
Her sacrifice gave Onderon
its freedom.
But at what cost?
It's like you once said.
Many lives get caught
between the Republic
and the Separatists.
I did say that once,
but after watching your heroics
and the selflessness of the Jedi,
I do believe the Republic
is the right side to be on.
What do you mean?
Dendup has appointed me
the new Senator of Onderon.
I will follow
in my mother's footsteps,
and I will bring us back
to the Republic.
Remember this day,
the day Onderon became free again.