Abandoned!
After an assassination attempt by
his forsaken apprentice, Asajj Ventress,
Count Dooku launches
a brutal counterattack
against the Nightsisters,
massacring the entire clan.
Forced into exile, Ventress wanders
far into the Outer Rim,
among the castaways
and vagabonds of the galaxy,
seeking her new life that
was foretold by Mother Talzin.
Prow. Straight up.
Another.
Hey, there.
What's a pretty bald babe like you
doing in a desert like this?
Get lost.
Hey! I'm talkin' to you, lady.
I'm not much of a talker.
Uh, compliments of the lizard in the back.
What do you want?
I'm Bossk and this is Latts Razzi.
- We're bounty hunters, and...
- We have a problem.
Hmm.
What kind of problem?
You just killed one of our team.
Sorry about that.
So where did you get the lightsabers?
Stole them.
Bounty hunter, then?
No.
Ever considered it?
You certainly have the right.
Disposition.
Never thought about it. Does it pay well?
Very well.
We have a job to do and you owe us a man.
Join our merry band of bounty hunters,
or we turn you over to the authorities.
What do I have to do?
Hey, Bossk, who's your girlfriend?
Shut up, Dengar.
Hey, boss.
"Boss." This is your boss?
You got a problem with that?
My name's Boba, and this is Highsinger.
I see you've already met Bossk and Latts.
What's your name?
I don't have a name.
So it's going to be like that, huh?
Look, kid, I don't take orders very well.
Especially from someone of your stature,
and obvious lack of experience.
She killed Oked. So she agreed
to fill in for him on this particular job.
Or, like I said,
we can always find another way
to settle your debt.
That won't be necessary, I'm a
little short of work right now anyway.
She's a little rough around the edges,
but we need six hunters.
Without her, we got no job.
Fine. Let's get going.
Don't we settle first?
What? You don't trust us?
When the job's done, you'll get your cut.
Just like the rest of us.
Welcome. Welcome. I am Major Rigosso.
We are thrilled to have you here.
Please allow me the pleasure
of explaining the mission.
These elevators will take us beneath
the surface of the planet below.
Waiting there is a sub tram
which is carrying very precious cargo.
Your mission is to protect the tram as
it makes its way to the final destination.
And what is this precious cargo?
That's none of your concern.
Just make sure it gets where it's going.
And where exactly is it going?
To my lord, Otua Blank. He rules
over this planet with an iron fist.
If you fail to protect his cargo,
losing your bounty
will be the least of your concerns.
This way, please.
Why do we have to travel by sub tram?
Wouldn't it be easier
just to land at our destination?
You'd think so.
The atmosphere of our planet
is completely pressurized,
leaving all aerial travel impossible.
If we attempted to land
on the planet's surface,
our ship would immediately implode.
Sub tram it is then.
So why hire six expensive
bounty hunters to move cargo?
There's a group of marauders
that would like nothing more
than to hijack my master's cargo.
So far, my men have been
ineffective against them.
They've arrived.
No matter what happens,
do not open this box.
You make the rules, I follow them.
So that's it? That is
what we're protecting?
Who cares? As long as we get paid.
My lord, Otua Blank, will meet us
on the other side. Good luck.
After them!
Okay, Boba, the cargo is secure.
Latss, you and Highsinger stay there.
I'll be in the engine room with Bossk.
I sent the new girl and Dengar to the back.
Hello, darling, looks like we're securing
the back platform together.
Wonderful.
So what do you think is in that box?
Whatever it is,
it better be worth all this effort.
Heads up, people, we got company.
Latts, Highsinger, get ready!
They're here!
Protect the cargo at all costs.
Goodbye.
Oh, no, you don't.
Poodoo.
I'll check the cargo, stay here.
Oh, hey, boss, you'd better get down.
They're boarding from the rear,
I could use a hand back here!
Hold your position!
Bossk, get to the back and help the rookie!
I'm on it.
Stop him, he's the leader!
You!
I want what's mine!
Over my dead body.
What?
Don't worry, I'll protect you.
Hey!
Pluma, are you okay?
Brother, you came for me!
Of course I did.
Well, well, well, what do we have here?
Stay back!
That little girl
is worth a lot of money to me.
Now step aside!
Stop it!
Krismo!
That girl's crazy! We're protecting her?
Try not to be such a novice.
Open your eyes, she's on their side.
It doesn't matter,
tie them down and let's finish this job.
Is this really necessary?
None of this was my choice.
I never asked to be ripped away
from my home, from my family.
You'll never know what it's like.
I wish I didn't, but I do.
You're just doing this for the money.
It's just another job to you.
You don't even care what's going
to happen to us once it's over.
Hey, rookie! I need you in the back.
You're right, you are just another job
that I couldn't care less about.
Don't move.
We're almost to the drop-off point.
Soon, I'll be delivering
that brat to the warlord
and collecting a handsome bounty
which you will get your share of.
Share of? There's only two of us left.
I get half.
Half? Please. You just got to the game.
Boy, don't test me.
I will be delivering the cargo
and collecting the bounty.
No one of true importance
would lower themselves
to trade with a mere boy.
Boy? You have no idea
who you're talking to.
I have been in charge
of this whole operation...
No, you have no idea
who you are talking to.
Welcome!
Ah! Finally,
my bride.
Uh, bride?
Uh-uh-uh.
Bounty first.
Your unmarked credits as promised.
Enjoy!
My bride! At last!
Ugh!
You pay my price first
then you get the girl.
How do I know you won't take the
credits and then hand us over?
You don't.
Run along now.
Thank you.
You made it? I don't believe it!
Here's the payment,
I already subtracted my share.
Boba's is in there too,
make sure he gets it.
Where is he?
He'll turn up.
Well, you certainly turned out to
be quite the member of the team,
didn't you?
I'm not part of any team.
You're too good for us now, is that it?
No. Once I was just like you,
but I'm not that person anymore.
Now, I have a future.