While fighting to control
the darkened world of Umbara,
Anakin Skywalker's battalion
is temporarily placed under the command
of Jedi General Pong Krell.
As Krell's disastrous strategies
result in increasing casualties,
his men begin to turn against him.
Captain Rex struggles to balance loyalty
between his commander
and his fellow men.
Under his watch, Fives and Jesse
disobey Krell's orders,
resulting in their court-martial.
General Krell, I respectfully request
you reconsider court-martialing
Fives and Jesse.
The actions of ARC trooper
5555 and CT-5597
were a clear act of treachery
and disregard for my command.
If punishment isn't swift,
their defiance may inspire others
to follow suit.
Sir, the men are with you.
It's just that some of them feel you're
putting their lives in danger needlessly.
All the more reason
to send a clear message
that I am in charge
and insubordination will not be tolerated.
The truth is,
these clones have had a difficult time
respecting my command
since the beginning.
I've seen it before.
Some clones are just defective.
They aren't able to succumb to authority.
You're right, Captain.
I don't think I can court-martial them.
It will only be a waste of time
and that's something we don't have.
I'm afraid they'll need to be disposed of.
Prepare a squad for execution.
What? But, sir...
You heard me, Captain.
Have it done immediately,
or I'll do it myself.
Fives, Jesse, I'm sorry.
General Krell has ordered
your execution immediately.
What? But how? He can't do this!
He has authority to render
punishment during combat.
I can understand a court-martial
and locking us up in the brig,
but executing us?
I tried to convince him that it's my fault,
but he wouldn't let me.
Rex, you have to face it,
he's been using you.
He needs your loyalty
to control the others.
I won't let him get away with this.
Don't beat yourself up about it.
We made our choice.
We knew what the price was.
Speak for yourself.
Still got your sense of humor, I see.
- Yeah, who said I was joking?
- Well...
I guess this is it.
Line up the prisoners.
Well,
I've officially lost my sense of humor.
Will the prisoners
request to be blindfolded?
I'll take that as a no.
I hope you can live with yourself, Dogma.
Ready weapons.
Never thought we'd go out this way.
Aim.
Wait!
This is wrong and we all know it!
The general is making a mistake,
and he needs to be called on it.
No clone should have to go out this way!
We're loyal soldiers!
We follow orders, but we are not
a bunch of unthinking droids!
We are men! We must be trusted
to make the right decisions!
Especially when the orders
we are given are wrong!
Fire!
What... What happened?
They're doing the right thing, Dogma.
Because if this is how soldiers
are rewarded for heroic actions,
then one day, every man in this battalion
may face a similar fate.
- Take off their binders.
- No!
We have orders!
We have to go through with this!
Good luck finding anyone to do it.
You wanted us, sir?
I ordered those clones to be destroyed.
You are making a mistake
by crossing me, clone.
It's Captain, sir.
- General, there's an incoming transmission.
- Put it through.
General, the Umbarans
have stepped up their offensive.
We're holding them off,
but their squadrons have ambushed
one of our platoons,
seizing weapons and uniforms.
We believe they may be planning
to launch a massive attack.
Looks like you have your stay
of execution for now.
Lock the traitors in the brig, and prepare
your platoons to move out immediately.
We need to pre-empt the enemy
by hitting them now
with everything we've got.
We're finally going to take the capital.
And, Captain,
make sure the troops are aware
that the enemy may disguise themselves
as clones to try to trick us.
I will, sir.
Stay alert.
The enemy has our weapons and our armor,
they may try to trick us with an ambush.
Watch out, Dogma!
I saw that thing attack Hardcase.
It'll chew you up and spit you out.
Here, watch.
Ew!
- Gross.
- We're under attack!
- Where's the enemy?
- I don't know! I can't see anything.
Get those mortars up here!
Anyone have a visual?
Negative. It's too dark.
Wait! I see them!
They're disguised as clones, all right.
- Captain, where are you?
- We're sustaining heavy casualties!
What?
Everyone, stop firing!
We're shooting at our own men!
They're not Umbarans! They're clones!
Take off your helmets!
Show them you're not the enemy.
- They're clones!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Everyone, stop firing.
Cease fire! They're not Umbarans.
They're clones!
What the...
Look! We're clones! We're all clones!
What?
This can't be happening.
What have we done?
I don't understand.
Why did these troopers attack us?
Captain, I've found their platoon leader.
It's Waxer, he's still alive.
Waxer.
Tell me who gave you the orders
to attack us.
It... It was General Krell.
He sent us to these coordinates
to stop the enemy.
We thought they were wearing our armor,
but it was...
You.
We all know who's responsible
for what happened out there.
What we don't know, is why.
Something has to be done.
What I'm proposing is highly treasonous.
If any man chooses to opt out, do it now.
From this point forward,
we are entering uncharted territory.
My orders are, we arrest General Krell
for treason against the Republic.
General Krell, you are being
relieved of duty.
It's treason then.
Surrender, General.
- You're committing mutiny, Captain.
- Explain your actions!
My actions?
For ordering your troops
against one another.
Oh, that.
I'm surprised you were
able to figure it out,
for a clone.
Surrender, General. You're outnumbered!
You dare to attack a Jedi?
I will not be undermined
by creatures bred in some laboratory!
Get him!
Hold it right there!
- Lower your weapon, Dogma!
- I can't do that, sir.
- That's an order!
- It's my duty!
You're all traitors!
I used to believe that being a good soldier
meant doing everything they told you.
That's how they engineered us.
But we're not droids.
We're not programmed.
You have to learn
to make your own decisions.
Dogma, don't do it.
Take him to the brig.
Troopers, don't let General Krell escape!
Anybody got anything?
Negative, Captain. We lost him.
Wait!
He's too powerful!
Hurry!
He's coming!
You should have listened to the
ARC trooper from the beginning, Captain.
He was right. I was using you.
- You've all been my pawns.
- Get him!
Captain Rex, this is Tup.
If you can, force the General towards me!
- What? Why?
- Trust me, sir!
Troopers, listen up!
Circle around, lure him towards Tup.
Hey, ugly, come and get me!
I stunned him, sir.
Nice work, Tup.
Why, General? Why kill your own men?
Because I can.
Because you fell for it.
Because you're inferior.
But you're a Jedi! How could you?
A Jedi?
I'm no longer naive enough to be a Jedi.
A new power is rising, I've foreseen it.
The Jedi are going to lose this war,
and the Republic will
be ripped apart from the inside.
In its place is going to rise a new order,
and I will rule as part of it.
You're a Separatist!
I serve no one's side, only my own.
And soon, my new master.
You're an agent of Dooku.
Not yet,
but when I get out of here, I will be.
After I've succeeded
in driving the Republic from Umbara,
the Count will reward my actions
and make me his new apprentice.
How could you do this? You had my trust!
My loyalty! I followed all of your orders,
and you made me kill my brothers.
That's because you were
the biggest fool of them all, Dogma.
I counted on blind loyalty like yours
to make my plan succeed.
That will never happen.
You're a traitor, General,
and you'll be dealt with as one.
You never learn, Captain.
The Umbarans are going
to retake this base.
And when they do, I will be free.
Captain, we've repaired the transmitter.
It looks like it was sabotaged.
We received a message
from General Kenobi.
His forces have captured the capital,
but the remaining Umbarans
are heading here!
Get everyone on the perimeter!
We need to prepare for a full-scale attack.
Yes, sir!
Krell sabotaged the transmitter.
He's been against us from the beginning.
If the Umbarans get to him,
he'll turn over all our intel.
The defense codes, everything.
He'll strike a crippling
blow to the Republic.
Something has to be done.
We can't risk the possibility
that he might escape.
As long as Krell's alive,
he's a threat to every one of us.
I agree.
Turn around and step toward the wall.
On your knees.
You're in a position of power now.
How does it feel?
I said, on your knees.
It feels good, doesn't it?
But I can sense your fear.
You're shaking, aren't you?
What are you waiting for?
The Umbarans are getting closer.
I have to do this.
You can't do it, can you?
Eventually, you'll have to do
the right thing...
I... I had to.
He betrayed us.
General Kenobi's battalions have
routed the last hold-outs of Umbarans,
and we've secured all sectors.
We did it. We took Umbara.
What's the point of all this?
I mean, why?
I don't know, sir.
I don't think anybody knows.
But I do know that someday
this war is gonna end.
Then what? We're soldiers.
What happens to us then?