Turmoil in the Outer Rim!
Located near a major hyperspace lane,
the planet Felucia
is caught in an unending battle
between Republic and Separatist forces.
Clone tank divisions make a valiant push
deep into Separatist controlled territory
led by Anakin Skywalker
and his Padawan Ahsoka Tano.
General Grievous
learning of the impending Jedi attack,
has dispatched reinforcements
to one of his droid outposts
hoping to secure his grip on the system.
Droid re-enforcements
have just arrived.
We shall break into three groups
to divide their defenses.
I'll take the left flank.
Skywalker, attack the front gate,
Ahsoka, you scale the back wall,
we'll meet in the middle.
Okay, scouts, find me a way down there,
quiet-like.
Going through the front gate won't be easy.
You have it tougher going over that wall.
You taught me well. I can handle anything.
Don't get cocky.
- Hold up, I sense something out there.
- A droid?
I don't think so.
Probably just an animal.
- Come on, we got to get to that wall.
- Stay alert, men. Let's move.
Skywalker, Ahsoka, are you in position?
Ready and waiting, Master Plo.
We're in position.
We are detecting several Republic tanks
moving in on the ridge in front of us.
Artillery, open fire.
Form up for counter attack. Lower the gate.
Forward, forward, attack!
- Steady, steady, wait for my move.
- Copy that.
Follow me.
Comet, Sinker, Boost, get up there.
- We're all clear, Commander, come on up.
- I'll be right there.
I can't believe my luck, a Jedi youngling.
The outpost is secure.
Good job, Corporal.
Where's Commander Tano?
She was covering our flank
when we scaled the wall.
Everybody fan out.
I want a perimeter sweep now.
Ahsoka, state your location.
Ahsoka, come in. Are you there?
Can you hear me?
Ahsoka, come in. Where could she be?
Ahsoka, can you hear me? Ahsoka!
You won't be needing this.
Hey, what is this place?
Who are these pirates?
These are Trandoshans,
they're gonna release us
and hunt us down for sport.
Hunt us down?
We have found new prey for the hunt.
The youngling will provide great sport.
Perhaps your first Jedi kill.
Are you ready, Young Dar?
She'll die by my claw.
Your son will outplay all comers.
We'll take this new batch to Island Four.
Time to see
who's smart enough to join the hunt.
Open fire!
You need to come with us.
Who are you?
We used to be Jedi younglings.
We never stood a chance.
They attacked us on a training mission.
We were captured and brought here.
Why would they take younglings?
Because Jedi Knights
are too powerful for them.
I'm Kalifa. This is O-Mer and Jinx.
- Who are you?
- Ahsoka Tano.
I was captured during the Battle
of Felucia. I'm a Padawan learner.
- What's the situation here?
- You'd better sit down.
We were taken by those foul lizards
for their amusement.
To be hunted, killed
and mounted on their wall as trophies.
We've been stuck here for more rotations
than we can count.
No one has come for us.
I doubt anyone is still looking.
Chew on that, Padawan, then rest.
You'll need your strength.
General, we've been over the same area
a dozen times,
there's no sign of Commander Tano.
Not good enough, Rex, try again.
We have alerted our forces
throughout the Outer Rim
and intelligence assets
inside the Confederacy.
- If she's spotted, we shall know about it.
- Good.
Skywalker, our mission here is finished.
We must return to Coruscant.
I am not abandoning her.
Your emotions are clouding your judgment.
- I will not leave her fate up to others.
- It's time to go.
Call everybody in, Rex, we're leaving.
Ahsoka, it's time to go.
What's happened?
The sun's almost up
which means we clear out.
- Where do you go?
- We keep moving
and keep those disgusting hunters
from picking up our scent.
That's your plan?
If you really are a Padawan, you would
know there's wisdom in experience.
We've been here longer.
You will learn if you listen.
And only if you listen.
The sun has risen, let the hunt begin!
Get down. Someone's coming.
Those two came in with me,
we should help them.
No, it's too late.
Look at her run.
It's your shot, take her out.
Ugh!
We could've stopped them.
No, Ahsoka, we are not saviors here.
Here, we are survivors.
If they had spotted us we'd be dead now.
We'll never get out of here
if we just keep hiding.
We have to act.
There were other Padawans here
that once thought as you do now.
- All right, where are they?
- They're dead!
Just because they failed
doesn't mean we will.
You don't understand,
it's not that we don't want to fight,
we're younglings.
They have every advantage.
- Get back here.
- I can't do that.
My Master would never forgive me
for running and hiding
in a situation like this.
Do not overestimate your abilities.
I'm not.
Ahsoka, don't...
Here, lizard, lizard. Come and find me.
Kalifa! Don't kill him out of hatred.
It's not the Jedi way.
The others will be coming.
I don't understand,
why won't this thing work?
The Trandoshans deactivate the blasters
if we take them.
That is why none of us have any.
It's been a long time since the Trandoshans
captured another Padawan
and brought them here.
- Thanks.
- I didn't mean it as an insult.
I meant it as a sign,
a mistake on their part.
Ahsoka, your energy, your strength,
it's what we've been lacking.
We were beginning to lose hope
and forgot who we are.
And who are you?
We are Jedi.
All right, we need a strategy.
- So, what do you suggest?
- What about a base?
I mean, they must have a compound
or something, right?
Not that we've ever seen.
So where do they come from?
We don't know, we've only witnessed them
hunting and in their hover pods.
If we are gonna go on the offensive,
we'll need to find out where they live.
We'll start covering ground tomorrow.
Dar! Dar! Dar! Dar! Dar! Dar!
We have already covered the beach area
and most of the briar
on this side of the bay.
If it was easy to find, you guys
would have found it before I got here.
True enough.
- Maybe we should try more inland?
- It's worth a shot.
Guys, I think
we're looking in the wrong place.
That's their fortress.
Split up!
O-Mer, this way!
Kalifa!
- Finish her, my son, the kill is yours.
- I will kill her with my own hands.
Come here, you Jedi whelp.
Not so impressive, are you?
And yet you have the honor of being
my first Jedi kill.
First of many, I hope.
- Careful.
- It's okay. I can make it.
Kalifa!
Those Jedi whelps killed my son.
Young Dar!
There's no escape! I'll hunt you down!
- Move us in closer!
- We can't, the brush is too thick.
Kalifa, we have to move, hurry.
Please, Ahsoka, leave me.
- I won't.
- You have to.
Ahsoka, please take care...
I'll take care of the others.
I know you will.
I'll kill you! You killed my son!
I'll kill you!
You can't hide from me!
- What is Ahsoka's strength?
- She is fearless.
That can also be a weakness.
Is she a worthy apprentice?
No one has her kind of determination.
Except you.
I'll find her.
This may not be within your power.
Whatever you're trying to say, Master Plo,
just say it.
I am suggesting that perhaps,
if you have trained her well,
she shall take care of herself,
and find a way back to you.