A bid for revenge!
Betrayed and left for dead
by Count Dooku,
Asajj Ventress has begun a deadly game
with her former master,
launching a secret assassination attempt
against him
with the help of her kin,
the mysterious Nightsisters.
Deceived into believing
the Jedi are behind the recent attack,
Dooku has traveled across the galaxy
to enlist the Nightsisters
in his quest for vengeance.
Mother Talzin.
Count Dooku.
Come, we have much to discuss.
Thank you for receiving me, Sister.
I believe the old alliance can again be
what it once was.
You would only have to pledge your clan's
allegiance to the Separatists' cause.
We could certainly use the powers
of the Nightsisters against the Jedi.
Such a generous offer, Count.
But our loyalty is reserved
for only each other.
The only reason I am aiding
in your search for a new assassin
is because, long ago,
you chose to help me.
After this matter is resolved,
I hope our paths never cross again.
As you wish, Sister.
Drink.
You must gather your strength
after such a long journey.
Thank you.
Blackroot, to replenish the body.
You have heard of the Sith Warrior
Darth Maul, have you not?
Yes. He was slain on Naboo
at the hand of Obi-Wan Kenobi.
A few still remain in his bloodline.
The men dwell on the far side of Dathomir.
What if I could provide
another of his kind?
A warrior of the same caliber?
Yes.
But I warn you,
men are easy to acquire, hard to control.
With my last assassin,
Asajj Ventress, dead,
and the Jedis' attacks against me
increasing,
procuring a new personal assassin
is essential.
Very well. It shall be done, my Lord.
So he has agreed
to take another apprentice.
A barbarian, no less.
A man who we will deliver to the Count
with all of the training and skill
an assassin can possess.
This warrior
must have no loyalty to Dooku.
He will be our pawn.
Yes.
Yes!
We will use our magicks
to manipulate his assassin,
and when the time is right...
Dooku will pay for his betrayal,
with his life.
You will go to the far side of Dathomir
and find the men.
You will select
the most suitable candidate,
one with your strength and skill,
one we can use to our advantage.
Yes, Mother.
Welcome, Sister.
I have come for the selection.
Yes, yes, of course.
Line up! Heads of each tribe!
Line up for the Sister!
Feral,
try not to draw attention to yourself.
That won't be a problem for me, Savage.
What a fine-looking specimen.
But looks aren't everything.
Too small.
Too weak.
These will do.
Him.
And him.
These men are to your liking, Sister?
Yes.
Now for the tests.
There will be three of them.
Whoever survives will be my champion
and go on to serve me.
Understood?
- Yes, Sister!
Excellent! Let the games begin!
We must be vigilant, Feral.
Aren't I always?
Feral!
Brother, get up!
The witch, where is she?
Pathetic!
Where are the warriors I came for?
Is this all the power these men possess?
In order to fight against the Force,
you must see what cannot be seen.
Only four of you remain.
Who will be the first to fall?
Not fast enough!
Show yourself!
Good.
Let the third and final challenge begin!
There are only two of us left, brother,
but only one will survive.
No, not if I can help it.
Stick together. We must work as a team.
Go!
Savage!
As long as I live,
you will not harm him!
Please. Spare him. Take me.
Leave us.
My life is yours.
Yes, it is.
He has surrendered his life to me.
This one is strong.
A perfect male specimen.
Such hate!
The sheer power of it.
A tremendous gift
from the galaxy, Mother.
He will serve us well.
He is ready, Sisters.
Look at the strength in him!
The power!
Let me go!
Calmly, Sister.
Let me go.
That's better.
Bring in the prisoner!
Now for the final test.
Savage?
Kill him.
Savage, you know me.
I am your kin!
Do not do this!
I said, kill him!
No!
Brother!
Brother, please!
You beg?
Weakling!
Savage!
Good.
Very good.
You will learn to draw your strength
from your emotions.
Hate will feed you.
Never sympathize with the enemy,
not even for a moment.
Yes, Sister.
For you, an enchanted blade,
blessed with our most potent magicks.
I think it's time we introduce
the apprentice to his new master.
Wouldn't you agree?
At last.
Sister.
Count Dooku, may I present.
Savage Oppress.
He certainly is a sight to behold.
The fiercest of his kind, my Lord.
He shall serve you well.
Yes, he shall.
Mother Talzin speaks very highly
of your skills.
Still, I require proof
of your abilities as a warrior.
The Jedi are in control of a vital outpost
on the jungle planet of Devaron.
A temple.
A temple?
Do not be fooled, Savage.
The Temple of Eedit serves only as a front
for the military
operations of the Republic.
It is essential that we seize the Temple
if the Separatists ever hope to take
control of that corner of the galaxy.
You shall go to Devaron
and take what is rightfully ours.
Yes, my Lord.
Get him!
Jedi!
- Master?
- Stay back!
No!
- My Lord.
- Is it finished?
Yes. The Temple has been taken.
- And the Jedi?
- Dead.
Very impressive, Savage.
Return to Serenno immediately.
Very well, my Lord.
You have done well, Savage.
I'll have much use for you.
Thank you, my Lord.
I foresee we will do great things together.
I shall teach you the
ways of the dark side.
Soon your powers will rival
that of the great Sith Lord Darth Maul.
We will be even more powerful
than Lord Sidious.
We shall rule the galaxy together,
my apprentice.
I am your servant, Master.