Victory on Geonosis!
After a massive planetary siege,
the Separatist forces on Geonosis
have finally fallen.
Key weapons factories
have been destroyed,
but at a heavy cost to Republic troops.
Now, as Jedi Master Luminara Unduli
and Obi-Wan Kenobi
begin a cleanup of the planet,
they launch an intense campaign
to find Separatist leader Poggle the Lesser
and bring him to justice.
Sorry to leave you here, Rex.
There's still a lot to do.
You two have done enough
destroying that factory.
Go get some rest.
We'll let General Kenobi take it from here.
We'll be back before you know it,
Captain Rex.
We're ready, sir.
- A hard-won victory.
- Indeed. And a costly one.
We suffer a great many losses
in these battles. Too many.
The battles do appear to be coming
with growing frequency.
- No sign of Poggle, then?
- Nothing.
We have clone squadrons spread out
all over the area, but no hits yet.
I'll go out and find some clue
as to where he went.
I'm sure the clones can handle...
Poggle has too much information
about the Separatists to let him get away.
Very well, Master Unduli.
Just make sure to leave a bit
of strategic planning for me
when I come back, Master Kenobi.
I'd hate to feel left out.
We lost one!
Lord Poggle says leave it.
We gotta keep moving.
What's this?
I didn't expect to find you up and about.
After enough time in a bacta tank,
one longs for the mundane comfort
of star charts.
It seems like it did you some good.
Your wound looks almost healed.
I wish I could say the same
for most of my men.
Well, let's make sure we don't have
to take Geonosis a third time.
Poggle's forces seem to have come
from the northern hemisphere.
And where was Master Unduli's
last contact made from?
This region, farther to the west,
but there's nothing out there
according to our latest intel.
- There.
- Where?
150 clicks southeast.
It appears to be a munitions container
of some kind.
It could just be debris.
I don't think so.
There was no battle in this area.
That makes no sense.
Nothing in the temple could have survived
the munitions we used
in the first wave of our attack.
Why would he risk exposure to go there?
I'm not yet sure.
Perhaps he doesn't realize the extent
to which we cleared that area.
Master Luminara, I'm tracking a sandstorm
that's heading your way.
No matter.
Poggle is out in the open, and I intend
to grab him before he can get off-world.
I advise against it.
You might get lost in the storm.
Then we'd have to find
both you and Poggle.
I feel it is a risk worth taking.
As you wish.
Let's go.
- OM-5, are you still there?
- Yes. I think I'm right next to you.
Where is Lord Poggle taking us?
OM-5? OM-5!
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
Don't leave me.
I can't track Poggle in this storm.
We'll reach the temple soon.
We can get out of the storm there.
What could be taking her so long?
Something must have happened.
Patience, Skywalker.
It's a delicate operation.
I'm sure we'll have more information soon.
I must admit, I am troubled
that we've not heard from her.
Let's not start worrying yet.
Luminara's not one
to take unnecessary risks.
You were right. He's here somewhere.
Master Kenobi.
We tracked Poggle to the Progate Temple,
but now there's no sign of him.
Go no further until we can send support.
The storm is making things difficult.
We can barely read
your transmission as it is.
Are you sure he went into the temple?
Yes, we saw him enter, but I think
he's gone down into the catacombs below.
Those catacombs go on for miles.
I fear we may have lost him.
Get yourself out of there.
Master Unduli? Master Unduli!
We've lost the connection.
- Where are you going?
- Take a guess.
We'll never get to her in this storm.
The gunships can't handle it.
- We can't wait!
- I'm sorry, Skywalker. We have no choice.
We must be patient
and trust in Master Unduli.
We'll leave as soon as the storm lifts.
Stay alert, everyone.
Spread out and look around, men.
General.
Buzz is dead.
- Any sign of Luminara?
- No, sir.
There was a struggle.
This is not a good sign.
Luminara's lightsaber.
Poggle didn't do this.
But maybe that did.
That is one ugly bug.
I haven't seen one
that looks like that before.
I don't believe anyone has.
It could be the Geonosian queen.
- The bugs have a queen?
- Mmm. Rumored.
But we haven't found
any proof of her existence.
Until now.
This way.
Come on, men, let's move.
This leads to a dead end.
This one goes down the furthest.
- Sir, I'd say that's our best bet.
- I'll go first.
Master Kenobi!
If you're following me,
you must leave this place. Just get out!
I repeat, fall back!
She must be close by. Come on!
I don't like the looks of this.
Look out!
I can't stop them!
Oh, no! No!
Back, everyone! Back!
Take out the tunnel supports!
It's the only way!
What were those things?
We couldn't kill them.
I've heard stories of a Geonosian hive mind
so powerful, so strong,
that it can maintain its connection
with its warriors even after they have died.
And you think
that's why we couldn't kill them?
- Because they're...
- Already dead, yes.
- That can't be true. That's impossible!
- Impossible or not,
these creatures keep moving
after we cut them up or shoot them down.
Call for reinforcements.
- There's no signal.
- We must be too deep underground.
You two, head back to the surface
and contact General Mundi.
- Tell him we need reinforcements.
- Yes, sir.
I won't be unhappy to get out
from under all this dirt.
This place gives me the shivers.
Wind's probably
playing tricks on us, right?
Look around. There's nothing...
What the...
Blast them!
They're not going down!
We have to turn back!
Gearshift!
Obviously the thing is a lot more powerful
than we assumed.
I'm going to the surface
to alert General Mundi myself.
I think that would be
a foolhardy move, Anakin.
We can't divide our troops again.
We don't have time to double back
to the surface.
Every moment we waste
puts Luminara in greater danger.
The air is warmer here.
We must be getting close.
Forget the heat.
- It smells down here.
- Keep your voice down.
I'm just saying.
This planet is rotten from the inside out.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
It must be the queen.
- Any sign of Luminara?
I see her.
She's suspended near the throne.
- Perfect. What about Poggle?
- He's speaking with the queen.
Good. You take the soldiers,
I'll take the queen.
Must you always rush into things?
Oh, no. You don't actually want
to talk to it, do you?
Matter of fact, I do.
Anakin, don't you wonder
why they took Luminara captive?
- Why not just kill her?
- She's leverage. She's a hostage.
Leverage for what?
No, there's something else going on here,
and these zombies are connected to it.
Fine. We'll try it your way.
So glad you agree.
Cody, set your men up
around the perimeter.
These creatures live in darkness.
The light from your helmet
should blind them temporarily.
Turn your lamps on at my signal.
They should create enough confusion
for us to get Luminara out of here.
But what happens when the bugs pursue?
You've seen them in action, sir.
We can't kill them.
We'll have to bury them.
It'll at least slow them down.
Shoot out the support pillars
and this whole place will collapse.
Let's go!
How did you know
they wouldn't just attack us?
Because I make observations,
while you think with your lightsaber.
Well, that quick thinking of mine
is usually needed
when your observations
get us into trouble.
Anakin, the queen took Luminara hostage.
She wanted a Jedi, now she has two more.
I want to know what she's after.
Well, when this doesn't go as planned,
which it won't, I'll be ready.
That is so reassuring.
I thought I told you not to follow me,
Master Kenobi.
Yes, well, I took a lesson from Anakin
- and decided not to follow orders.
- Hey!
You.
You are the creatures
that attack Geonosia.
Why have you come before me?
Your Majesty,
it is a pleasure to finally meet you.
I am Obi-Wan Kenobi,
and this is Anakin Skywalker.
It is our sad duty to inform you
that your rule is at an end.
You not dictate to me, Jedi!
My empire is forever!
I'm afraid it does not appear
that way, Your Grace.
You shall release the Jedi Luminara
and submit to Republic law.
I no submit to you!
No, patience, Anakin. Wait.
Majesty, destroying us shall only make
the Republic's judgment of you harsher.
No, Jedi. No!
I no destroy you,
I devour you!
I control you.
I had but one Jedi before
young Poggle bring me,
but now I have three!
Now, watch as my child
enters your Jedi friend.
And once inside,
her mind becomes my mind,
her thoughts, my thoughts.
It's a sort of mind control, a hive mind.
She thinks she can possess us.
Great. Find out everything
you wanted to know yet?
No, wait, I want to see how it works.
I don't think Luminara wants to see
how it works.
No, I don't.
I'm curious. The more we know, the better.
I disagree!
- So do I.
- Come, now, the nose or the ear?
Which do you think it will enter?
- I think the nose.
- I hope this is part of the plan.
Isn't it always? Cody! Now!
You're coming with us, Poggle!
Obi-Wan, look out!
What? Anakin, no!
Got it.
What are you doing?
I was going to study that!
Study the bottom of my boot.
Come on, let's get out of here!
Here they come!
Take out the supports!
They're still coming!
This is our way out.
Start climbing.
Obi-Wan, look out!
All things considered,
that went better than I expected.
I wish we could have gotten
one of those worms.
Knowing how the queen controls
her minions could have proven valuable.
Well, hopefully the secret
is buried with her.