How are we gonna get out of here?
I have an idea.
Which is?
Just set those things to stun.
We're not trying to kill anyone.
Yeah, well, tell that to them.
They're almost through.
Wait.
Now!
R7, find us a path out of here.
All right. Now what?
The escape pods have been destroyed.
Taking a shuttle is our best bet.
The boys are having
a rough time of it.
Did you hear Maul also escaped?
He didn't escape. I let him out.
What? Why?
Diversion. Come on!
That's one word for it.
Target number
one's escaped the medical bay.
We're in pursuit.
What is the status of CT-7567?
Commander Rex
is still missing in action, sir.
Did he aid in Tano's escape?
Unknown at present.
Target number two
is in the hyperdrive room!
Sir, the hyperdrive generators
are failing!
Disengage! Disengage!
It's too late!
Oh, I don't like the sound of that.
Hangar bay doors are sealed.
They've got everything locked down.
If they weren't trying to kill us,
I'd be proud.
R7, start unlocking the doors on bay 12.
Cheep, prep the shuttle.
G-G, find out what happened to the ship.
- Watch it!
- Look out!
Control failed to report in.
We think they'll make their move
to escape via the main hangar.
Affirmative, I want
squads marshaled at position 2-5 and 2-7.
Wait for my signal before proceeding.
Copy that, Lieutenant.
What do you mean
the hyperdrive is off-line?
Destroyed? It's completely gone?
We're caught
in that moon's gravitational field.
R7, open the main hangar doors.
We need to get out of here.
Any luck with those doors?
And the shuttle?
There it is.
- Go!
- I can see them there!
Go, go, go!
They were waiting for us.
Hold your position, men.
If they try to leave,
they'll have to go through us.
So what do we do?
Fight our way to the shuttle?
They're too many.
Besides, I don't wanna hurt them.
I hate to tell you this,
but they don't care.
This ship is going down,
and those soldiers, my brothers,
are willing to die and take you and me
along with them.
You're a good soldier, Rex.
So is every one of those men down there.
They may be willing to die, but I am not
the one who is going to kill them.
So, we're just gonna surrender?
Admit defeat? Is that it?
No.
Well, I don't see any other option.
I have an idea.
Don't worry. It's a good one... I think.
Can I count on the three of you?
Good. I'll explain on the way.
Sir, we think
Maul might be headed your way. Be aware.
Hold your fire!
Hang on.
We have Tano and the commander.
Send all remaining troops to my position.
I said hold your fire, Jesse.
I have the situation under control.
You have your order, sir.
Now execute it or I will!
The order was to execute the Jedi
for treason against the Republic.
The problem is,
Ahsoka Tano is no longer a Jedi.
Hasn't been for some time.
Sir, you said yourself we're under
special order from Darth Sidious
to eliminate Ahsoka Tano
and any other clone who disobeys Order 66.
Just keep him talking,
a little bit longer.
Jesse. Jesse, listen to me.
We've known each other a long time.
If we don't get this right, we will be
the ones committing treason, not her.
Commander Rex,
you're in violation of Order 66.
I accuse you of treason
against the Grand Army of the Republic.
You'll be demoted in rank from commander
and subject to execution
along with the traitor Ahsoka Tano.
Ready?
Yeah, I didn't much like
being a commander anyway.
Company, ready. Aim!
Now!
Rex, the ship.
You wanted this chaos.
Move it. Move it.
Get these lifts activated.
Get us up there.
Our panel's locked out.
Fire on those droids.
The shuttle.
Incoming.
Surround them!
Can't hold them off.
Too many of them.
Blast them.
Hey.
Blast those dirty droids.
Nothing. Nothing. Nothing.
Everything down here is under maintenance.
There!
Get me over there.
We've entered the atmosphere.
Fire retro-rockets.
We've lost lateral control.
We're gonna break apart...
Look out!
Come on.