♪ ♪
Who a person truly is cannot
be seen with the eye.
As war continues to fracture the Galaxy,
planets become pawns in
a dangerous chess game.
One planet in peril is Naboo,
where suffering and civil
unrest threaten once-friendly relations
between the
people on the surface
and the underwater-dwelling Gungans.
Rumors that the Gungans plan
to aid the separatists
in an attack on Theed force Senator
Padme Amidala home,
accompanied
by Jedi General Anakin Skywalker.
Jar Jar, do you read me?
It's Anakin.
We need you to meet us on
the surface of lake Paonga immediately.
Okeyday, mooie palo.
There's bombad trouble down here.
We know.
That's why we need to talk to you.
Oh boy! Mesa must stop
zippen to ze surface.
Ears go boomba some day.
What's going on Jar Jar?
We're hearing disturbing rumors.
Is Boss Lyonie calling
for a march on Theed?
Oh yesa, my lady.
Hesa give mooie fiery speeches,
blamen Naboo for everytin.
Mesa say it couldn't be true.
Of course, it's not.
We need to talk to him, Jar Jar.
Oh Centuriees! Da Nabooin have treated
yousa like second-class citizens.
Nosa more.
There-sa moments in da history
when change isa necessary.
Are yousa going to take what is
rightfully oursa?
Thesa mooie mooie bad.
Don't worry General.
Mesa friends can help.
Mesa hope so, Jar Jar.
Be quick.
Young Senator Amidala. If yousa here
to talk mesa
out of marchen on Theed,
yousa wasting time.
With all due respect, your
course of action is based on lies.
You must make your warriors stand down.
Mesa different now.
Mesa enlightened.
See?
Acting loconut.
He seems possessed, if you ask me.
Or under someone's influence.
Stop whisperen and go.
Besa gone.
The necklace.
Wha?
Wasa happenin?
Binks?
Whosa are they?
Who are we?
Boss Lyonie, don't you remember anything?
Who gave you this necklace, your majesty?
Minister Risha Loo.
Hesa given it to me.
Hesa tellin me itsa make me
bombad leader, very powerful.
They say Risha Loo know
ancient Gungan mystical power,
mind over matter, but
hesa only use it for good.
Until now, you mean.
Invasion procedein as planned, count.
Very good.
Mesa able to persuade
the officers to allowin
da separatist army easy access into Naboo.
You're doing the right thing
for your people, minister Loo.
- ***
- We'll be right outside.
And mesa counsel will be
rewarded in yousa new order?
You will be most influential.
Someone isa coming.
Whasa Boss Lyonie!
What do mesa owe da pleasure?
Yousa tricked me, Rish Loo.
- Mesa don't--
- Yousa used magical powers
to manipulate mesa head thoughts.
Mesa never attack da
surface-dwelling brothers and sisters...
unless yousa clouded mesa head.
Yousa not thinking clearly, bombad leader.
Wheresa necklace mesa given you?
Itsa destroyed.
Yousa not control me no more.
Yousa mistaken, King fool.
Something's wrong.
We better get up there.
Boss Lyonie don't listen to him.
Yousa get them.
- Check on Boss Lyonie.
- Ani!
This is mooie upsetting my lady.
I know, Jar Jar.
How is he?
The bandages have stopped the bleeding,
but he's unconscious.
The Gungans are still gathered
and poised to march on Theed.
Boss Lyonie never got a chance
to call off the invasion.
And it's almost dusk.
Jar jar, you're a Senator.
You have to tell them to stand down.
They'll listen to you.
Thesa Gungans are proud.
With theysa mood at the moment,
mesa the last person they'll
listen to now.
I don't believe it.
The resemblance is remarkable.
Whosa resemble whatsa?
You.
You Look just like Boss Lyonie.
I didn't realize it until
you put the crown on.
This gives me an idea.
Jar jar, you must put on
Lyonie's robes
and keep that crown on.
Oh, noi, noi.
Mesa can't do that.
You have to if we're going
to convince the Gungan army to stand down.
But theysa never listen to mesa.
Maybe not, but they will
listen to Boss Lyonie.
But wesa all don't Look alike.
Disa sad day for all Gungans.
Our beloved leader, Boss Lyonie, isa dead.
Wesa must honor his last order
and prepare
for oursa attack against the Naboo.
Weesa march with the
separatist droid army on Theed.
Death to the Naboo.
Thisa bad.
Thisa very bad.
Get up there and stop the attack.
Ah, mesa can't do it.
You can't, but Boss Lyonie can.
Now get out there.
Isa Boss Lyonie.
Hesa alive.
Say something.
- I... uh...
- He is alive.
He is.
Uh...Mesa... mesa fellow
Gungans, uh... Mesa made terrible mistaken
orderen march on Theed.
Wesa cancelling our attack.
It is Boss Lyonie.
It's working.
Risha Loo manipulated mesa
head thoughts
with lies and da misinformation.
Hesa da real enemy.
No.
No. No.
Now try not to mess this up,
Boss Lyonie.
Battle Droids?
Whatsa they doing here?
Theysa think weesa still
allies because of Rish Loo.
Our General wishes to speak
with you about the cancelled attack.
Jar jar?
Nosa, Lyonie.
Mesa Boss Lyonie.
Mesa talk to the General.
Follow me.
Come in, minister Lyonie.
Let's sit down and have a talk.
Oh deer.
So... so... I hear you have decided
not to aid our attack on the Naboo.
Oh yesa... oh yesa.
We must put end to unfortunate--
unfortunate bang-bang conflict.
It was a great effort
and cost for me to bring my armies here.
Mesa sorry dat Boss...
Exsqueezee me.
Mesa was receivin mooie bad advice.
If you won't attack the Naboo, I will.
Hold dat thought.
G-General Tarpals?
Yesa, Boss.
Yousa need to do dat... dat
ting... Dat big troop ting.
What did you just say?
Gosa, go.
Mesa--mesa just telling General dat
wesa must make da immediate arrangements
for a Gungan separatist attack.
Senator, mesa has urgent
message from Boss Lyonie.
Hesa say General Grievous isa here.
Grievous is here?
Where's Anakin?
Hesa chasing Risha Loo.
General Tarpals, listen to me.
You must capture Grievous.
But how?
There'sa too many droids helping him.
The droid commander still
thinks you're on the same side.
Have the droids shut down.
Then attack.
Its the only way.
Grievous is a bombad warrior,
but wesa shall do as you say.
I always be believen in the
friendship
Thank you, General.
What are we waiting for?
Hmm... Planning attack take a time.
You are a man of few words, Boss Lyonie.
Well, uh... Mesa more of a deep thinker.
You are not Boss Lyonie.
You have no idea of the
power within my grasp.
Yousa army is shut down, General.
Huh? Mesa suggest you surrender.
You can't be serious?
How does it feel to die?
Not die... sacrifice.
Jar jar, now.
This turn of the events is unfortunate.
General Grievous is a critical
part of my plan for the clone wars.
He must not remain captive.
What is to be done, my lord?
You must lure Skywalker
into a trap,
then negotiate a prisoner exchange.
How can you be certain
the Republic will trade Grievous
for Skywalker?
I have no doubt Senator
Amidala will gladly agree to your terms.
As you wish, my lord.
Rish Loo.
Yesa, Count?
I am at your secret laboratory.
Meet me here and leave enough
of a trail
for Skywalker to follow you.
I have a surprise waiting for him.
Master I have done what yousa asked.
Skywalker isa here.
Young Master Skywalker.
You're nothing if not relentless.
What a surprise.
Dooku.
You're a fool, Rish Loo.
- Why bring the war to Naboo?
- How quickly you forget.
After all, the war started here years ago.
You were a part of that first battle?
The sith control everything.
You just don't know it.
Where-sa Ani?
Hesa been gone mooie long time.
I'm not sure, Jar Jar.
Anakin.
Senator Amidala, we meet again.
I must regretfully inform
you
that young Skywalker has
been detained.
What have you done with Anakin?
Now, now, Senator, let's
not become emotional.
What do you want, Dooku?
I'm glad you asked.
I could be persuaded to return
Skywalker to you
in exchange
for General Grievous.
I--I can't
do that.
I'm sorry.
You soon will be.
Stop!
You cannot torture a prisoner.
Torture?
I don't know what you mean.
I'll give you an hour to
consider my proposition.
I'm sure you will make the right choice.
Yousa have to trade with him.
I can't, Jar Jar.
With Grievous captured,
we could win the war.
But--but, Padme,
hesa our friend.
I know.
I know, Jar Jar.
Mesa think yousa have to deal.
Yousa should listen to Binks.
Hesa right.
Release the General.
- Padme... I'm sorry.
- Shh.
It's all right, Ani.
Binks, yousa be bombad leader in my place.
Disa second time yousa stoppen
war between us and the Naboo.
And we are grateful, Senator Binks.
Mesa doin my best.