A long awaited truth!
A distress signal has been received
at the Jedi Temple
and Master Plo Koon has been
dispatched to investigate its origin.
The signal is from a ship
thought to be lost
and was last known to be
in the possession of a Jedi Master
who was killed long ago.
Can anyone hear us?
Come in please.
We're not getting anything over here.
We're off. We must be way off.
Negative. It is here.
The data specifically states.
It has got to be.
We've scanned the area three times.
This is a wasteland. There's nothing.
All of our information
pinpoints it is here.
I don't know
what to tell you, sir.
We're getting no visual,
and no recognition on the scanner.
We must locate the source of the signal,
Commander, press on!
Wait, I think
I've found something.
It's very faint, sir.
That is it.
Halt! Halt!
Halt all vehicles!
The hull
shows substantial scoring and wear.
Whenever it crashed, it wasn't recently.
General Plo, the scans check out,
it's a T-6 Shuttle all right,
serial number 7-7-5-5-1 -9.
I want the entire area cleared.
We're taking everything
back to Coruscant.
- Everything?
- Everything!
Then it is the lost ship
of Master Sifo-Dyas?
I found this at the crash site.
Hmm. The lightsaber of Sifo-Dyas it is.
Never found when he died it was.
Master Kenobi, remind the Council
of what you discovered
regarding Master Sifo-Dyas before
the start of the Clone War.
My investigation of the bounty hunter
Jango Fett led to Kamino.
The Kaminoans recounted
that it was Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas
who ordered the production
of a Clone Army.
Without the consent of the Council
or the Senate he did this.
Prior to the blockade of Naboo,
Sifo-Dyas sat on this Council until
we judged his ideas to be too extreme.
Indeed.
He said he foresaw a great conflict,
and that the Republic would need
to raise an army.
At the time the Council
rejected those ideas.
Well, it's not the first time
we've been wrong recently, is it?
The creation of the Clone Army,
kept secret from us Sifo-Dyas did.
How this was done we know not.
Yet now, a new piece
of the puzzle we have,
perhaps clarity, it will bring us, yes.
Our records definitively state
that Master Sifo-Dyas died on Felucia.
In the fifth quarter, a small skirmish
broke out between the native Felucians.
Master Sifo-Dyas was assigned
to negotiate peace talks
between the tribes.
The negotiations failed
and Sifo-Dyas was killed.
What became of his body?
I am afraid I cannot answer that.
Any further information on this incident
has been sealed.
On whose authority?
By the office
of the Supreme Chancellor.
Thank you, Madame Jocasta.
To Felucia
Skywalker and Kenobi will go.
A trail long cold it is, yet still
lay hidden there a clue might be.
Question all who were present the day
of Sifo-Dyas's death, you must.
And what of the sealed file?
Speak with the Chancellor
personally I will,
to see what part in this the politics
of the Senate have played.
Master Sifo-Dyas?
Forgive me, I'm afraid I am not familiar
with that name.
Died some time ago he did on Felucia.
Investigating his death we are,
and yet sealed by the Chancellor's
office some of his files were.
And what is the nature
of your investigation?
A Jedi matter it is, Chancellor.
Add to your troubles I would not.
That is very considerate, Master Yoda.
May I at least ask when Master...
Sifo-Dyas.
Yes, Master Sifo-Dyas,
may I ask when he was killed?
Over 10 years ago it was.
Well, that explains it.
I'm afraid this was before my time.
Ten years ago, I was a humble Senator
serving the planet Naboo.
Only my predecessor,
Chancellor Valorum,
would have the answers you seek.
I suggest you speak with him.
Very well. Thank you, Chancellor.
I have spoken with
the tribal leaders on Felucia.
They use a very ancient dialect
which is hard to understand
but from what I can make out,
when Master Sifo-Dyas died,
he was not alone.
There was a second Jedi
here with him.
And the name of this second Jedi?
Either I don't understand them
or they won't say. It's hard to tell.
This is a primitive people
we are dealing with.
After his death,
they cremated Sifo-Dyas's body
and I'm afraid the trail goes cold there.
Did you have any success
with the Chancellor?
As much success as usual,
I am afraid.
Pointed in another direction I am now,
to speak with Valorum I go.
It's been a long time, my friend.
What can I do for you?
A file sealed by your administration
the Jedi Council has come across.
The subject of the file?
Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas.
Sifo-Dyas?
When I was Chancellor,
I sent him on a mission to deal
with a flare up in the Pyke syndicate.
The Pykes?
A powerful part of the spice cartel.
Their criminal activities
had allowed them
to almost completely control
the production of raw spice
used to create a powerful drug.
We were facing a full scale war
underneath the surface of Coruscant.
Knowing of his expertise
on the Underworld,
I contacted Master Sifo-Dyas
to stabilize the problem.
Know of this, the Jedi Council did not.
The Senate Committee
assigned to the matter
feared that open discussions
with such a criminal element
could legitimize their activities
and give strength to opposition leaders
within the bureaucracy.
Secrecy was our only choice.
The timing of these negotiations,
when were they to take place?
I cannot remember the precise timing,
I'm afraid. It was so long ago.
I do remember that
the talks were postponed
not long after our delegates
arrived on Oba Diah.
Something about a flare up
of activity on Felucia.
Yes, intervene on Felucia,
the Council insisted Sifo-Dyas did,
but tell me, Chancellor, who was
the other Jedi you sent with Sifo-Dyas?
Other Jedi? I know of no other Jedi.
There was only my personal aide,
Silman, and Sifo-Dyas.
I'm afraid they were
both killed on Felucia.
Personal aid? Silman?
Tell me, why do the Jedi
look for Sifo-Dyas?
What trail are they following?
If there is a trail, it is unknown to me.
Retrace your steps,
find this loose end, and eliminate it.
I understand what is at stake, my Lord.
I will go to the Pykes and take care of it.
This is not the first time you have
proven to be clumsy, Lord Tyranus.
- You know the price of failure.
The Felucians know
nothing of this Silman.
No one there seems
to know anything about him.
What's that symbol he's wearing?
The symbol of the high Chancellor
before the war, Chancellor Valorum.
So, we have one dead Jedi with
no physical evidence of a body,
a second Jedi who appeared
on Felucia that we have no record of,
and now this Silman, personal attache
to the Chancellor, is missing?
Yet, now we know Sifo-Dyas
and Silman were both on Oba Diah,
according to Chancellor Valorum.
The crashed shuttle I found was located
on a moon which orbits the Pyke planet.
Hmm. To the Pykes you must go,
to Oba Diah, yes.
I cannot remember the last time
a Jedi came here.
Many years it has been.
Funny you should say that.
We're looking for a Jedi that got
lost here. His name is Sifo-Dyas.
Oh, the Jedi Sifo-Dyas was here,
but that was a long time ago.
Master Sifo-Dyas's ship was found
crashed on a moon orbiting this world.
What you found, we know nothing of.
Would the Jedi like
to join us for a refreshment?
The Pykes offer is kindly accepted.
To friendship.
- Friendship.
What an interesting necklace that is.
May I have a look?
Perhaps the Pykes have taken
enough of the Jedi's time.
Oh, no, no. It's no bother at all,
the Jedi are happy
to know all the Pykes' secrets.
We have no quarrel with the Jedi.
Maybe you should tell us
why you're wearing
the crest of the Chancellor's
personal advisor?
I am confused.
Is the Jedi looking for a Jedi Master
or someone else?
Stop playing games.
Sifo-Dyas was traveling with an advisor.
They were sent here
to negotiate with you.
Well, it looks like you have finally
put the pieces together.
The man you are looking for is here.
The Pykes wanted to gain an advantage
over the other crime families,
so alliances were made.
One alliance was with
a man named Tyranus.
I've heard that name before,
Jango Fett mentioned it during
my Kamino investigation.
Tyranus wanted Sifo-Dyas dead,
the Pykes were well paid
to shoot down his ship.
However, any man that is willing to pay
to have a Jedi killed is dangerous,
and unpredictable.
The Pykes inspected the crash,
to retrieve the Jedi's body for proof.
But, with the dead Jedi,
the Pykes found another, still alive.
Silman, the Chancellor's aide?
The Pykes gave Tyranus Sifo-Dyas,
but the Pykes did not
tell Tyranus of Silman.
The Pykes needed insurance.
Insurance?
Yes, and now the Pykes can bargain.
We give you Silman, you forget about
the Pykes' treachery against the Jedi.
Hello?
- Who's there?
- We are Jedi sent to find you.
Jedi?
To find me?
Why me?
I was betrayed, forgotten. Long ago.
No one knew you were alive.
Quick. Maybe you have some food.
Have you any food?
Of course.
Oh!
Thank you, my friend. A supply bar!
Mmm! Mmm! Delicious.
You see, I was so frightened
I would have nothing to serve.
Serve?
My babies, they get so angry
when I have nothing to serve.
We might have a problem here.
Tyranus, you are no longer
welcome here.
I think you've been cooped up
in here too long, old man.
We've come to take you home.
Home? No, no, this is my home!
I can't leave my friends.
You were traveling with
Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas.
Tell us what happed to him.
Sifo-Dyas?
He died.
Died. Died. Died. Died.
Tricked we were.
The Pykes are not to be trusted.
Oh, no. No, no, no. Oh, no, no, no.
But the Pykes were not the ones.
No, no, the Pykes were not the reason.
Who was responsible?
Someone powerful...
Someone who wanted to be Sifo-Dyas!
Why?
All is deception.
Can't you see... Because... Because...
Dooku! For once you actually came
to do your own dirty work.
Sometimes things
are just that important.
Ah!
You have no business
left with the Pykes, Tyranus.
Tyranus?
You are the man called Tyranus?
I told you everything
you needed to know
on Geonosis
all those years ago, Kenobi.
You should have joined me.
Sifo-Dyas understood.
He saw the future,
that is why he helped me.
You lie!
Minister Lom, if you are going
to help us, now is the time.
Kill Tyranus!
I'll give you a push!
Know now we do,
that guide the creation of the clones
from the beginning, Dooku did.
Hmm.
Our enemy created an army for us.
If this was known,
public confidence in the war effort,
the Jedi and the Republic would vanish.
There would be mass chaos.
Cover up this discovery we must.
No one,
not even the Chancellor may know.
Valiant men,
the clones have proven to be,
saved my life and yours
they have many times.
Believe in them we must,
win the war swiftly we must,
before our enemy's designs
reach completion,
whatever they may be.
Are you sure
we are taking the right path?
The right path, no.
The only path, yes.
Designed by the Dark Lord of the Sith,
this web is.
For now, play his game we must.