War on many fronts!
While battles are fought
by Clones in the field.
A different war is waged
on the Galactic Senate.
As heavy loses add up
a group of senators lead
by Halle Burtoni of Comino
propose an escalation
of troop production
Senator Padme Amidala, recognizing that
more troops will only prolong the fighting.
Works tirelessly with her allies to
introduce a bill to cut military spending
and stop the creation
of more clone troopers.
Yes of course Senator. Thank
you for telling me yourself.
I completely understand.
Did we loose someone else's vote?
Senator Stank is worried
about Republic opinion.
But he wants us to know
how very sorry he is.
Sorry doesn't get us votes.
We will get votes, when in your speech,
you convince people to stand
up for what they know is right.
I hope you're right, Uncle.
You have been doing an amazing
job, rallying votes to our side.
Choose cool Senator Farr.
Perhaps, I am the most
influential man on Rodia, Lolo.
But after all the mistakes I've made,
peace...
is what matters to me now.
Senator Amidala,
they're ready for your
speech now. It's time.
We'll see you in the
chamber, Senator Amidala.
Good luck, Padme.
It is quite exciting.
Exciting isn't exactly
the word I would use.
I think terrifying is more appropriate.
Pay her no mind Senator Organa...
Even as a girl, Padme
down played her strengths
helps to maintain the
element of surprise.
I learned it from you.
See you inside Senators.
The creation of more
warriors will not end this war
the financial cost alone will
bankrupt and cripple the Republic.
By adding more clones to the conflict,
we're only escalating the
destruction, not winning the war.
Which is why we must vote for this
resolution to promote more diplomacy,
and to bring an end to
this killing, and hatred.
Oh, it wasn't a compliment.
You shouldn't make speeches like that.
It's unpatriotic.
The only thing I find
unpatriotic is your war mongering.
Truly,
you have turned the tide.
My dear, you were brilliant.
Thank you. But perhaps,
we should wait to we actually win the
vote before we make a victory speech.
What a novel idea.
Imagine that.
Amadala's actually making
sense for once in her life.
Senator Burtoni. This is
a private conversation.
Private conversation or
separatist conspiracy?
How dare you? We're not pro separatist.
We want to end the war.
- Committing more troops to the front
lines will not allow diplomacy to resume.
Diplomacy failed the Republic long ago.
Senators, please.
Senator Burtoni,
the Kaminoans might have
bartered their creation
of the clones into a seat
in the Galactic Senate.
But this is not give you free reign.
Thank you for visiting, Senator.
We would like to continue our
meeting now... if you don't mind.
Enjoy your moment in
the spot light Senators.
This war will not end soon.
Well, we must be doing something
right if we've rattled Senator Burtoni.
What matters is that we've made great
strides in our fight against this bill.
I know you've done a wonderful
job leading the effort
I'm just trying to do what's right.
I only wish I'd tried
doing that a long time ago.
You're doing it now.
To victory and an end to this war.
To victories.
My heart,
I can't breathe.
Uncle? What is it?
Ono! It's his heart!
Please! Someone get help!
And we are all aware that
Ono Condo was a flawed man.
He knew better than
anyone of his own mistakes.
But he never compromised his principals.
And what he did, he did for his people.
Their needs always came first.
Senator, if you need anything.
What we need is to get
his resolution passed.
He was my mentor.
I don't know how to carry
on without him guiding me.
I know. No one could
ever take his place.
Excuse me. Chancellor Palpatine has
summoned both of you to his chambers.
What's happened?
I'm afraid my friends that Lieutenant
Divo here has some questions
about Senator Farr.
Do you know of anyone who...
how to put this...
hated Senator Farr?
Enough to kill him?
What?
I'll need to find out who
wanted to hurt Senator Farr...
Actually kill him
would be more accurate.
What with him being dead.
No one wanted him dead
Everyone loved him
Well, that's obviously
not true or I wouldn't
be here, and he would.
Lieutenant, even Ono's
political enemies respected him
we need time to deal with this situation
Time, time, there's no time. A murderers
on the lose and it's my job to find him.
Ahem
what makes you think it was murder
poison of course
the politician's preferred method
found a chemical in his blood
stream, killed him right away.
It's an obvious case.
Politicians always
have something to hide.
And it always come back to haunt them.
Am I right?
Oh! Look who I am asking
a room full of politicians
So, one of Farr's secrets
must have resurfaced.
Ono had no secrets.
That's not it.
Perhaps someone was upset
about the Clone troop bill
currently on the floor.
It's very controversial
Thank you Senator Amadala, is it?
But I have my theory
and I'll follow my
hunch if you don't mind.
After all I am the
inspector. your the senator.
So I'll handle the inspecting
and you can stick to the 'senating'.
Good day.
Murder.
It's inconceivable.
Who would wish Ono Conda
harm? What if it's the BIM.
What if we're all being targeted.
Speculation gets us no where.
There is work to do, we should
double our efforts on the vote
It'll be even harder with Ono gone.
No, no, we should delay the vote.
But why? No one will give the vote their full
attention they know what's happened to Ono.
Well, maybe I can put
a motion on the floor
I don't think anyone will
object given the circumstances.
Good
and we'll have time to
conduct our own investigation
Detective Divo specifically asked us
not to interfere.
- Well he didn't exactly
inspire confidence did he?
He didn't know Ono.
We did.
We'll have a far easier
time looking into this
than detective Divo will.
Running around could
disrupt our coalition
Yet you still seem determined
to see this through.
Indeed I am.
and I don't supposed
you'd considering bringing
Captain Tyfo along with you? No.
I'd rather do this quietly
then perhaps Sentator Organa,
you should accompany her.
I think that's an excellent idea.
I don't need a guardian.
Of course not my dear
think of it as precautionary.
Don't worry, I won't get in your way.
- very well, I don't
have any objections.
And I know exactly where to start.
You're suggesting one of
us killed Ono Conda Farr.
How delightful. I don't
find any of this amusing.
Neither do I.
Every time Ono opened his befuddled mouth it
gave us another quote to use in our fund-raising.
Why would we kill our
best source of income.
You both opposed Ono's
ideas in the senate.
With enough at stake
maybe you decided to silence his voice
for good. Ono Conda
and I were often at odds
but I respected him.
- I respected him greatly.
- For the record,
I had no respect for
Ono Conda what so ever.
Ono had a secret meeting at the docks on
the direct Major on the night before he died.
And you just happened to
know about this meeting how?
Oh, I was having Ono followed.
Just because I respected Ono,
doesn't mean I wasn't trying
to get dirt on him. Of course.
The point is... a clandestined off the
books meeting under cover of darkness.
Perhaps that location holds some clue.
Fine, I will go look.
But whatever we find,
I'll have more questions
for both of you.
Have I said that I think we're
very far out of our element here?
Yes, Bail. I believed that
you've mentioned once or twice.
Using this investigation to bury your
grief, might not be the best way to...
I'm not.
Then why can't you just
leave it to Lieutenant Divo?
Padme!
Wait! Watch out!
Senator Amadala is it possible
you might be going deaf?
Lieutenant?
Because when I said I didn't want you
to interfere with my investigation.
I can only assume you didn't hear me.
I had some information about
a lead here at the docks.
Which you naturally brought to me straight
away so I could investigate... only...
no wait.. you did exactly
the opposite of that.
There are rules senator
my friend was murdered.
I don't care about rules.
Don't care about rules?
My dears without rules
there's only chaos. everyone
must care about rules.
We know that.
But now you've alerted the
killer that you're on to him.
And my investigation
is that much harder.
Do you have any idea how many
reports I'll have to file now.
We alerted the killer.
Yes, that is what I'm saying.
What if we were sent here on purpose.
To the docks?
Yes!
What if this was all a setup.
What if Dechee sent us here
just so he could kill us.
If we hurry we might still be able to
catch Dechee before
he leaves the senate.
Agreed!
But wait, I'm still investigating.
This is still an active crime
scene you can't... oh fine.
Senator Dechee, I'm
sure you're surprised
to see me, after what
you. Oh! he's dead.
He's been stabbed.
This is definitely going
to require another report.
The killer is obviously
targeting the leadership.
You must stay here under my protection.
Why? So the killer can
take us all out at once?
Oh, that's preposterous.
Even if the killer did
get through my security,
it's very unlikely that all
of you would end up dead.
We are far to easy a
target sitting here.
I am leaving.
No you can't leave Lolo. I think...
in this instance, the
Inspector is right.
Out of my way
Oh, who else knew you
were going to the docks.
Just Senator Bertoni. She was the
only other one in the room with us.
Bertoni, eh?
Sir, Senator Bertoni is not here.
Ah!
Looks like that long necked Kaminonan
has flown the coop.
It's been a difficult time.
You've handled yourself well.
I had to try.
Ono believed if you see injustice
you can't wait for
someone else to fix it.
You must stand up and get involved.
He did.
Help, I have been attacked.
She's over there.
She tried to kill me.
What happened?
Senator Bertoni.
She jumped me.
She's in the east wing corridor. Hurry!
Guards go.
You're insane.
I didn't kill anyone.
Last thing I remember I
was walking to my office.
Then I woke up here.
Senator Lolo has a very different story.
She says you attacked her.
Attacked her?
Lolo?
If I ever attack someone
I hope it will be
someone mildly important.
Someone like Senator Farr?
Ono was a harmless bug.
I wouldn't bother killing him.
And Dechee was my ally.
I've been thinking about how you
were in Senator Amadala's office
right before Farr died.
So what?
And I've been thinking about
how you were in Dechee's
office to hear about
the meeting at the docks.
A meeting I think Farr has with you.
It wasn't me. You have no proof.
No? I have this.
I ordered an extensive forensic
report on Farr as soon as he died.
The poison which killed Farr
only affected Rodian blood.
And it was developed
by Kamonian scientists.
But.. that's...
I didn't kill him.
You're Kamanoain. You
had access to the poison.
That's motive, means,
and opportunity. Guards!
But the scan must be wrong.
If the poison was in all our drinks.
Lolo would have died too.
What?
She's Rodian. She'd
have been poisoned too.
Unless she didn't drink.
But you drank, right Lolo?
Lolo,
you didn't drink.
Did you?
You're right, I should
have pretended to drink.
Alright, You're coming
with me, for insurance.
Why did you kill Ono?
He brought war to my planet.
No! He made a mistake, Lolo.
Which everyone seemed to
forget, including you. I didn't.
Did you honestly think he had
the moral right to lead us?
After he betrayed us?
He was sorry!
He was weak!
We needed someone of strength
to stand against this war.
I tried to scare him at the docks.
But he wouldn't go
away, so I removed him.
And then I heard Dechee
heard about the meeting.
He had to go too.
Halt! Put down your weapon.
With the final votes tallied.
Let it be known that
the motion to stop the
the creation of more
clone troops has failed.
And the continued
manufacturing of clone troopers
shall proceed as scheduled
After all that.
We lost.
I know this decision
was most unexpected.
I myself don't support it, but,
democracy must stand.
Of course, you were right chancellor.
Actually, given recent events
perhaps it is for the best.
How can we justify
fortifying our security
here in the senate.
If we don't provide
reenforcement on the front lines.
You see,
the victory of the clone army, for now,
is the only thing that
can lead us to peace.