Clone crisis!
After the mysterious death
of his friend Tup,
ARC Trooper Fives
embarked on an investigation,
which led to the discovery
of a hidden chip
which is placed inside clone troopers
when they are still embryos.
The Kaminoan scientist Nala Se
claims the chip is harmless
and is meant to restrain the clones
from violent unpredictable action.
Fives claims otherwise,
and has convinced
Jedi Master Shaak Ti
to allow him to plead his case
directly to Supreme Chancellor
Palpatine on Coruscant.
Attention.
Please be advised
we have arrived at Coruscant
and will be touching down
at our destination shortly.
No. Wait.
No. What was that?
What did you do?
You drugged me.
Greetings, Master Jedi.
The Chancellor is waiting inside.
Tup... The mission...
AZI-3...
Master Shaak Ti,
it is good to see you again.
I trust you've kept this matter
extremely confidential.
Of course, Chancellor.
Ah, good.
So this is the clone
who has caused so much alarm?
No... No, you drugged me.
She...
There, there, soldier,
don't strain yourself.
Sir.
Guards, let him down, please.
Now, Trooper,
what brings you before me?
The chips, Chancellor.
Chips?
These were removed
from both clone troopers.
Clone Trooper Fives claims
they are the cause of the problem.
Those are inhibitor chips,
which are placed in clones
to make them less aggressive
and more compliant to orders.
I tried to explain to this clone
that they are placed in them
for his own good,
but he removed his chip nonetheless.
Our own good?
This thing they put in us
malfunctioned in Clone Trooper Tup.
I removed his and analyzed it.
There were signs of rapid decay.
And we're positive
this has nothing to do with a virus?
No, we still do not know for sure
what caused Trooper Tup to kill.
We only know that his chip failed.
And now this clone
has removed his own chip,
which makes him
a risk to himself and others.
I'm not at risk.
Sir, they're covering something up,
I know it.
If it's not them,
then it's a Separatist plot.
They use this chip against us
to make us more violent than less.
That's why Tup killed General Tiplar.
A Separatist plot
from before the war even started?
That seems unlikely,
don't you agree, Master Shaak Ti?
It does, Chancellor.
It seems very unlikely.
It is absolutely impossible.
What we have here is a single
malfunction to one clone's inhibitor chip
caused by a virus,
Separatist plot or not.
Perhaps it would be best
if Clone Trooper Fives and I
discussed this without your presence.
Chancellor, I must object.
Please, Master Jedi, trust me.
I will not be alone.
I have my security here.
I want this soldier to feel
he is having a fair say in this matter.
Now,
where were we?
- No! Let me go!
- Guards!
No! You!
He tried to kill me. It was so sudden.
You were right, Doctor,
he must have gone mad
without his chip.
You have done all you can, Doctor.
I trust you will keep these safe.
Of course, Chancellor.
Fives, stop!
Fives!
Close the blast doors!
I can't believe Fives would try
to assassinate the Chancellor.
The Kaminoans feel a virus
corrupted the Clone's inhibitor chip,
which has led to this behavior.
ARC Trooper Fives feels
he is the victim of a plot,
Separatist or otherwise.
All security and clone forces
on Coruscant
have been ordered to join the manhunt.
The Chancellor has been
moved to his Senate quarters
and the perimeter has been secured.
However, Jedi involvement
has not been requested.
That's a little odd, isn't it?
Hmm. Discover the truth we must.
If there is a plot involving the clones,
we must get to the bottom of it.
We will investigate quietly, undercover.
We must make sure
this clone is not killed.
I'll handle this investigation.
Fives was part of the 501 st.
If Rex and I find him, he'll trust us.
Be wary.
Since he removed his inhibitor chip,
Fives may no longer be
the man you once knew.
- Here you go.
- Thank you, ladies.
Have a good time on Coruscant, now.
Thank you.
Hey, pal, where to?
Take me to 79's.
The clone bar?
Oh! You're a clone, eh?
Look, just shut up and drive.
Okay, you got it.
So, heading out
for a little fun on the town, eh?
I didn't know clones could have fun.
There's a lot you don't know
about clones.
No one knows.
Ooh, very mysterious, eh?
I like a good mystery.
Yeah? You ever hear the one
about the people engineered to kill,
engineered to kill their best friends,
their leaders,
and they don't even know it?
I'm a cab driver, pal.
I hear stories like that all the time.
Hey. You paying for this ride or what?
Ah, bill it to the Republic.
"Bill it to the Republic."
Good one, brother.
Lousy cheap clones!
It's your credit, pal.
You're paying for this.
Ah, your mother's a droid.
Get out of here.
Droid lover!
Come on, brother, let's go inside.
Corporal, that's a nice hat you got there.
Mind if I see it?
Oh, sure. Yeah. Sure, you got it.
- To the Republic!
Can I get you fellas anything?
I think it's time for another round.
Hey, bartender!
Hey, see you around, brother.
Kix, Jesse.
To the 212th!
Down the hatch, boys! Ah!
Fan out and check IDs.
So, I guess the 501 st
is back on Coruscant.
Oh, yeah, we just got back
from Ringo Vinda.
The strangest thing
happened out there.
Yeah, I know.
Fives?
Whoa! What's going on?
They say you tried
to assassinate the Chancellor!
And that you're infected
with that virus that killed Tup.
I don't have time to explain right now.
All I can tell you
is that I'm being framed.
All of us, even the Jedi,
are in grave danger.
But what can I do, Fives?
How can I help?
I need to talk to Rex, or...
Or General Skywalker.
Well, they've been tasked with
finding you. Just turn yourself in!
No! No, I'll never get to them.
You don't understand.
What I'm mixed up in,
it goes all the way to the top.
The highest levels
are involved in the conspiracy.
I have to talk to General Skywalker
and Rex directly, alone.
Look, I can contact Rex, but I can't
guarantee he'll bring the General.
Good, good, good.
Thanks, Kix. I appreciate it.
Here. Here are the coordinates.
Just make sure he meets me there.
Right. Good luck, Fives.
Identification, please.
Have you seen this clone?
- Uh... No, sir. I haven't seen him.
- All right. Move along.
Identification, please.
All right, you guys check out.
Move along.
Sir, the fugitive clone has been spotted
by one of our probes in sector I-9.
Well, these are the coordinates
Kix gave us.
Let's hope Fives is inside.
I hope
he knows what he's doing.
Fives?
Fives, we're here.
Come on out,
we just want to talk to you.
General Skywalker, thank you.
Thank you for trusting me.
Have you come without troops?
We have.
Put down your weapons, then.
I don't think so, Fives.
Please, sir.
Please, I'm unarmed.
All right, I'm putting my pistols down.
What are we here for, Fives?
I need your help.
I know you do. We know you're not well.
It's been rough for you
these past couple days.
I'm not crazy!
Please. Please, just...
Just hear what I have to say.
We're here to help you, Fives.
Just come with us.
Let us take you back to the Temple.
No!
I just need you to listen to me. Please.
I'm not really sure
we have any other choice.
I was framed because I know the truth.
The truth about a plot,
a massive deception!
By whom?
Well, there's a sinister plot in the works
against the Jedi.
I have proof of it.
I can prove that everything
that I know is true
beyond a shadow of a doubt!
Show me the evidence.
The evidence is in here.
It's in here. It's in all of us,
every clone!
What is it?
Organic chips,
built into our genetic code
to make us do
whatever someone wants,
even kill the Jedi.
It's all in here!
Let's just get you some help first,
then we can review everything.
It'll be okay, Fives. We'll sort this out.
You don't believe me!
We're closing in on the target.
Everyone be ready.
Fives, we are listening to you.
We only want to help.
How do I know you're not tricking me?
How do I know it won't be a trap?
The Chancellor will try to kill me!
I promise you that!
The Chancellor?
He's in on it!
I don't know to what extent.
But I know he orchestrated much of this.
He told me in the medical bay!
He told you?
When you tried to assassinate him?
You have gone too far, Fives.
The Chancellor is incapable
of what you claim.
He is!
I swear to you, General.
You have no idea...
Stand down, soldier! Stand down!
Get on your knees!
No! No! No! Stay back!
Don't do it! Don't do it, soldier!
Get away from me!
Fives, no!
Fives!
- Fives!
- Get this ray shield off!
Fives!
Brother!
Call for help! We need a medic!
Rex...
Fives.
This... It's bigger than any of us...
Than anything I could have imagined.
I never meant to...
I only wanted to do my duty.
Brother...
Fives, stay with me, Fives!
Fives!
The mission...
The nightmares...
They're finally over.
Fives?
No, Fives... Come on, Fives.
Don't go! Stay with me. Stay with me.
Fives! Fives!
Don't go.
No!
Oh, no.
A tragic situation, indeed.
About the clone's breakdowns,
have we discovered any new evidence?
I've had my own personal doctors
examine both bodies.
It appears Nala Se did miss something
in her examination.
Another cause your doctors found?
A parasite, native to Ringo Vinda.
Probably in a canteen of water
they both shared.
It did cause the inhibitors to decay,
once the parasite had taken hold.
It is very rare.
However, just to be cautious,
we have prepared an inoculation
for every clone trooper in our army.
So, I guess it's over, then?
Yes, we can finally put this
whole wretched situation behind us.
We must direct our attention
back to the war at hand.
Each day we grow
closer and closer to victory.
Lord Tyranus, have you received
the inhibitor chip that you requested?
I have indeed.
You have done well, Doctor.
Our plan has gone
undiscovered, Master.
The clone in question is now dead
and the Jedi still suspect nothing.
Good.
Destroy all evidence.
When the time comes,
no one will be able to stop our plan
to execute Order 66.