A world under siege!
The Separatists have launched
a massive offensive
against the planet Ryloth.
A blockade of deadly battleships
has cut off any support
for the dwindling Republic defenses.
Though they have fought valiantly
with the help of
Twi'lek freedom fighter Cham Syndulla,
hope is fading for Jedi Master Di
and his men as the droid army closes in.
Master Jedi!
We're running out of food and water,
and our heavy weapons systems
are out of power.
I'll contact our forces in orbit.
Admiral Dao, this is General Di.
We're in trouble down here.
We need those supplies immediately.
I understand, General,
but I am in no position to help.
We are critically low
on fuel and ammunition.
Contact the Jedi Council again!
Tell them reinforcements
must be dispatched without delay!
If help does not arrive soon, the entire
Outer Rim garrison will be wiped out.
Surely there must be
something you can do...
The main reactor's been hit, sir.
Systems are shutting down.
We are dead in space.
With regret, I report that
my fleet will no longer be able
to provide protection for
the troops on Ryloth.
I repeat my request
that help be sent right away.
The shields are gone! We have no...
Trapped on Ryloth,
Master Di and his men are.
My trade mission was successful.
Thank you for asking.
But what's the matter?
You all look very somber.
Senator, the fleet protecting Ryloth
has been destroyed,
and the supply lines have been cut.
The troops are out of food,
fuel, ammunition,
and the civilian population is starving.
That is grim news.
Our blockade runners should be able
to penetrate the Separatist lines
and drop relief supplies,
but they do not have the range
to reach Ryloth.
The planet Toydaria is 2,000 parsecs closer
than the nearest fleet.
If the blockade runners
can supply from there,
they might reach Ryloth in time.
What would you have me do?
We've dispatched a ship loaded with
relief supplies to meet you on Toydaria.
You are a more experienced diplomat
than the representative from Naboo
who is already there.
Senator Amidala is
an excellent negotiator. I am sure...
Senator Amidala
could not leave the Senate.
Representative Binks
accompanied the shipment.
You must negotiate the treaty so that
we can dispatch ships from Toydaria
and get Ryloth the
relief supplies it needs.
I understand perfectly.
This had better be important.
Sir, we intercepted a coded transmission
between Senator Organa
and the Jedi Council.
We were able to partially unscramble it.
The Jedi have sent Senator Organa
to Toydaria to negotiate a treaty,
which would allow them to send
relief supplies to their forces on Ryloth.
Send a message to Senator Lott Dod
of the Trade Federation.
I wish to speak with him immediately.
Stop where you are, offworlder.
We will provide you whatever you need
to continue your journey,
but you may not leave this ship.
I am Senator Bail Organa
of the Galactic Republic.
I come to speak with
the High Exalted King of Toydaria.
Hi-lo!
Let meesa through!
Meesa on a diplomatic mission.
Senator Organa!
Itsa pleasure to be seeing yousa.
And you, Representative Binks. Shall we?
Our laws of hospitality
demand that we offer assistance,
but this planet is closed to offworlders.
We are obliged to deliver our message
to your king in person.
It won't take a minute.
Hi-lo? Yousa Majesty?
Let me do the talking, okay?
State your business, offworlders.
Representative Binks of Naboo.
Senator Bail Organa of Alderaan, sire.
We have come to ask for your help.
Perhaps you failed to pay attention
to the Senate orientation.
They should have explained
that Toydaria is a neutral system.
We are not part of the Republic.
Yes, Your Majesty.
That is why we have come before you
as friends.
There is a humanitarian crisis on Ryloth.
Millions will be starving and dying
without your help.
My esteemed colleague and I humbly beg
that you allow us to use Toydaria
as a staging ground
to supply the planet with relief aid.
Do not make your decision in haste,
Your Majesty.
There are other factors
you might wish to consider.
I believe you know Lott Dod,
Senator for the Trade Federation.
Yes, we are acquainted. Senator.
Begging Your Highness,
whatsa he doing here?
Why shouldn't he be?
Toydaria has an important contract
with his Trade Federation.
The Trade Federation is too chummy
with the Separatists for my taste.
We have nothing to do
with the Separatists!
Nute Gunray is an extremist.
His views do not reflect
those of the Trade Federation.
Perhaps not.
But you can understand the confusion.
We are only here to ensure that
nothing jeopardizes the agreement
between Toydaria
and the Trade Federation.
Naboo and Alderaan have a long tradition
of providing humanitarian aid.
- I see no reason for conflict.
- Nor do I.
The people of Ryloth are suffering,
and compassion
is a sacred Toydarian value.
Honesty is also a Toydarian value,
is it not?
I'm sure the Senator mentioned
the Separatist blockade around Ryloth.
A blockade? Is this true?
Yes, Your Majesty, but it changes nothing.
It changes everything.
If the Separatists are blockading
the planet and we help the Republic,
it will destroy our neutrality.
I must convene my ministers,
then we shall hear your arguments.
General Di, the right flank has collapsed.
The droids will be closing in
on our position.
What about reinforcements?
Communication has been spotty.
I promise you, Cham,
the Republic will not abandon Ryloth.
I've heard enough of your promises, Jedi.
The fact remains, if we stay here without
reinforcements, we're all going to die.
Gobi, tell the people we're leaving.
Yes, sir.
I don't think you understand.
The right flank has collapsed.
There's no leaving.
We're stuck here together.
We will now hear arguments
in the matter of using Toydarian territory
to aid the shipment of relief supplies
to the citizens of Ryloth.
- Senator Organa.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
The operation the Republic proposes
is purely humanitarian.
We wish to deliver food and
medical supplies to the people of Ryloth.
But if you won't listen to me, wise king,
listen to Senator Orn Free Taa of Ryloth,
who is well aware
of the suffering of his people.
Your Highness, our cities lie in ruins.
Our transportation hubs are all but
destroyed, so I cannot return home.
Our crops burn.
The Twi'lek people are starving,
and they will die if no aid comes to them.
I appeal to you, great king.
The basic tenets of our morality,
and even our constitution,
demand that we help those in need.
Those ideals are noble,
but we must be careful
that our compassion does not
draw us into this war.
Senator Dod, if you please.
Great king,
Senator Organa is deceiving you.
The inconvenient fact remains that
this is a war, and Ryloth is a battlefield.
The planet is under a Separatist blockade
because Jedi Knights and clone soldiers
are battling the droid army
for control of the surface.
This will not be a humanitarian base.
It will be a military base.
The Separatist Senate will see it
as a violation of your neutrality.
That, in turn, will expose
the Trade Federation's ships
to attacks from the Separatists
and force us to cease trade with Toydaria,
a situation desirable to no one.
Your Majesty, the people of Ryloth
did not ask to be invaded.
Do not let them suffer
because war came to them.
I sympathize with
the plight of the Twi'leks,
but this is not about saving them when
they are fighting against the Separatists.
Thank you, Senators.
You have given us much to consider.
I will summon you
once I have made my decision.
Come on, hurry, hurry!
Captain, is the gunship ready?
Yes, sir, but it's too small
to evacuate the refugees.
No escape? But our families are with us.
If we reconfigure the fuel system,
we can turn the ship
into a bomb big enough
to collapse the pass, here.
The enemy will then only be able to
engage us on one front, from this ravine.
While we provide cover,
the Twi'leks will have time to escape
with the families over the mountain.
Brilliant strategy, General.
I'll go tell the men.
After considerable debate,
I have made my decision.
I am sorry, Senator Organa.
But for the sake of my people,
Toydaria must remain neutral.
A wise ruling, Your Majesty.
That did not go well.
What are weesa gonna do now?
My friends.
Toydaria cannot turn a blind eye
to the suffering of Ryloth.
The Twi'leks are innocent victims
caught between the warring factions
through no fault of their own.
I'm glad you agree, Your Highness.
What are you prepared to do?
You may use Toydaria to transfer
the supplies you brought with you.
That's only enough food for one,
maybe two rotations.
It will have to do.
And you must guarantee
that the Trade Federation will not be able
to link Toydaria to the mission.
Agreed. I have an idea.
I'll signal you
when the ships are ready to depart.
Meesa won't let you down, Senator.
We're pleased you could join us, Senator.
- Your Majesty.
- The pleasure is mine.
Formal dinners are so tedious.
I'm afraid that pressing matters require me
to make immediate contact with Alderaan.
But I leave you in the capable hands
of my colleague, Representative Binks.
General, we're loading the rest of
the explosives onto the gunship.
Very good, Captain. Ready the men.
All units, prepare for attack!
We won't be able
to hold off the droids for long.
You'll have to move quickly
to get your families out of danger.
Cham is still angry. He feels betrayed.
He counted on Republic assistance,
and it didn't come.
War turns promises into hopes.
I wish it wasn't so.
- Tell him.
- I will.
Captain Keeli, tell the pilots
to move the gunship into position.
This is Command.
Are all the charges in place?
Copy that. We're all ready.
The droid army is closing.
As soon as they are in range,
blow up the gunship.
There is a gunship blocking our way.
OM-5, OM-7, go check it out.
Roger, roger.
Careful. It might be full of clones.
No clones, just explosives.
Explosives?
Gotcha!
Halt, halt! We cannot get through.
We will have to find another way around.
Move those supplies into the transport
as soon as possible.
Repeat. The ships are ready to launch.
Uh, lookie, lookie!
Meesa proposing a conceptual work of art
to honor the ambassador
of Trade Federation.
Let's see, I'll take that one. Mmm-hmm.
Uh-oh.
Yeah, just give me... You done with that?
That's really good.
I heard Toydarians really like that,
but I'm taking it.
Thank you very much.
I'm sure you're finished with that.
Did you enjoy that? Did you like that one?
Well, I'll take it, thank you.
Uh...
Excuse me. Thank you. I'll take that.
Gentlemen and... gentlemen.
Here, let's try this one.
You thought I was going to drop...
I... Here we go!
Whoo!
Spinning. One, two, three! Ah!
Thank you very much.
That is conceptual art piece.
Thank you.
Meesa just sharing my Gungan art
with yousa and...
And meesa.
What are you looking at?
Meesa look at nothing.
No, no, no. Meesa look at nothing.
Meesa creating and sharing.
Gungan ritual-style art
with Trade Federation
to promote love and understanding.
Steady. Remember, we have to buy
as much time for the Twi'leks as possible.
Yes, sir.
For the Republic! For the Twi'leks!
- Captain Keeli!
- I'm not finished yet, sir.
We can do this, General.
Well, let's make the end memorable.
This is
Republic blockade runner 0-niner-niner.
We have broken through.
The Twi'leks will live
to fight another day.
The supplies have
arrived at the drop point.
It's food and medical supplies
from the Republic!
Safe journey, my friends.
I hope when we meet again,
it is under more pleasant circumstances.
Stop right there!
You look pale, Senator.
I have just received information
that a fleet of Republic ships has
penetrated the blockade around Ryloth.
If the Trade Federation
has proof of any treaty violation,
you are welcome to present it
to the full Senate.
It takes years for the Senate
to decide anything.
You play a dangerous game, Organa.
Next time, you will not get away with this.
The Republic has heart, my friend,
but I am not convinced
it has the strength to prevail.
However, after what I witnessed
here today,
perhaps it is time
I reconsidered our neutrality.
Tell the Jedi
I am open to meeting with them.
Master Yoda will be glad to hear it.
For now, at least,
the people of Ryloth shall endure.