A calculated risk!
Following a costly victory
on the planet Malastare,
Chancellor Palpatine orders Jedi Knights
Mace Windu and Anakin Skywalker
to transport a fearsome Zillo Beast
captured during the battle
back to Coruscant.
After seeing that not even a lightsaber
could harm the Beast,
Chancellor Palpatine hopes to unlock
the secret of its invulnerability
to create new armor
for the Republic's clone troopers.
Tensions run high as the most
dangerous life form in the galaxy
touches down
on the Republic's most populous planet.
Let's go! Move it! Move it!
Come on. Come on! I can see him.
Stand your ground.
Watch it! Watch it!
- You are clear. You are clear.
- Copy that.
No, no, don't stop.
- Yes, sir.
Your Excellency.
Such size, such power.
With respect, Chancellor,
I believe this creature could pose
any number of dangers.
Bringing it here to Coruscant is a mistake.
I assure you I did not make this decision
lightly, Master Jedi.
The sooner we unlock
the Zillo Beast's secrets,
the sooner we can end this terrible war.
I hope you're right, Chancellor.
I'm turning the Zillo Beast
over to you, Doctor.
I trust it will be given good care.
The Beast is a priceless resource,
Master Windu.
It will be well treated, I assure you.
Why would the Chancellor
want to bring the Beast here?
I know that he thinks by studying it,
the knowledge could prove beneficial,
but from what you and Anakin
reported on Malastare,
it hardly seems worth the effort.
I raised the issue with the Chancellor
during the Battle of Malastare,
without success.
Well then, in that case,
perhaps it's time we let someone else try.
That's enough.
Its scales are remarkably strong and light.
If we could examine their composition,
we might be able to synthesize them
to reinforce our clone armor.
- And what is stopping you?
- We need to remove the scales first.
It's very difficult, not to mention painful.
Chancellor, I must protest.
Besides being the last of its kind,
this creature may be intelligent.
I find that hard to believe.
It is, after all, just an animal.
It didn't seem to like your comment.
I applaud your high moral stance, Doctor.
After all,
principle is in short supply these days.
However, every passing minute of warfare
brings countless deaths,
deaths that could be prevented
once the Beast's secrets are unlocked.
If there is any way to hasten that process,
it is our moral duty to explore it.
I serve at your pleasure, Chancellor.
I'm just not sure where to begin.
The fact remains
that the Beast is indestructible.
Nothing is truly indestructible, Doctor.
Wasn't there something in Malastare fuel
that affected the Beast?
- It weakened the Zillo, yes, but...
- Excellent.
I suggest you start there.
Doctor, you need to find a way
to kill that Beast,
or we shall replace you
with someone who can.
Oh, hello!
You're not in trouble again, are you?
I am not being rude.
Not that it isn't a pleasure, Senator,
but I thought I was just meeting
Obi-Wan here.
Master Kenobi explained the problem.
I'm here to help.
Problem? What problem?
The situation with our friend
from Malastare.
Uh-huh. I see what's going on here.
You think I can help influence
the Chancellor.
The Zillo Beast was chained up
and brought here against its will.
It has no voice to defend itself.
Anakin, we have to be that voice.
You haven't seen it in action.
You have no idea what it's capable of.
It's what we're capable of
that frightens me.
A creature's life,
maybe even an entire species, is at stake.
Doesn't that at least warrant a discussion?
I didn't think you'd feel
so strongly about it.
All right, let's speak to the Chancellor.
But I still don't like this.
I should have known secrets
do not stay secret for long around here.
Isn't that precisely the point
of a democracy?
Of course, in wartime,
some things must be kept secret.
Even from the people,
so as not to aid the enemy.
It is unfortunate
that the Beast must die, Senator.
But the greater good demands it.
How is killing the last of a species,
in secret and without debate,
good for anyone?
Don't you have more pressing issues
that require your attention today?
No, Mr. Speaker, I do not.
I sympathize, my dear, truly I do.
But consider this.
A democracy is only as strong
as the people who comprise it.
At present,
the people I am charged with protecting
are dying faster than I can count.
It is my moral imperative to take action.
Anakin, is it not worth
the life of one savage beast
to give our brave troops
the advantage they need to win this war?
My role is not to set policy, Chancellor,
but I do see both points of view.
I'm certain a reasonable solution
will present itself.
Master Kenobi has taught you well.
Chancellor.
Excuse me.
You are supposed to be helping!
Whose side are you on, anyway?
Yours, but you must admit the Chancellor
makes some good points.
Ah, Doctor Boll,
I trust you have some progress to report.
Yes, Chancellor. I was able to convert
the Malastare fuel toxin into a poison gas.
I believe it's now strong enough
to kill the Zillo Beast,
if that's still how you wish to proceed.
I wish I saw an alternative.
However, sadly I must ask you
to proceed with your assignment.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry, it will all be over soon.
Begin procedure.
Vital signs are dropping.
No. It should have been enough.
I don't like the sound of that.
If that creature is as powerful as they say,
what good are these rifles gonna be?
Ah, shut up, Kosmos.
I'm on it, Leader.
Take it down! Take it down!
Man down!
You in the black, let's go!
Head up!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Hold. Everyone, back!
Oh, no.
Doctor, were you successful?
We have a problem, sir.
We need time to convert Malastare fuel
into more toxin, Chancellor.
I suggest you hurry, Doctor.
Evacuate the staff
to the underground shelters.
Stay with General Kenobi. I'm on my way.
Better hurry, sir.
You're missing all the fun.
I have no doubt the Jedi...
...to ensure the safety...
...that I will not stand...
It's coming this way!
Perhaps now would be a good time
to evacuate to the lower levels.
Yes. We are going now.
Desperately needed the tanks are.
We're almost at the loading dock,
Master Yoda.
Dire the situation has become.
Before more lives are lost,
act quickly we must.
My security staff insisted on adding
this emergency escape route.
Chancellor, I think we may have
enough toxin now.
My guards will be with you shortly.
Hand the gas over to them immediately.
Does it have to be destroyed?
- The Jedi stun cannons...
- Will not eliminate the problem.
Our advanced technology
simply cannot contain it.
I wish we had
never brought the Beast here.
Pardon me, Mistress Padmé,
but I believe something is following us.
Evasive action!
We're doomed!
All tanks acquire solution
and prepare to fire on my order.
Hold your fire.
In the Beast's clutches the Chancellor is.
Anakin might be with him,
and Senator Amidala.
If the Beast falls,
at risk their lives shall be.
I've got an idea, but it's risky.
Considering the circumstances,
I'll take the risk.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Sir, looks like
the General's up to something.
What is Skywalker doing?
It appears to be
one of Anakin's improvised plans.
How can it be a plan if it's improvised?
Not to worry.
Just catch them when they fall.
A lot of the General's plans involve falling.
Distract the Beast we shall,
to give Skywalker more time.
I hope you know what you're doing.
Here's where the fun begins. Hang on!
Catch it!
Ani!
All pilots, fire.
Sir, we have to get you out of here.
Artoo, get over there!
It can't carry both of us. You go, sir.
Oh, no!
- We aren't having much of an effect!
- Time to leave, it is.
Oh, no!
Let's go!
Use the gas bombs!
Copy that.
Bombs away!
It's a tragedy that the Zillo Beast
paid with its life for our mistakes.
I will make certain that sacrifice
was not made in vain.
Doctor, a word if you please.
Your new orders.
What is this?
You want me to clone the Beast?