A people enslaved!
To locate the abducted colonists
of a peace-loving world,
the Jedi infiltrated the slaver planet
of Zygerria,
only to be captured by its ambitious queen,
who plots to rebuild her empire
of oppression.
Now even Obi-Wan Kenobi
must come to terms with a life in chains.
Obi-Wan Kenobi, once a Jedi master,
now a Jedi slave.
Pitiful.
Keep eyes on your toil, skug!
Everything about this place
is designed to shatter the will.
It has already begun to affect
these poor people.
Speech is forbidden!
I'm sorry. It won't happen again.
There will be punishment!
No, stop, it's my mistake!
Leave him alone!
Now a slave gives me commands?
Beg!
Beg me before this one dies
because of you!
Please. Forgive me, Master.
Keep away from me.
Jedi only make things worse.
Long have Sith empires been built
upon the backs of slaves.
To carry on this tradition,
we will require millions.
I assure you, the Queen's defiance
will not sour your plans, Master.
If she fails to see the error of her ways,
end her rule.
Have you considered my offer, Skywalker?
If you vow loyalty to me,
I will free your friends.
It's not an easy decision.
Hmm, curious.
I thought the Jedi were selfless,
placing the needs of others
before their own.
My Queen, I bring word.
Count Dooku is on his way here.
Ah, sooner than anticipated.
Make preparations for his arrival.
So even you have a master.
Dooku is not my master!
Perhaps you should not attend
this meeting.
Can I trust you not to run away?
I don't run away from anything,
Your Highness.
Hmm...
Get off, you miserable tin can!
Get down there and find that Jedi.
Yes, sir.
Nice work, pal. You find Ahsoka?
I wasn't expecting you, Count.
Not without an invitation.
But I was invited,
by your faithful advisor.
He's concerned over
how attached you've become to Skywalker.
Skywalker is a symbol of my...
Our power to enslave even Jedi.
Your power over him is an illusion.
You forget, I was once a Jedi myself.
You have little in common with Anakin.
Please, hear my plans for the Jedi,
then decide.
Right now,
at my facility in the Kadavo system,
Obi-Wan Kenobi is in despair.
I'm listening.
Kenobi is coming to realize,
perhaps for the first time in his life,
that his efforts to help others
will only injure them.
As plans for escape
and hopes of rescue fade,
the gnawing fear
that he will never be able to take action
will grow in Kenobi's heart.
To ease the burden of his fellow slaves,
defiance will become compliance.
When Kenobi realizes
he cannot help those around him,
his spirit will break and he will be mine.
If such Jedi as Skywalker and Kenobi
can fall,
how many others will follow?
Hmm?
Imagine...
Imagine an army of Jedi in your service.
Zygerria will be invincible!
A most ambitious plan, Your Highness.
Only my goal is not the enslavement
of the Jedi Order,
but its extermination.
I have come to supervise their execution,
perform it if necessary.
Now,
summon Skywalker.
Well, hello, Master.
Took you long enough.
Well, I knew you had a nice view.
Are you okay?
I sense a disturbance in the Force.
It's Dooku. I need you to get our ship.
Here, take this comlink.
Where are you going?
The Queen knows where Obi-Wan is.
Hold on to that comlink
and wait for my signal.
Come on, Artoo.
I have no desire to end Skywalker's life.
He has become a valuable asset to me
and my throne.
Your compliance is not optional.
I command you to kill Skywalker.
I will not be ordered about
in my own palace, Count!
If you won't do my bidding,
perhaps your prime minister will.
Atai, what does he mean?
I'm sorry, Your Majesty,
but the Count is right.
The Jedi should die.
You're not fit to be queen any longer.
Atai, you traitor!
I'll make you both pay for this treachery.
Punishment for a slave
who disobeys her master.
That's enough, Dooku!
Skywalker.
I see the Queen has given you a long leash.
One more step and I will end her life.
Why would you think I care
about this slaver scum?
Indeed.
The Queen!
She was murdered by the Jedi.
That's our signal. Let's get going.
Take your vengeance!
Your Highness.
No escape
for any of us.
Where is Obi-Wan?
Tell me.
Kadavo system.
You were right, Skywalker.
I am a slave.
Just as you are.
Someone wishes to speak with you.
Obi-Wan Kenobi.
In chains once again, I see.
Count Dooku.
Still afraid to get your hands dirty?
I would gladly make an exception
in your case, my friend.
I wanted to say a proper farewell
before Keeper Agruss puts you to death.
Keeper, the slave ship Tecora
is making an unscheduled landing
on platform two-four.
Skywalker.
So much for our ride home.
What now?
We get through the old fashioned way.
Kenobi, tell your young friend, Skywalker,
if he does not surrender,
the slaves will be terminated in his name.
Anakin! I'm glad to see you,
but I'm afraid our host feels otherwise.
You can't make everyone happy, Master.
They're threatening to kill the slaves
unless you surrender.
It's good to see
you're always ready to negotiate.
But I've had enough bargaining
with slave drivers.
Anakin, you must realize
this is a fight you cannot win alone.
Who said I was alone?
Keeper, a fleet of warships has dropped out
of hyperspace in sector six.
Jedi reinforcements!
Wolf leader to wolf pack,
accelerate to attack speed.
This is Warthog, we're going in.
Rex! Now!
About time.
Those towers are ray shielded.
I hope you told Master Plo
not to destroy this facility
before we get off of it.
Yeah, all of us and the slaves.
We'll need a bigger ship.
I'm catching too much heat!
R-7, cut the engines!
Yeah! That got 'em. Good work, General!
Keep your focus, Warthog.
Watch out for those towers!
No!
The walls, they're electrified.
The controls are destroyed, Master Plo.
There's nothing we can do from here!
I cannot move the cruiser in
for the rescue operation
until those enemy canons are destroyed.
We'll take care of those canons.
Just make sure
that cruiser gets down here.
We're running out of time!
I'm going to go help my people,
I'll see if I can buy us some time!
Good luck!
Incoming!
A Jedi!
You're all clear, Master Plo.
Bring the cruiser down to the landing pad.
Cancel that order, Master!
There's no way
to get the people out of the holding cell
and up to the landing platform.
But I have an idea.
We need to have the cruiser move in
underneath the facility.
We can escape onto the ship
if Admiral Coburn can get in close enough.
You heard Commander Tano.
I want the men topside with rocket packs
and cable guns. Move it!
Yes, sir!
Come now, Master Kenobi, I know
a Jedi won't kill an unarmed man!
I'm no Jedi.
Okay, everyone, get ready.
We'll have to go by groups!
Gotcha.
That's everyone. We have to go.
The facility's breaking up!
Okay, Master Plo, the cruiser is clear!
All gunships, fire!
I thank you, the Jedi, and the Republic
for saving our lives.
Ahsoka is the real hero.
Without her creativity, I don't think
we would've gotten your people to safety.
Indeed. Padawan Tano,
might I have a word in private?
Of course.
Ahsoka, you have done a great deed
for your people today.
You're sad?
Well, you and the Jedi have done your best,
but I do not think our people will recover
from this horror anytime soon.
I understand, but in the end,
surviving this
will only strengthen the people.
Perhaps, and perhaps the people of Kiros
will also join the Republic.
I think that's a wise choice, Governor.