Reunited.
With the help of the Bad Batch,
Captain Rex rescues his
old friend, ARC Trooper Echo,
from the Techno Union.
The separatist loss of Echo's
strategic algorithm
provides a chance for
the Republic to turn the tide
in the battle for Anaxis.
However, Echo's horrifying
experience behind enemy lines
leaves lingering questions
of his true loyalty
and uncertain future.
We have more than a dozen
active battlefronts on Anaxis,
and we are losing nearly every one.
But, if Admiral Trench can no
longer anticipate our moves,
we now have the opportunity to
retake the planet.
I can improve your chances.
Uh, excuse me, Generals.
Echo, I'm sorry,
but I just don't think
you're ready for battle yet.
I am not a liability, Rex.
I'm the best chance we have to take
back Anaxis.
If the Trooper has a plan,
I'd like to hear it.
May I?
While Master Windu leads a team
to retake the Assembly Complex,
the Bad Batch will escort
me into Trench's new com-port,
which, according to code intel,
is now located on this separatist
dreadnought above Anaxis.
Once I'm plugged in,
I can feed Trench strategies,
but this time,
you'll know every move
before he makes it.
And you are certain
that if we get you on board that ship,
that you can convince Trench's army
to do what you want?
Absolutely.
Unfortunately,
I've been doing this for a while,
but this time,
I can help bring about a Republic victory
instead of a defeat.
Tech, is everything ready?
Yup, Sarge.
We are ready.
Still not sure how we're
gonna land on that ship.
Don't worry.
Echo says he's got a plan.
That makes me feel so much better.
What do you mean by that?
To be blunt, his mind belonged to the
separatists until we unplugged him.
We don't really know
where his loyalties lie.
Yeah, well I know.
Now get moving.
Please tell me we are
blowing something up!
Sorry, Wrecker.
This is strictly stealth.
I hate that word!
Echo, you're up.
Don't worry.
As soon as I plug in,
I'll send a signal to the command ship.
What type of signal are you gonna send?
Nothing that will give us away, right?
As far as the droids are concerned,
we're just gonna be another
one of their shuttles
coming in for a landing.
The regs think we take risks.
We have an incoming ship.
Is this one of ours?
I've never seen this model.
Sending the signal.
Now.
Yep, it's one of ours.
Roger, roger, shuttle TC-159.
You may approach and land.
I'd still rather blow it up.
I have a feeling you'll get your chance.
Gold Leader, you're cleared for launch.
Copy that, General. We're going in.
Admiral Trench,
the Jedi are attacking the assembly plant
with a large force.
Yes.
Now I will use their
arrogance and desperation
to our advantage.
Tech, can you rig an interface.
I assume that's a rhetorical question.
We should make sure this comvault
has no other entrances.
I'm on it.
Contact Skako.
I want to use the algorithm to calculate
the best possible counterattack.
As you command.
All right.
I have access to everything.
And good timing.
I just scanned a strategy request
Trench sent to the techno-union.
Wait!
You can't just send a signal from here.
Why not?
We have to make it appear as if
your signal is originating
from Skako Minor.
Otherwise they'll know we are here.
My name is General Mace Windu
of the Jedi Order.
At this point of the Clone War,
I have dismantled and destroyed
over 100,000 of you
Type-1 battle droids.
I'm giving you an opportunity to
peacefully lay down your weapons,
so that you may be reprogrammed
to serve a better
purpose than spreading
the mindless violence and chaos
which you have
inflicted upon the galaxy.
Blast him!
Well, I guess it was worth a try.
Here is the new strategy
from Skako, Admiral.
Mobilize all troops on Anaxis to the
Assembly Complex.
The Republic will not
send reinforcements.
They will put all their faith
in the Jedi.
Give the order.
I'm intercepting a transmission.
Trench is ordering all of his droids
to the Assembly Complex.
All right, Echo.
What are you trying to pull?
Don't worry.
That's what I told him to do.
But our troops will be
vastly outnumbered.
Not when I send them a feedback pulse
that shuts down all the droids.
How do we know that's what
you're really going to do?
We have to trust him.
Rex is right.
Echo, we're all counting on you.
Master Windu, I know
this sounds crazy, but
it's about to get a little more
crowded where you are.
We have our hands full as it is.
What is your plan?
If it makes you feel any
better, it isn't my plan.
Echo is drawing all the droids to your
position so he can neutralize
them all at the same time.
Obi-Wan, Skywalker just contacted me.
He said we've got a lot more droids
headed our way.
I see Anakin is being as
insightful as ever.
I was told not to worry.
It was all part of their plan?
If I know Anakin, we've got the easy part.
The droids are going to
overwhelm the Jedi.
They don't stand a chance.
Well, there weren't as many as I thought
there were going to be.
Does this meet your expectations?
This exceeds my expectations.
Hey there.
Shutting down.
Awaiting orders.
What?!
What was that?
We monitored a powerful energy surge,
which has overloaded the droid circuitry.
We are tracking the
origin of this pulse now.
I am pleased to report that we are
in control of the assembly complex,
and all other fronts are
falling to the Republic,
thanks to Echo's plan.
That's good news, Master Windu.
We're on our way back to the base.
May the Force be with you.
Good job, Echo.
Well, I guess you
actually are on our side.
Was there ever any doubt?
Some?
Well, thanks.
Come on, brother.
Unplug and let's get out of here.
The algorithm has never
been wrong before.
How could we have missed this?
The source originated on board this ship.
Dispatch security droids.
What about our apparent defeat?
A wise leader does not rely completely on
things such as algorithms.
My personal strategy for victory
is through total annihilation.
Wait.
I just scanned a new order from Trench.
He's initiated a countdown.
There's a bomb,
hidden at the assembly complex.
But it's big enough to
destroy most of Anaxes.
Can you stop it?
Well, I can try.
General, where are you going?
If you can't stop the detonation,
perhaps Trench can.
You're clear.
Continue your sweep, Jesse.
Sir.
General Windu, this is Tech.
We've discovered a bomb
in the fusion reactor.
We need someone to go down
there and help disarm it.
I'm on my way.
Get the men out of here.
You heard General Windu.
Organize your platoons and have
them evacuated as soon as possible.
Sir, yes, sir.
Ray shield.
Echo, I found the bomb.
Tell me the sequence to shut it down.
I'm decrypting it now.
You have to unplug.
They're going to detect us.
No, no, we need these codes.
The first number in
the sequence is three.
The next is one.
Eight.
We have located the source of the pulse.
Seven.
Jam the signal at its source.
They're on to us.
We need to unplug now.
Echo.
The server overloaded its neural system.
And it appears deliberate.
Echo!
That means Trench knows we're here.
Echo, are you there?
General Windu, Trench took out Echo.
We can't get to the last number in
the sequence.
Sorry, General.
You'll have to disarm
that bomb without us.
Don't worry about me, Captain.
Just get your men out of there.
Yes, sir.
We got company.
The Jedi lacks the final
sequences to stop
the detonation.
The loss of clones at the shipyard will
seal the Republic's fate.
Dispatch more units to deal
with the infiltrators on the ship.
And prepare our landing
craft for our next assault.
As you command.
Jedi scum.
Tell me the sequence
to disarm the bomb.
Never.
Dooku would kill me for losing Anaxes.
And you think I won't?
You're a Jedi.
Your nobility...
I don't have such weaknesses!
Now let's try that again.
Mace, if you can't stop the detonation,
you must leave now.
That is not an option.
I still have a chance to stop this,
even if it's down to my best guess.
How about I take the
guesswork out of it, Master?
Admiral Trent was kind
enough to give me
the final number himself.
Try seven.
Good work, Skywalker.
The bomb has been disarmed.
You both owe me one now.
Wrecker is gonna love this.
Admiral, it was a pleasure.
Hey! Fire!
Can't blast our way out.
There's too many of them.
What's he doing?
Time to release the wrecking ball!
Yeah!
Hey!
I honestly feel bad for those droids.
It's all clear.
Please, not the face.
Not the face.
More droids.
Go.
I'll buy you some time.
Stickey.
We'll meet you at the infiltration point.
Oh.
He's gonna try and top me.
You watch.
This is the infiltration point.
I'm picking up dozens of
droids on my sensors,
all heading this way.
Hope you're not waiting on me.
Now all we're missing is Crosshair.
You miss me?
How touching.
Relax, Wrecker.
You'll top him next time.
No, he won't.
I've got a present for you, Wrecker.
Oh, seriously?
I get to blow it up?
The whole stinkin' thing?
This is the happiest day of my life.
Captain Rex, Corporal Echo
and Clone Force 99.
You have all done a great
service for the Republic.
Thanks to your courage and effort,
Republic shipyards will soon
be up and running again.
You've got some medals
coming your way.
Thank you, General.
You coming?
Not really our thing.
Accolades.
Yeah, we're just in it for the thrill.
Go!
You sure it's your thing?
What do you mean?
Your path is different.
Like ours.
If you ever feel like you
don't fit in with them,
well, find us.
Those are some of
the finest troopers I've
ever fought alongside.
Echo,
you and I go way back.
If that's where you feel your place is,
then that's where you belong.