Turning the tide!
As Separatist control over vital
but isolated supply routes expands,
Republic forces invade a key planet,
the darkened world of Umbara.
In the midst of helping
Obi-Wan Kenobi's battalion
conquer the Umbaran capital,
Anakin Skywalker
is called away to Coruscant.
His battalion is temporarily placed
under the command
of Jedi General Pong Krell,
a shrewd and temperamental leader.
Krell's reckless strategy
forced Captain Rex to retreat
with his platoons in a disastrous defeat.
We have got to move
before those fighters come back.
Rex! Rex, over here!
Jesse, take the right flank.
Dogma, take the left flank.
It'll be okay,
buddy. This will ease the pain.
The capital city's too fortified.
We need your battalion to help us take it.
Resistance from the Umbarans
has been greater than anticipated.
We're holding our ground at the moment.
We've gathered intel
on an airbase to the west.
It is re-supplying the capital's defenses.
Incoming! Incoming!
Get down, get down!
If you could capture that airbase,
it will sever the capital's supply lines
allowing the rest of our forces to move in.
I'll see to it that the airbase
is placed under our control.
Remember, General Krell,
the entire invasion
depends on your battalion.
Captain Rex,
have those coordinates mapped
and all troops ready
to move out immediately!
Yes, General!
There's a base there, all right,
and it's heavily guarded.
At least three tank divisions, plus guns.
We'll advance along the central gorge
and engage their forces
in a full-forward assault.
The gorge is narrow, sir.
We'll only be able to move our platoons
in single squads.
Perhaps a closer recon will tell us
if there's a more secure route.
Obi-Wan and the other battalions
are holding off the enemy right now
while they wait for us
to take out this base.
We don't have time
to look for a more secure route.
Yes, sir.
All right, listen up.
We'll assemble the squads
into two divisions.
We'll move straight up this gorge
towards the airbase at the far side.
The casualties are going to be high.
Is Krell trying to get us killed?
You know, I wasn't sure
that Krell was crazy before,
but now I'm positive.
We had to retreat from the capital
because the General pushed
a flawed strategy. Now this?
I don't know! Could be fun.
Well, I, for one,
agree with the General's plan.
We're running out of time
and this is the best option.
No recon? No air support?
We don't know what we're up against.
They have weapons
we've never seen before.
A few of General Skywalker's plans
seemed reckless, too,
but they worked.
Yeah, but General Skywalker is usually
leading his men up in the front
not bringing up the
rear like General Krell.
A full-forward assault
would leave us too exposed.
We have to look at other options.
- It's going to be a meat grinder.
- Fives.
It would help if you eased their minds.
What, you mean coax them into following
another one of Krell's suicide missions?
We lost a lot of men last time.
Krell may do things differently,
but he is effective in getting them done.
He's a recognized war hero.
He may have had some victories,
but have you seen his casualty numbers?
More troopers have been killed
under his command than anyone else!
That's the price of war, Fives.
We're soldiers.
We have a duty to follow orders and,
if we must, lay down our lives for victory.
You believe that,
or is that what you were
engineered to think?
I honor my code. That's what I believe.
- Is everyone clear on the plan? Hardcase?
- Yes, sir.
- Fives, are you clear?
- Yeah.
All right, get in your groups.
Let's move out.
Everybody stay alert.
Fingers on the trigger.
They look spooked.
What the...
Oh, skrag!
Blast it!
Look out!
Its head is ray-shielded!
We need rocket launchers!
Mayday, mayday!
Rex, we need rocket launchers now!
Get those rocket launchers down there!
Move it, troopers!
- Take it, take it.
- Thanks, buddy.
I got him, I got him.
Go! Go, go, go!
Keep moving, keep moving!
- That was close.
- You got a point there.
Move it, trooper.
Everyone regroup, now! Take cover!
Move it! Move it!
We're safe for the moment,
but they'll be coming around any second.
Bring up the launchers,
spread detonators along that corridor.
Trap them into the bottleneck.
We're going to blow those things sky high.
Hurry up, we only have a few seconds.
Here they come!
Hey, come on! Over here!
- Let's see how tough you are!
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
Right over here!
Over here!
We got her! We got them!
Good job! All right, let's move out.
That one's still got some juice in it,
waste it!
Sure.
No juice left in him either.
Hey! Still hungry?
Chew on that!
Everyone, keep moving.
Hey, Kix, leave it.
We've got a problem.
Fall back! Fall back now!
What are they doing?
Captain, continue your attack!
Sir, we're overpowered.
We need reinforcements!
The rest of the battalion is holding
the entrance to the gorge, Captain.
They're guarding it so your troops
can break through to the airbase.
- Sir, we can't possibly...
- You must stand your ground!
Do you read me?
Captain, are you listening?
Do not fall back! That is an order!
The platoons are in the formation
you requested, General.
Should I send them
to support Captain Rex?
I'll give the order when I give it,
Sergeant Appo.
Keep the wounded as quiet as possible.
All right, you heard the General. Let's go.
You can't be serious.
I used to think General Krell was reckless,
but now I'm beginning to think
he just hates clones.
The Captain is right. Now let's move out.
We can't take them head-on.
We need to find another way.
You got any ideas?
Then this is it.
Okay. Let's do it!
The rocket launchers
don't work on these things!
Help me with the wounded!
We got to get these guys out of here.
Forget it, we have to leave them!
We can't just leave them, sir!
You don't have a choice. That's an order!
You sound like General Krell.
Look, Kix, it's more important
to save yourself right now.
If we survive,
you can patch up the wounded later.
We're finished.
We've still got some fight left in us, Tup,
and I've got an idea.
What were you thinking?
Remember what you were saying
about finding another way
to destroy those tanks?
- Yeah.
- Well, I have a mission for you.
CT-7567, where are you?
General Krell, we've come up with a plan
to infiltrate the airbase.
What is your plan?
I've dispatched two men
on a stealth incursion into the airbase.
They've been ordered to co-opt starfighters
and use them against the tanks.
You what?
You've put this entire assault on your hope
that two clones can do
what your entire group could not?
Sir, the rocket launchers
don't work on these tanks
and it'll be easier to slip by undetected
while the rest of us
keep the tanks occupied.
Captain, you will launch
a full-forward strike immediately
or you will be relieved of duty.
We need to hold out as long as we can.
I'm trusting Fives and Hardcase
to pull this thing off.
The second they spot us, I start blasting.
Hardcase, can't you take it easy for once?
Stick to the plan, instead of guns blazing.
I'm sorry, it's just how I am.
My commander on Kamino said my
growth acceleration chamber had a leak.
Made me hyper-active, I guess.
Shh! There's the airbase.
Hmm...
Some kind of sensor wall.
Use the tree to get over the sensor wall.
Uh, how am I supposed to do this, exactly?
Figure it out.
"Figure it out, Hardcase. Figure it out."
What's to figure out
about climbing up a tree?
How about you try it next time?
Great, nice view.
I prefer a good fight
to all this sneaking around.
Wow, I never actually thought
that would work.
So, how do I start this thing?
Well, how should I know?
Start pushing buttons!
Glad these things are ray-shielded.
I don't think I can do this!
Watch out!
Let's hope this trip was worth it.
All right, let's go!
Hey, Kix, put it down, you're wasting aim.
- Clear out, Captain!
- The big guns have arrived, sir!
Take that!
That's the stuff!
Whoo-hoo!
Way to go, boys!
Attaboy, Hardcase!
All right, let's bring them home.
Impressive.
Sergeant, their defenses are down.
Send in the rest of our forces.
Attack the airbase!
All units, move out.
Despite Hardcase's flying,
you two saved us all.
That wasn't so tough.
You sure? You looked a little green
when you came out of that fighter.
Captain. Report. What is our situation?
General, we have taken the base and
cut off enemy supply lines to the capital.
Luck has smiled on you today, Captain.
Consider yourself fortunate.
It wasn't all luck, sir.
A lot of men died to take this base.
The price for such victory.
Perhaps someday you'll realize this.
Dismissed.
He's the one who will never realize.