Pantora in peril!
The newly elected Chairman of Pantora,
Baron Papanoida,
is caught in a deadly political game.
The Trade Federation
has blockaded Pantora
and suspended all commerce
with the system.
Isolated from the rest of the Republic,
the people of Pantora are beginning
to rally against the Senate,
who have seemed unsympathetic
to their plight.
To make matters worse, Count Dooku
has come forward, offering aid
if Pantora joins the Separatist alliance.
Chairman Papanoida has dispatched
Senator Chuchi to Coruscant
with the hope that she can motivate
the Senate to act in favor of Pantora
before Lott Dod can legitimize
the blockade.
The Trade Federation is neutral in this,
but Pantora must pay its debt
before we can resume commerce
with the system.
That is a lie.
It is well known that the Trade Federation
is aligned with the Separatists.
Slanderous!
We are not Separatists simply
because we do business with them.
How many times must I remind you
of the Commerce Treaty of 1647?
The Trade Federation is neutral.
I beg the Senate to listen to our pleas.
Ignore the Trade Federation's
feeble attempt
to paint this as a domestic financial issue
and allow us to resume trade.
Wait! Senator Chuchi.
I wanted to compliment you
on your speech.
- Thank you, Padmé.
- You are very brave.
The Trade Federation doesn't frighten me.
I just wanted to let you know
that there are many of us in the Senate
that support you and Pantora
in these difficult times.
I know the Separatists have
approached you to offer their help.
Please do not take it.
The Senate will force the Trade Federation
to resume trade.
Don't worry, Senator.
There's no way that Pantora will ever
have dealings with the Separatists.
We'll always be loyal to the Republic.
The Chairman of Pantora has just arrived.
I must go brief him.
Please, send him my best wishes.
- Chairman Papanoida.
- Senator Chuchi.
You spoke well
on behalf of our people today.
I only hope the Senate is truly listening.
As do I, Chairman.
Allow me to introduce my family.
These are my daughters, Chi Eekway
and Che Amanwe, and my son, Ion.
Father, Amanwe and I are going home.
Don't be too late.
I won't be long. Ion and I have some issues
to discuss with the Senator first.
Things are deteriorating rapidly, Senator.
Ion has just brought word from Pantora
that things are far worse
than we've been led to believe.
The people are restless.
The Trade Federation blockade is causing
far more damage and disorder
- than we predicted.
- We need more time.
The Senate will vote in our favor,
I'm sure of it.
Count Dooku and the Separatists
are promising immediate aid
and a resolution to the blockade.
You're not suggesting we join them,
are you?
Certainly not.
I merely point out that the wheels
of democracy are moving too slowly.
There are Pantorans rallying
for us to leave the Republic
and join the Separatists.
We cannot give up
on the Republic Senate!
Chairman, you must convince the people
to remain loyal to our cause.
I will do what I can, Senator.
What's wrong with the lights?
Did you see that?
It's nothing,
just the shadows playing tricks.
Don't tell me you are afraid of the dark?
Chi?
Chi? Stop fooling around.
My father's a powerful man. If you
hurt me or my sister, you'll be dead!
Big talk. You're coming with us!
Hurry! Let's go!
I don't like the situation on Pantora
one bit.
It reminds me far too much
of Naboo's own scarred history.
Well, that blockade wasn't that bad.
It's the reason I met you, after all.
You certainly have a unique way
of looking at things, Ani.
Senator Amidala! Master Skywalker!
What is it, Ahsoka?
Someone has kidnapped
Chairman Papanoida's daughters.
I was afraid something like this
would happen. Anakin?
The Jedi can't get involved.
This is a job for the local police.
I'm not so sure
local authorities can handle it.
The Separatists are putting a lot
of pressure on Pantora to join them.
I'm afraid this blockade may give
the Pantorans no other choice.
Master, if the Jedi can't officially
get involved, let me do this on my own.
Senator Chuchi is a good friend of mine.
All right. With the Separatists involved,
I guess it gives you cause to investigate.
Go help Senator Chuchi, but don't get
in the way of the local authorities.
Aren't you going to help?
I said the situation gives "you"
cause to investigate, not "us."
I need to go back to the Jedi Temple
and make sure the Council doesn't find out
about your little expedition.
Should you really proceed
without the Council's approval?
- We do it all the time, don't we, Snips?
- Yep.
Well, be careful, Ahsoka.
I still can't believe they let you teach.
Give your father my condolences.
If you want your sisters back,
we're here to help.
Father, Count Dooku has offered to help us
find Chi Eekway and Che Amanwe.
Chuchi, Senator Amidala sent me to help,
if I can.
Chairman Papanoida.
This is my good friend Ahsoka.
Good. A Jedi can always be of help.
Senator Amidala thinks this may have
something to do with the Separatists.
They've already made contact with us.
I don't think this is a kidnapping.
I think they're holding them hostage.
A not very subtle attempt
to get us to join the Separatists?
If the Separatists are involved,
your daughters may be held
on the Trade Federation ship
blockading your planet.
That is a possibility.
Why don't you and Chuchi
pay them a diplomatic visit
and see what you can find out?
We'll stay here
and follow the police investigation.
Did you find anything?
We've completed a thorough sweep
of your apartment, Chairman.
No evidence of foul play.
My daughters' lives are in your hands,
Inspector.
You have nothing to worry about,
Your Honor.
We are in complete control
of the situation.
That inspector is useless!
They must have left clues somewhere.
Look here. The icon of the moon goddess.
It should be up on the shrine
with the others.
Wait a minute! What's this?
Blood?
It must be what they used
to fight off their attackers.
But the kidnappers didn't know
to put it back in the right place.
Information Retrieval,
I need you to match this blood sample
against known galactic criminals.
A Rodian.
Says here his name's Greedo.
Looks like he's based on Tatooine.
Then what are we waiting for?
Senator Chuchi.
To what do we owe this pleasure?
I bring word from the Chairman of Pantora.
The Chairman has finally decided
to agree to our terms?
Not exactly.
The Chairman wanted to inform you
of an impending alliance
between Pantora and
the Confederacy of Independent Systems.
The Chairman is planning
to join the Separatist alliance?
If that were the case, would you remove
your blockade of Pantora?
If that were the case,
the Chairman would have to go
to the Senate and renounce the Republic.
Then we could discuss
how quickly we can resume commerce.
Very well. I shall contact the Chairman.
We can discuss the finer details
of the terms later this evening.
Agreed.
Now you and your servant
may stay as our honored guests.
Come this way to your rooms.
Be careful, Ion.
The Hutts are the only law
that matters on Tatooine.
I don't scare easily.
- Where do we start?
- We'll have to get a feel for the crowd.
Shouldn't we talk to Jabba directly?
No. Remember, we're not sure
who's behind this kidnapping yet.
- Jabba could be involved.
- What if Greedo runs?
We'll let Greedo know we're here.
That way, he'll come to us.
- How are we going to do that?
- Follow me.
Ladies! Do any of you know Greedo?
Who's asking?
We're asking.
We're looking to hire a bounty hunter.
He's not here.
But if he comes back,
I'll tell him you were asking for him.
Patience.
If she won't lead us to Greedo,
she'll lead Greedo to us.
This is the ambassador's office.
Maybe we'll find something here.
The Separatists are still recovering
from their defeat
- on Orto Plutonia.
- They're coming! Hide!
We need to know who our supporters are.
I understand your profit margins
with the Separatists can be considerable.
However, I object to the kidnapping.
The Chairman's children are leverage.
Besides, they're well taken care of.
Yes, but why on my ship?
What was that?
Are you certain we're alone?
I'm sure I heard something.
All of this scheming with the Separatists
is making you paranoid.
Do not worry,
the daughters are not to be harmed,
at least for now.
You see? The Trade Federation
is behind the kidnapping.
Let's find the detention area. Come on.
Ha!
Poodoo!
Greedo, baby, there you are.
There's some men here looking for you.
Pantorans.
They must have found some evidence.
We'll have to settle things
more permanently.
- Have you done this before?
- No. But I've been practicing.
The detention block is closed to visitors.
Move along.
You will let me pass.
I will let you pass.
I'm sorry, the detention block
is closed to visitors.
Ahsoka?
You will let us both pass.
I... I will let you both pass.
Looking for someone, Chairman?
I was looking for you, Greedo.
Tell me where my daughters are, or die.
You were a fool to come here.
Let's dispose of them outside.
- I don't want to die on this dust ball.
- We won't have to.
We're going to talk to Jabba about this.
This is the fifth area we've checked,
and there's no sign
of the Chairman's daughters.
Can't you sense where they are?
Isn't that something you Jedi can do?
It's not something
I can just turn on or off.
We'll just have to keep looking.
Sir, we have intruders
in the detention area.
It looks like our guests got
a little too curious for their own good.
Chairman Papanoida,
the mighty Jabba wishes to know
why you tried to kill
one of his bounty hunters.
Great Jabba,
my daughters have been kidnapped.
As a father yourself,
I know you understand
that I will do anything
to get them back safely.
I have evidence that Greedo is responsible,
which means that either you are behind it
or Greedo is working for someone else.
Since we are friends, Jabba,
I know you would never do such a thing.
No! No! He's lying!
We found blood at the scene of the crime.
If it matches Greedo's,
it will prove he is the kidnapper.
Jabba will allow a blood sample
to be taken.
Wait. Wait, no! It's all lies!
Okay, okay! I kidnapped them!
The Separatists wanted leverage
against you.
Where are they, you slime?
One of them is here, at Mos Eisley.
She's safe, I assure you.
Take us there!
Let's hope she's in this one.
Senator Chuchi? How did you find me?
It's a long story. Where's your sister?
I don't know. We were separated.
All right, sleemo, no tricks!
We're gonna go inside and find my sister.
Nice and easy.
You think they will just
hand her over to you?
No,
but I'll bet they'll hand her over to you.
Go get the prisoner.
Greedo, what are you doing here?
There's been a change of plans.
We're going to have to move the prisoner.
On whose orders?
Gunray.
He contacted me at Jabba's palace.
Why'd he contact you?
And who are those two?
They're emissaries
of the Trade Federation.
Trade Federation? They don't look
like Trade Federation to me.
- Father!
- Father?
They're Pantorans! Blast them!
Stop them!
Surrender, Separatist!
What is the meaning of this?
You've been holding the Chairman
of Pantora's daughter as a hostage!
What?
Sib Canay, what is she talking about?
I want my litigator.
We are businessmen!
We deal in trade and commerce!
Yes, but perhaps your business
is war profiteering.
- How dare you!
- I dare
because you claim
to have no involvement,
and yet here stands the Chairman's
daughter on your ship,
held by your administrator.
I may understand your position,
but I doubt the rest of the Senate will.
- Blackmail!
- No,
business.
I could, of course, be persuaded
to defend your unfortunate circumstances
to the Senate.
That is, if this blockade ended.
I'll see what I can do.
It has come to our attention
that the ugly head of the Separatist
has once again raised itself in the ranks
of our very own Trade Federation.
Nute Gunray's influence extends farther
than we ever imagined.
It was Sib Canay,
acting on his own accord,
who kidnapped the children
of Chairman Papanoida.
In good faith,
we have returned them to him.
And also, as a gesture of friendship,
we are removing our blockade
and reopening trade with the Pantorans.