Conspiracy!
After repeated setbacks
on the planet Anaxes,
an elite clone squad
is deployed to investigate
the Separatists' tactical advantage.
This special unit, called the Bad Batch,
infiltrates Admiral Trench's Cyber Center
to steal a strategic algorithm
capable of predicting
the Republic's every move.
What our heroes found
was a live signal
from the ARC trooper known as Echo,
a clone long believed to be dead.
Word is the general staff
isn't completely behind this mission.
I admit the idea that Echo
is still alive is a long shot.
I'm sure the Council
will approve the mission.
Just remember the primary goal
is to learn how the Separatists
are predicting our strategy,
whether it's Echo behind it or not.
Well, if you want my opinion,
sounds like a trap,
but me and the boys
will tag along anyway,
if only to say "I told you so."
Just make sure you're ready
if we get the go-ahead
from General Kenobi.
If you're certain
he'll approve the mission, why wait?
Let's get going.
First, we have
that thing to do.
Uh, what thing?
You know.
We don't have time for that, sir.
Yes, we do.
Well, I'll just let you two sort this out.
I'll be waiting on the ship
with the rest of the team.
Come on, Rex. I'm late as it is.
You're late again.
Padmé, I'm so sorry.
We didn't anticipate the Outer Rim
Sieges would last this long.
That would be why
they call it a siege, Anakin.
I know, I just thought that I...
You thought you could bring a swift end
to the conflict single-handedly.
Yeah.
Anakin, what you're doing is important.
The Republic needs
you on the front lines
just as they need my
voice in the Senate.
I know.
Oh, great.
What is it?
Obi-Wan is coming.
No, that's not it.
There's something else.
It's Rex.
I'm worried he's letting
his personal feelings
drive him too much on this mission.
I wonder where he learned that.
Rex, where's Anakin?
I need to speak to him
about this mission.
Well, General, he's, um...
Well, he's inside your barracks, isn't he?
Yes, sir.
What's going on here?
Nothing, sir.
I was just waiting for the General...
uh, General.
You'll have to do
better than that, Captain.
You've known Rex a long time.
When you throw caution to the wind
and take chances, where is he?
Right beside me.
Then maybe that's where you should be
for him, Ani.
Trust his instincts like he trusts yours.
I'm just trying to look out for him.
I know you are.
I love you, Ani.
I love you too.
Then what is Anakin doing in there?
Ah, he's spot-checking my gear, sir.
Really? Without you?
Well...
Here you go, Rex.
- And try not to break it again.
- Anakin.
About this mission, the Council thinks...
That it's a good idea? I agree.
Let's get moving, Rex.
No, wait. That's not...
No time.
I hope you at least told Padmé
I said hello.
So, how many missions
has your team been on, Sergeant?
Honestly, sir, I've lost count.
All the action sort of blurs together.
I know you work with Cody sometimes,
but who do you guys report to?
Hmm... good question.
Can't say I've got an answer.
Yeah!
We are approaching Skako Minor.
It looks to be a difficult landing.
Rex, what do we know about this place?
On this part of Skako,
there's a race of locals, the Poletecs.
All we know is they're very primitive.
"Primitive" is being kind.
My intel says
the Poletecs worship flying reptiles.
Oh! What the heck was that?
It's one of those reptiles.
I want that thing off my ship.
Hold on! Hold on!
Don't just run out there.
Hey! Get off of there!
Hey, calm down. We
need to talk to them.
Why?
The General's right.
Watch out, Rex!
I have a thermal reading.
Point-two-five east, elevation 175.
Relax. I'll handle this.
What are you doing?
Going for a ride.
Tech, I'm with the General.
Hone in on my signal.
Okay, I think we're gonna have
a slight communication problem here.
That creature still has
a hold of the General.
We're going in,
but remember what the General said.
"No casualties, disarm only."
We're on it, Captain.
Wrecker, Crosshair, rockslide!
Tech, translate what he said.
He says
he does not want our war on his planet.
That is why he took our leader.
We didn't bring the war here.
It was Wat Tambor and the Separatists.
Separatists.
Tell him we apologize
for what's happened.
But tell him the enemy is holding
one of our men prisoner in Purkoll.
As soon as we rescue him,
we'll leave his planet, for good.
The chief says
he will provide us with scouts
and lead us to Tambor's city.
From there, we're on our own.
Any help is better than no help.
We are receiving a transmission
from Admiral Trench on Anaxes.
Put him through.
Pardon the intrusion, Minister Tambor...
but I have disturbing news.
You may proceed, Admiral.
An infiltration team of clones
has traced the algorithm signal to Skako.
I believe your operation there
is in jeopardy.
The Republic would not dare attack us.
The Techno Union has
corporate neutrality.
From what I have seen,
that would not matter
to these Republic operatives.
Then we shall be ready for them.
Hope nobody's scared of heights.
Well, I'm not scared of nothing.
I just... When I'm up real high,
I got a problem with gravity.
Speaking of problems,
I am no longer picking up Echo's signal.
I... I don't understand.
You said it was coming from this city.
I can only speculate,
but it is possible there's a latency issue
with the frequency
caused by all these
atmospheric disturbances.
Or... maybe they sent the signal
to lure us into a trap.
And maybe your friend's actually dead.
Well, I can't be the only one
thinking of that.
Look, every mission could be a trap.
This one is no different.
I'm telling you that signal is being sent
by Echo himself! He's alive!
I think you're letting
your personal feelings get in the way
because you left him for dead
at the Citadel.
I had no choice. You hear me?
Oh, I don't blame you.
I would've left him for dead too.
Besides, he's just another reg.
Hey!
Why don't you pick on someone
not your size?
You'll be a whole lot smaller
when I'm through with you.
That's enough!
Sergeant, take your men
and scout the area for a tower entrance.
I want to talk to my Captain alone.
Rex, I hate to say it, but...
you have to prepare yourself
for the possibility that Echo is dead,
and this is all a Separatist trick.
Sir, I have watched so many of
my brothers fall during this war,
and I try not to hang on
to any one of them.
But that changed when I
heard that Separatist transmission.
It was no algorithm.
That was Echo's voice. I know it.
I hope you're right.
But if, for some reason, you're wrong...
Then I'll deal with it.
We're in business, General.
Tech regained Echo's signal.
It's coming from this tower.
How's it going, Tech?
Sorry it took so long.
Hey, Crosshair, check it out.
Yeah, it's a lift.
Well, we already knew that.
Wait, wait, wait. A lift?
How far up are we going?
Don't worry, Wrecker. I'll hold your hand.
Hey! Cut it out, Sarge.
Just give me some droids to crush.
Remember, this is a stealth mission.
No blasting, no blowing things up.
Nobody knows we're here.
Intruders! Attack!
Why?
So much for stealth.
Yeah! Hah! Ha-ha!
Yeah!
Uh... sorry. I just got excited.
I've still got a lock on Echo's signal.
All right, men. Let's hunt some droids.
Now you're talking! Yeah!
Where exactly
is Echo's signal coming from?
Strange. I just lost the signal.
What? How can that be?
There's no "atmospheric disturbances"
up here.
Well, I have a new theory.
I'm surprised
I did not consider it earlier.
The signal is only traceable
during data transmissions.
So until Echo
dispenses more intel,
I cannot pick up the signal.
Okay, we're splitting up.
Search every door.
If someone finds Echo,
contact the others.
We go in together,
just in case there's trouble.
Drop your weapon!
You are surrounded!
Ah! It appears the signal is back.
It's from up ahead.
In there.
Tech, open this door.
You clones are so predictable.
Wat Tambor.
Your algorithm predicted
nearly every move
you made to infiltrate Purkoll.
There is no algorithm.
We know you're holding
a prisoner of war here.
Prisoner?
I don't know what
you mean, Captain.
I am leaving here with my friend.
Your friend is dead.
His mind is ours.
Liar!
Execute them.
Tech, open that door for Rex!
Yes, sir!
I hope you find
what you're looking for, Captain.
I don't like the look of this.
I'm definitely picking up a life-form
in there.
It seems to be a stasis chamber.
I think I can get it open.
Echo. Tech.
We got to get him out of here.
Figure out how to
unplug him from...
From this mess.
What have they done to you?
We... We have to get to the shuttle
to escape the Citadel.
- No! I'll go first.
- Echo.
- No! No. No.
- Echo, it's Rex. I'm here.
No.
Rex? You, you came back for me.
Yes. Yes, I did.
What?
What happened?
Where am I?
It's okay, Echo.
You're safe now.
Just sit tight, trooper.
You're going home.