A darkness awakes!
Count Dooku's bitter betrayal of
his former apprentice, Asajj Ventress,
resulted in the creation of a new menace
in the galaxy, Savage Opress.
Caught in a deadly game of revenge
between Ventress and Dooku,
Savage barely escaped the carnage.
Beaten and alone he returned
to Mother Talzin,
his creator, who gave him a new quest
to pursue his long-lost brother.
I can sense him, Grievous.
That creature, Savage Opress,
is growing stronger and stronger
as each day passes.
You consider him a threat?
He is a threat to all of us!
Even the Jedi!
With the Nightsisters eradicated,
there is no one left to control him.
Something is rising, something sinister.
He's choking her.
- Hey!
- Let her go!
He's choking her.
Hurry up! Call the authorities!
Mother Talzin, this dust,
it's a clue.
Yes, Savage, you are getting
closer and closer.
Soon you and your brother will be reunited.
I must make the necessary preparations.
So he hands me a blaster
about a fourth the size...
Cheers.
- Why so tense?
- I'm not sure.
I thought I sensed someone from my past.
Who is this someone?
A monster.
Huh. Hey! What are you doing here?
Get outta here! I'm about to take off!
The cargo you just dropped off,
what planet did it come from?
The junk fields on planet Lotho Minor!
- Take me there.
- Okay! Okay!
Uh, shouldn't we be getting
back to the cruiser?
Nah, I'm hungry and tired of
those government rations.
Hey, looks like trouble. Come on.
Hey, what are you doing?
We don't want any trouble.
We were only trying to help.
Lou! Are you crazy?
Pointing that thing at a Jedi?
Put it down now!
I'm sorry, sir. I'm just all shook up.
I understand. You want to tell me
what happened here?
We have it under control, sir.
It looks like only a simple altercation.
Happens here all the time.
He's telling the truth.
We get some rough characters in here.
Things like this happen too often to count.
Why don't you and your friend
take a load off?
I'll get you some food.
Meal's on the house.
You're not gonna kill me, are you?
Master?
Anakin?
I sense a disturbance. Something sinister.
All the way out here?
Yes.
Do you know what, or who, it is?
No,
but whatever it is, it feels familiar.
Just my luck, I got to go back
to that scrap pile floating in space.
Just get moving.
Fine, I guess things could be worse.
Though I'm not sure how.
He is close.
- Get out. Now!
- No. Come on!
I'm here at last, brother.
No, no, not when I'm so close!
Hey! Big guy!
I don't have time for you!
Over here!
You trackin' somebody?
What do you know about it?
I'm... I'm Morley.
I could help you!
We've got everything here!
I can get you what you want,
for the right amount, of course.
I mean, it'd be my payment-free
pleasure, of course!
I think I can manage on my own.
Show me something,
show me which way to go!
What you need is a guide!
Leave me alone!
Wait!
Trust me! Not everything
on this planet is junk.
It's not?
There are things like me.
Things that live and breathe.
Perhaps you're looking for something
more like that.
Show me.
You're already heading
in the right direction,
even though your
Handy doo-da there isn't working.
But you'll need my guidance to
avoid the fire-breathers.
Fire-breathers?
Yep. Fire-breathers.
They'll getcha! Follow me!
Ah!
The Junkers. Junkers strange folk.
Yeah, looks like it.
We better get outta here.
They can get a little cranky.
Big guy, we really should go.
A fight?
Wow!
Let's go.
So, who are you looking for?
Come on.
My brother. I've been searching for him.
Uh... Does he look like you?
Have you seen him?
No. No. I just heard stories
about a horned man.
I thought it was just an old local legend.
How old?
Old.
They say he drags things down beneath
and they never come back up.
Oh, but it's only a legend, like I said.
Acid rain.
It'll melt us down
if we don't find shelter soon.
Over there.
Oh, oh, oh...
What the...
This is it.
It doesn't look like anyone's here,
big guy.
I can see that!
Mother Talzin! She betrayed me!
My brother must be dead!
She's not the only one who betrayed you!
You'll make a good offering
and when my master's finished with you,
I get the leftovers!
Brother? Is that you, brother?
Is that you, brother?
You!
Stop there! What have you done
with my brother?
Answer me, you monster!
What? It can't be.
- Brother!
- No!
Wait, brother!
No! No!
No! No! No!
You are the brother
I've been searching for.
No! No! No! No! No!
Yes! We are, we are brothers.
No!
You... You don't know!
You don't know anything!
Never, never!
I know I am your blood!
Never!
Never, never!
I'm ready for my leftovers.
Oh! You're still alive, huh?
- Who did this to my brother?
- No.
Are you part of this?
No.
No. No. I found him this way.
It wasn't me. I found him this way.
You can't be trusted.
You're a slithering liar!
You should have been helping him!
I didn't know! I didn't know!
This is where you live?
How long have you been here?
Years and years and years.
Through victory, my chains are broken.
The chains, the chains are the easy part.
It's what goes on in here that's hard.
You have been lost, my brother.
Do you remember who you are?
Where you came from?
Always remember I am fear,
always remember I am hunter,
always remember I am filth,
always remember I am nothing.
Your legs...
That scum, he took them from me.
He took them!
Who? Who took them?
Jedi. Jedi.
- You remember?
- I don't ask for mercy, Master.
Mercy is a lie, a delusion of the weak
to think themselves strong.
- I ask not for mercy...
- What? What is it?
- But the chance...
- Brother, what are you saying?
And through the filth,
through the grief, Jedi!
Revenge.
I must have revenge.
Master Yoda?
Feel the disturbance in the Force, do you?
Yes, Master.
Fear you are in danger, I do.
From the dead, an old enemy
has awakened seeking vengeance.
An old enemy?
Killed your master many moons ago,
he did.
How can this be? I killed him myself!
It is so, I fear.
Darth Maul alive?