Jedi abducted!
Ahsoka Tano is missing in action.
Captured and released
into a hostile jungle,
she fights to stay alive with the help
of a small band of Jedi younglings.
As Anakin Skywalker scours the galaxy,
desperate to find his lost apprentice,
Trandoshan sport hunters
track their youngling prey.
With the death of their leader Kalifa,
and separated from her friends,
we find Ahsoka on the run,
as the hunters close in around her.
Where is she?
This one was faster than most,
I've lost the scent!
She can't hide forever.
Mark my words,
I'll have her hide
and nail it to the wall for killing my son.
You made it!
We feared the worst.
Where's Kalifa?
She didn't make it.
She's dead?
I can't believe it.
She had been here longer than any of us,
and now...
We're all going to die here,
it's only a matter of time.
If it's only a matter of time till we die,
I say we go down with a fight.
That is suicide.
You've said that every few days
they release new prisoners on the beach.
I say we attack that dropship head on.
They'll never expect it.
Is it worth a shot?
Maybe it is.
Get ready, we'll have to be swift.
The drop point's not far.
Now!
What the...
It's one of those blasted Jedi whelps!
Get her!
I'll take the pilot!
Get out of there, come on!
But the prisoners! They'll die!
Hit the release, hurry!
Well, I guess we won't be escaping
on that ship.
We'll find another way.
- What was that?
- A survivor.
It could be one of the prisoners
they were dropping off.
What is that?
It's a Wookiee!
Ahh!
It's the younglings that did this.
They're getting bold.
What about survivors?
Both of our men were killed,
and there was only one prisoner,
a Wookiee.
And he's missing.
So now the younglings are organized, bold,
and they've got a Wookiee.
Your name is Chewbacca?
Chewbacca, does anyone even know
you were taken?
No, but he says his home world
is very close.
That's great,
but it might as well be Coruscant,
as far as I'm concerned.
We've got no ship.
He thinks he can contact his home planet
if we find a way to transmit a signal.
Right, and how would we do that?
Send smoke signals?
We don't exactly have a transmitter
lying around, if you haven't noticed.
Chewbacca says he can build a transmitter
from the wreckage on the beach.
Well, we can't just sit here.
Fine, we'll do it the Wookiee way.
Chewbacca and I will go out
to inspect the crash site.
You two stay here,
and signal us if you see anything.
Get back! It's a patrol.
Happy hunting.
Hopefully that patrol
won't be back for a while.
What are we looking for?
Are you still feeling optimistic about
making a transmitter out of this junk?
Now, what do we have here?
We better get going.
That patrol might come back.
Come on, pretties. One more step.
It looks clear, come on.
It's okay.
Time to join the Force, Jedi!
Sniper! Get down!
I'll gut you, whelp!
Wait! We should take him prisoner!
Fine. Chewbacca, let's take him.
How's it looking, Chewbacca?
Will it work?
Well, something's working.
We've got a prisoner.
We should be using him to our advantage
while we have a chance.
I thought the prisoner
was the backup plan?
It's clear enough
that we cannot rely on that device.
No offense,
but we just can't sit here any longer.
We should wait.
I agree with Jinx, we have to act
while we have an advantage.
Let's say we do it your way,
what's the plan?
We can use the prisoner to trick the enemy
into flying one of their pods down to us,
then we hijack the pod,
fly up to their base
and take them by surprise.
Ahsoka, you got us
to believe in ourselves again,
and, well, I believe Jinx's plan will work.
Look, do what you want,
but O-Mer and I are leaving
with the prisoner in the morning.
Their hearts are in the right place.
You know I can't let them go alone.
We're not going to be able
to do this without you.
We need your help.
Who knows?
Maybe our luck's just about to change.
All right, we better get started.
Right, time to call your friends.
I'm not helping you, whelp!
Chewbacca,
we need him at eye level, please.
You will listen to me.
No, I won't.
I will listen to you.
You were our captive,
but now you've escaped.
I was your captive but now I've escaped.
You need to call a speeder to pick you up.
I need to call a speeder to pick me up.
Smug? Where have you been?
I need a speeder to pick me up.
Get in. Let's go.
Now.
Want a lift?
Krix and Smug should be back by now.
Kill them! Kill them! I want their skins!
Hey, let's give him a lift.
A valiant effort, little younglings,
especially you, Togruta.
You will be a prized trophy
in my collection.
Make it quick, General.
We're charging by the minute.
And if my ship gets damaged,
it'll cost you extra.
Can you get me up there?
Lo-Taren!
What?
You're beaten.
You murdered my son,
and you need to pay for what you did.
Your son died because of your own actions,
not mine.
Don't!
Ahsoka!
It is good to see you safe, little Soka.
Ahsoka, I am so sorry.
For what?
For letting you go,
for letting you get taken.
It was my fault.
No, Master, it wasn't your fault.
I should've paid more attention,
I should've tried harder.
You already did everything you could,
everything you had to do.
When I was out there, alone,
all I had was your training
and the lessons you taught me.
And because of you, I did survive.
And not only that,
I was able to lead
others to survive as well.
I don't know what to say.
I do.
Thank you, Master.
You're welcome, my Padawan.