Lost!
Queen Julia of the planet Bardotta
has been abducted.
If Representative Jar Jar Binks
and Jedi Master Mace Windu
cannot find the missing Queen
in three rotations,
a sinister prophecy will be fulfilled.
The bloodthirsty Frangawl cult
will take over
the Bardottan government
and it's planetary system
will be overwhelmed by chaos,
death and destruction.
So, tell me exactly what you saw
when you were being held prisoner
by the cultists?
It's like mesa said.
The cultists took one of the Dagoyan
Masters and sacrificed him.
Hesa got all crispy-fried,
and then theysa stole
the Force right out of him
and put it in a shiny ball.
So the cultists are stealing living Force
and trapping it
in a containment sphere?
Yes. Theysa try to steal
my living Force, too,
but yousa saved me!
Hmm...
And now they plan to do the same thing
with the Queen, but to what end?
The cultists couldn't exploit
the living Force like a Jedi or a Sith.
I sense something else,
a darker presence.
Maxi big the Force, Masterin Mace,
but howsa we gonna find the Queenie?
She's still a prisoner.
If the containment sphere
has gathered enough
of the living Force, as you suggest,
I will be able to sense its location.
If we find the sphere,
we will find the Queen.
Okeday! Wesa make
a bombad team, Masterin Mace.
Indeed.
Where am I? Who are you?
Jar Jar? Jar Jar, where are you?
Unhand me!
Sleep.
No! No.
Brother, another vision
of the Great Mother came to me.
She said the Jedi knows of the sphere,
and that he is following us here
with the Gungan.
The Great Mother warned us
our plan would be discovered
if a Jedi ever came to Bardotta.
We did not know the Gungan
had such powerful friends.
Mmm... We must hurry.
Once we sacrifice
the Queen and transfer
the living Force
to the Great Mother,
she will deal with the Jedi.
Letsa get going.
Calm yourself, Representative.
Stay still.
But wesa must hurry.
That city, itsa mooie big.
Wesa have to move fast
to catch the cultists.
We cannot rush into this.
We must remain calm,
and let the Force guide us.
But maybe using da Force
taking too longo, and they getting away.
No, running blindly through
the city will only waste time
and allow them to escape,
now be still.
Okeday, Masterin Mace.
I see people, market, streets...
Yep, mesa see dat from here, too.
I see, crowds...
Wait, a square, a market square,
and the sphere...
I see it... And the Queen.
Let's go!
Wait, wait! Mesa thought
wesa not rushing in!
That was before
we knew where we were going.
Now the chase is on!
Mesa getting a creeping feeling here.
Do not center on your anxieties, Jar Jar.
Keep moving. This way.
This is it. The market square
I saw through the Force.
Stay alert.
The Queen may be close by.
I'm going topside for a better view.
Okeday.
Uh, hello?
Nope. No, thank you.
Mesa already got one of those.
Jar Jar, help!
Huh? Julia?
Jar Jar!
Julia! Masterin Mace, come quick!
Jar Jar, wait!
Uh-oh.
Jar Jar... What in the...
Mesa bet they're bringing
the Queenie this way.
- Queenie!
- Jar Jar!
Julia!
I've got this.
Keep after the Queen.
Oh, Julia!
Binks.
Mesa need to be brave.
Representative Binks!
Masterin Mace,
theysa went this way! Hurry!
Stop them!
Oh, boy.
Masterin Mace!
Queenie, mesa coming!
Why are you stealing the living Force?
The Shadow will come,
the Great Mother.
She will deal with you Jedi, you will see.
Have a nice nap!
Theysa gone!
They speeded away bombad fast.
Wesa need some kind of ride.
You're lucky I have no time to argue.
Let's get moving!
The appointed time draws near.
The sun and the moons
are almost aligned.
The Jedi is unyielding.
He will
arrive too late to save the Queen.
I have seen it in my visions.
Once the Great Mother
is in possession of the sphere,
she will combine her powers
with the living Force,
and a new order will arise.
Hyah!
Jar Jar!
Jar Jar, please.
Oh, Mesa sorry, Masterin Mace.
I'm just worried about the Queenie.
I understand your fears
and I am trying to help you,
but for now, keep your mind
focused on the task at hand.
That is the best way
you can help your friend.
Whysa you thinking
they want Queenie so badly?
As the spiritual leader of her people,
the living Force inside the Queen
must be very powerful.
Whoever the Great Mother is,
she wants that power.
Well, wesa not let them have
Queenie's Force.
No, we will not.
When we get to the temple, I'll handle
the guards and whatever evil we find.
You focus on the Queen.
And wesa good guys will triumph.
Right, Masterin Mace?
Yes.
Great Mother, my visions
have come to fruition.
At last, you are here.
You may rise.
Do you have the living sphere?
I can feel the power of the pure spirit
resonating in this orb!
The Jedi comes.
This temple is well protected.
When they arrive, the stone guardians
will deal with them.
We must begin the ritual at once.
Come.
Who are you?
The hour is far too late to trouble
yourself with such matters, my dear.
It may help you to know, however,
that I am not a natural Force wielder,
like the Jedi or Sith.
I use dark magic to achieve power.
But as a Bardottan,
you possess a strong connection
to the living Force.
A connection that will now be mine.
Never! I will not succumb to your evil!
How noble.
Upon that tower rests a device
that can harness the energy of the sun.
When the lenses are aligned,
the energy will rip your spirit from you
and I will gather it here.
With the combined power of your spirit
and my dark magic,
I will become more powerful
than any Sith or Jedi.
I see the Queen. The ritual has started.
Let's go.
Oh, boy. Masterin Mace!
Masterin Mace!
Oh, nosa! Demons!
Get behind me!
Mesa needing
some help back here!
Jar Jar, are you... Okay?
Look, mesa found a bang booma gun.
Nice work.
The Jedi have defeated
the stone guardians!
You mean the Jedi and the Gungan!
Jar Jar!
Mesa here, Queenie!
Master Windu.
I assume you are the Great Mother?
No, I am a simple witch,
not worth the trouble or attention
of the great Jedi Order.
A Nightsister!
Get the Queen!
Oh, boy!
Your power is no match for my magics!
Magic is only an illusion!
Hurry, Jar Jar!
Jar Jar, I knew you would save me.
Mesa never let anything
happen to you, Queenie.
Jar Jar, Your Highness,
over here.
I saw the witch when
I looked into the Force.
Jar Jar, I wanted to tell you.
I knew you would stop her.
You should be thanking Masterin Mace.
Jedi Master, I owe you my life.
It is my privilege to serve you,
Queen Julia.
Perhaps this is a new beginning
for the Bardottans and the Jedi.
Perhaps.