Planet Ryloth invaded!
Subjected to a brutal
droid occupation,
the people of Ryloth are starving
under the blockade
of a Separatist fleet.
Evil Separatist leader
Wat Tambor
now rules with an iron fist.
Answering a plea from the Senate,
the Grand Army of the Republic
mounts a bold offensive
to liberate the system.
It is up to Anakin Skywalker
and his Padawan Ahsoka
to make way
for Obi-Wan's ground assault.
Captain, are you prepared?
Our blockade is impenetrable.
When the Republic attacks,
they will get quite a surprise.
I'm counting on you, Captain.
We cannot allow the Republic
to invade this planet.
Sir, we're coming out of Hyperspace.
Prepare for battle, Raise the shields.
All ships prepare for launch.
This is my first time
commanding a squadron, R7.
Let's make a good impression.
Of course I'm not nervous
Hey,Snips this is it, First command.
Dont be nervous
I wish everyone would stop saying that
Now you're commanding people are
depending on you with their lives.
Thanks, that takes the pressure off.
If I wasnt nervous before I sure am now.
Hey, I have faith in you, I wouldn't send you out there
iIf I didn't think you could handle it.
May the Force be with you
I won't let you down. I hope.
OK, are you boys ready?
This is Two Ax.
Ready when you are, skipper.
Ready on three.
This is Slava. Over.
Ready on four.
Kicked back, checking in.
Soup to Blue leader.
Group Two is standing by. Over.
Taco on five.
Waiting for mother bird. Over.
Commander!  Yes Captain.
Launch all fighters.
Roger, roger.
- Tell Ahsoka the fleet is ready.
- Commander, you're all clear.
Thank you, Admiral.
Here we go.
- Clear!
- I'm on it.
- Nice work!
- Two new targets closing!
That is General Skywalker's
flagship.
He is leading this attack.
- Sir, their fighters are closing fast.
- Patience.
Let's see what trickery
the Jedi have planned for us.
We've got their fighters occupied.
Ax, time for us to make a run
for the battleship.
Come on, you whiners.
Let's get dirty!
Sir, a squadron of fighters
are attacking.
Battlecruiser 17, Battlecruiser 19,
attack position!
Admiral, four more enemy cruisers
have joined the blockade.
We've got to warn those fighters.
Commander,
we've been caught in a trap!
You're overreacting, Admiral.
I can get us through.
Blue Squadron, stay the course.
We're all set, Blue Leader.
I'm ordering you to return to the ship.
We're going to need your help.
Ahsoka, it's too risky.
Get your pilots out of there.
Sir, we've got their fighters
surrounded.
Good.
She's not turning around.
Ax, are you still there?
Got two on my tail.
I can't shake 'em!
I can't help you, Ax,
I've got my own problem.
- They're breaking our lines!
- Ahsoka, we are in trouble.
I order you back here.
All right, all right.
Let's go, squad.
Pull back to the command ship.
- Why are we retreating?
- We're not retreating. We're following orders.
Intensify deflector shields.
They're too many.
We can't shoot them all down!
Fighter squadron, where are you?
- We're almost there.
- It's too late!
Run for it!
Admiral, come in.
Admiral!
- Hang on, Admiral.
- Get us out of here.
Get those fighters onboard
and prepare for lightspeed.
All fighters return!
We're preparing for lightspeed.
Right.
Ax, stand on it!
We only have a few seconds
to get onboard.
Don't worry about me, skipper.
Captain, the Republic space forces
are in retreat.
Shall we pursue?
No.
Do not break our formation.
Let those cowards run.
My power converters,
they're failing!
Just stay with me, Ax.
Overload!
Ax!
Close up the hangar doors.
We're home.
Jump to lightspeed.
Get your squad together.
I need a head count.
I need to know
how many we lost today.
Ahsoka,
I am very disappointed in you.
You not only disobeyed the Admiral,
you disobeyed me.
I thought I could
knock out those battleships
so when Master Obi-Wan arrived,
he could get through.
I know you meant well, Snips,
but there's a bigger picture
that you're not aware of.
First rule of war,
listen and obey your superiors.
But sometimes you get carried away.
All that means is that I understand
what you're going through.
- But I failed.
- It was a trap, Snips.
It wasn't your fault.
I lost so many of my pilots.
Take heart, little one.
That's the reality of command.
General, we're approaching
our staging area.
Very good, Captain.
Master Windu is requesting
a report on our progress.
Our progress, huh?
- We haven't made any progress yet.
- I'll tell him, sir.
No, Rex.
I'll tell him myself, thank you.
As soon as we tend to our wounded,
get me a damage report.
Right away, sir.
Snips, I'm gonna need you to...
Captain, what is the status
of the enemy attack?
The Jedi were crushed, of course.
They fled the system,
their ships in flames.
I assure you, Admiral,
our blockade is very much intact.
Congratulations
are in order, Captain.
But do not underestimate the Jedi.
Commander,
bring me the archive data
on General Skywalker.
I need to learn more
about our opponent.
Roger, roger.
They caught us by surprise, Master.
- We were outnumbered.
- How many men did you lose?
We lost a cruiser, the Redeemer,
plus an entire squadron of fighters.
And your Padawan?
No, Ahsoka is fine.
She's just recovering from the battle.
Losing her squadron
was hard to take.
Give her time.
But, Anakin,
you will need her help
if you're going to get through this.
I know.
Your forces have been
cut in half, Skywalker.
If you can't break that blockade
before the next planetary rotation,
we will have to postpone the invasion.
The Twi'leks on that planet can't
wait forever, Master.
The longer the Techno Union
keeps control of Ryloth,
the more difficult it'll be
to free them.
I agree.
We don't have much time.
Rex, see if you can find Ahsoka.
He is stable for now.
Admiral, I am so sorry.
They're all gone.
Commander Ahsoka,
General Skywalker is looking for you.
No, R2, the other one.
Yeah, that's it.
This'll do it.
You wanted to see me, Master?
Ahsoka.
Hand me that socket plug.
Here.
Thanks, Snips.
How are you feeling?
Oh, I'm fine, Master.
Just fine.
That's good to hear.
I'm gonna need you level-headed
if we're gonna pull this thing off.
"Pull this off"?
Pull what off?
I talked to Master Windu.
We're to proceed
with our attack on the blockade.
What?!
We can't!
Ahsoka,
we have to break that blockade.
The Twi'leks on Ryloth
are depending on us.
I understand that, Master,
but we've lost so many men.
- Did we get more support?
- No.
We have to make do
with the forces we have.
- And I need to come up with a plan.
- You don't even have a plan?!
Don't worry, Ahsoka.
No!
That's what you said last time,
and now everyone's gone!
- My whole squadron!
- Ahsoka!
We can't just smash through
that blockade.
Skywalker here.
General,
the Defender is contacting us.
There seems to be a problem.
All right, Rex,
I'll be right there.
Go back to your quarters and cool off!
We'll finish this talk later.
Not a conventional Jedi,
to say the least,
it would seem.
- Commander!
- Yes, Captain?
Prepare all cannons and send
the droids to their battle stations.
Yes, sir.
Captain, are we under attack?
No, but if Skywalker's record
indicates anything,
he'll be back.
Trooper, what's going on?
The starship Defender
is being evacuated, sir.
Evacuated?
Why?
I'm not sure.
We're on our way
to help General Skywalker in the hangar.
All right, men, this way.
Come on, move it.
Move it! Let's go!
No time to waste!
Master, I'm almost afraid to ask.
- I ordered the Defender evacuated.
- I can see that.
Why?
Well, actually,
I got the idea from you.
Oh, great.
Rex, take over, will you?
You said we couldn't
just smash through the blockade.
I decided that's partly true.
You also implied that my plans
put a lot of people at risk
- and I agree with you on that one.
- That's a first.
I decided the only way
we can break the blockade
is if I pilot the Defender right into their
battleship and take out the commander.
- What?!
- This way I'm the only one at risk.
Besides, the Defender
is damaged already.
You can't be serious, Master.
- You'll die!
- No, I won't.
That's where you come in.
The enemy can't stop that ship
from taking them out.
R2 and I will get in an escape pod
and jettison right before impact.
But the enemy fleet is right there!
I know, and I'll pretty much be
defenseless in an escape pod,
so I'm depending on you
to engage the remaining fleet
with the combined forces
we have here.
Master, I...
I can't.
If something goes wrong,
I can't be responsible for--
You are responsible, Ahsoka.
These men are depending on you,
and this time so am I.
But, Master, last time I--
Attention! Everyone!
Attention!
All right, men,
listen up.
I'm taking over the Defender, and I'm
leaving Commander Ahsoka in charge.
She'll lead the second half
of the mission
when we engage
what's remaining of the blockade.
Commander Ahsoka will fill you in
on the full plan.
- Master, wait!
- Good luck.
Master!
Awaiting orders, Commander.
I'll be on the bridge.
Well, you heard her, boys.
Back to work!
Come on!
Move it! Move it!
- Commander on deck.
- At ease.
General Skywalker is contacting you.
All right, Ahsoka,
we're ready to get under way.
Master,
are you sure
you won't reconsider this?
This is the only way,
trust me.
Better fill us in, Commander.
Right.
Count Dooku has assured me
the Republic forces
are stretched thin in our sector.
They should be unable
to mount a counterattack.
Any attempt to do so
would be suicide.
Still, I am certain
this Skywalker will return.
His ultimate defeat
shall be my greatest victory.
You admire Skywalker?
As a general, yes.
His record shows
he is a great warrior.
And I want him to know
it is I...
...who has beaten him.
I have to say
this plan is questionable.
Yeah, but with their general destroyed
along with their battleship,
the droid commanders
will be in chaos.
Only temporarily.
And there's still General Skywalker
to find in all that mess.
I know, but--
In our first attack we had three
fully armed cruisers, and we failed.
I wish General Skywalker
had discussed this plan with us.
The odds are very much against us.
They always are.
Yes, but normally we have
General Skywalker to lead us and...
I meant no offense, Commander.
None taken.
Sir, an enemy ship
is emerging from hyperspace.
I knew he'd return.
There is
an incoming transmission, sir.
Put it through.
Greetings, Captain.
I'm Anakin Skywalker,
general of the Grand Army...
I know who you are, Skywalker.
Well, my reputation precedes me, then.
I've been ordered
to surrender myself,
the entire crew of this vessel
and my ship
in exchange for safe passage of food
and medical supplies
to the people of Ryloth.
A noble gesture, Jedi.
And your capture
would make me
the envy of the Separatist fleet.
Sir, even if Skywalker is successful
and destroys the battleship,
how will we stand up to the combined
firepower of the remaining frigates?
I thought about that
and, well, I have an idea.
Go ahead, Commander.
If we took the Resolute and angled
her hull against the incoming frigates,
the bridge and hangar deck would be
relatively safe from their attack.
We could draw them in and then
use the bombers to outflank them.
The bombers would be too fast,
and they would be trapped.
I'm not sure about this, Commander.
I think...
If we were certain
the shields would hold...
Perhaps a different strategy.
We need to take more time and plan.
No!
We don't have any more time!
Master Skywalker needs me now!
He needs us now.
The Commander is right.
I know this strategy is very bold,
but these circumstances
call for drastic measures.
Then, the strategy will work, sir?
Well, will it?
Yes, it will.
We have completed the scan
of the enemy ship.
And?
The ship is heavily damaged.
All power is diverted
to the forward shields.
There is only one life-form onboard.
- What?!
- The ship is heavily damaged.
- All power is--
- No, you insolent scrub!
Skywalker, what treachery is this?
You have nothing to bargain with.
In that case, I'll be going.
You can still have my ship.
Uh, sir...
there's a second Republic ship
entering the system.
She made it!
Boost the engines
and let's get outta here.
When those two ships collide,
there'll be chaos.
We need that time
to get General Skywalker's pod
into the tractor beam.
Right, Commander.
I'll man the fighter squadron.
Wait for my signal
to begin our attack.
Yes, sir.
All cannons, fire!
Fire!
We can't stop it!
- What should we do?
- You stay here. I'll be back.
That's great.
See, I told you
it would work.
We're approaching your position.
Stand by for retrieval.
Right on time, Ahsoka.
I don't think
they're going to attack, Commander.
- We'll have to retreat.
- No! Wait!
Remember, they are droids.
They're just a little slow.
They'll figure it out.
I think the Captain left.
- Who's in charge?
- Not me.
- What should we do?
- Begin attack.
The droids are attacking, sir.
Commander, on your order,
commence flanking manoeuvre.
OK, boys, here we go.
Follow my lead.
- We've been outflanked!
- Affirmative!
That-a girl, Ahsoka.
Where is the Captain?
What is going on?
He's in an escape pod.
Idiots!
The blockade has been broken!
Where are those escape pods?
Commander, the invasion fleet
is coming out of hyperspace.
Ahsoka, this is Obi-Wan.
May we begin our landing?
Yes, Master.
You're cleared for ground assault.
I won't even ask
where the rest of Anakin's fleet is,
or why he's in an escape pod.
That's probably for the best.
Rex, that reminds me,
send a shuttle
to pick up Master Skywalker.
General, are you still there?
Yep. I'm just sitting here
watching the show.