Cause ofdeath unknown!
Kaminoan Doctor Nala Se was unable
to find the cause of an illness
in Clone Trooper Tup.
In a desperate attempt
to save his friend's life,
Fives located and removed a tumor
from Tup's brain
with the help of medical droid AZI-3.
Immediately following the procedure,
Tup died,
and Fives was placed under arrest.
Now, the tumor is the only hope
to finding answers
for Tup's mysterious illness.
General, what did the Chancellor say?
Supreme Chancellor Palpatine
wants the tumor
and all of the intel gathered
sent to the Grand Republic
Medical Facility on Coruscant.
So, then I'll be going
to Coruscant as well?
You were not a part
of the Chancellor's request.
I'm sorry, Fives,
but this is a matter best left
to the medical professionals.
There is still so much we do not know.
Perhaps we would know more
if this clone had not taken matters
into his own hands.
Listen! I was trying to save my friend!
And yet perhaps by removing
this tumor, it was you who killed him.
What do you care?
You were going to kill him anyway,
and dissect him, too.
He's a soldier. He deserves better!
Stand down, Fives!
Doctor, there is no proof of your claim.
I want this specimen and all the data
prepared for transit to the Jedi Temple.
The Chancellor said the tumor and data
was to be sent directly
to the Medical Facility on Coruscant,
not the Jedi Temple.
And it will get there,
but after the Jedi have run
an analysis on it first.
I protest. I must personally deliver
the tumor to the Chancellor as ordered.
You can protest all you want.
My word is final.
You have one more physical to pass.
If you are cleared,
you will be sent back to the 501 st.
Thank you, General.
It will be good to put this
entire incident behind you, Trooper.
I agree.
AZI-3!
Hello, ARC Trooper Fives.
I regret that we were
unable to heal your friend.
Yeah, me, too.
Are you going to be
reprogrammed as well?
No, AZI, I'm going back to the front.
That is not what I heard.
I heard your mind was going to be wiped
and that you would be reassigned here
and placed on sanitation detail.
We can still be friends,
assuming we both remember each other
after our memories have been erased.
Let's go, CT-5555.
No!
Look what you did!
I cannot believe what you did!
I am not getting my mind erased,
and neither are you.
Get out of here!
Are we escaping?
Why are we here?
I knew it!
Nala Se switched the cases.
She's trying to hide something.
Oh, the tumor?
So we are going to
continue our research?
Yeah, the research, that's it.
Now come on!
Whoa!
I'm sorry, sir. All ships are locked down
during the emergency.
- Oh? What about that one?
- Hey!
There they are!
Sorry, brother.
I want him brought in alive!
- Have that ship tracked.
- Yes, ma'am.
Can you float?
I am buoyant
and have several survival modes.
Ah! Survival, eh?
Autopilot
engaged. Navigation and orbit set.
Wait! What are you doing?
I thought we were escaping?
Nope, this is a diversion.
I need them to chase this pod
while we go back and investigate
the cause of Tup's death.
Any more questions, Doctor?
Actually, yes, now that you mention it...
AZI! AZI!
Now what?
We're going back to figure out
why Tup died.
I can get us there much faster.
Oh! You're just full of surprises,
aren't you?
This is one
of my various survival modes.
I am equipped...
Droids.
A "thank you" would have been nice.
Lord Tyranus, you summoned me?
Prime Minister Lama Su tells me
there has been a complication.
What has happened
to the inhibitor chip?
It was stolen by a renegade clone.
What does this clone know?
Nothing as of yet.
He is just a soldier, after all.
However, he was a friend
to the clone which malfunctioned.
This behavior is unsettling.
First the malfunctioning clone
and now a renegade.
Are you certain these soldiers
will live up to your design in the end?
I am certain. The malfunction to
the inhibitor chip is an aberration.
And how do you explain the renegade?
I'm afraid the Jedi have inspired
creative thinking in some of the clones.
That is the cause of this type
of divergent behavior.
Will this interfere with Protocol 66?
No, I am certain of that.
Find the renegade clone immediately
and make sure you recover the chip.
The true nature of the inhibitor chip
must not be discovered by the Jedi.
Yes, Lord Tyranus.
What... Oh.
Once we're inside, I need you to
get me a change of clothes, AZI.
Trooper, I think I saw the renegade
clone head into the storage room.
All right, let's check it out.
I think he was over there.
We need to
get the tumor analyzed.
Follow me.
This is the Genetic Records Hall.
It contains data on the original DNA
of every being we have ever cloned.
We will compare the tumor's DNA
versus that of Jango Fett,
the original donor.
If any tumor like this has been
noted before, we will find it.
The tumor, please?
- Nothing.
- What?
The sample doesn't match anything
found in the Jango Fett genotype.
Furthermore, it is not
even completely organic.
It is foreign to the body.
Someone implanted it there.
An implant?
You mean this isn't an accident?
- Someone did this to Tup?
- Precisely.
There have been no unauthorized ships
leaving Kamino, General.
I sense we are looking
in the wrong place.
We have a report
from the Genetic Records Hall.
Explain.
Someone is accessing
the Jango Fett genotype.
It's them.
Evacuate that room quietly.
Is there another way out of here
besides the door we came in?
Yes, there are emergency
access hatches in every major room
in case of flooding.
Good, let's get moving.
There.
It's no good.
They've sealed it from the inside.
Station your men at every access point
back into the main hallway system!
Yes, ma'am.
Did you get
all the information you needed?
Mostly. We know that the tumor
is a foreign material
and was implanted
for an unknown reason.
However, there is still so much
we do not know about it.
For example, at what stage
was it introduced to Clone Tup?
And why?
What is this thing?
Why would someone put it in Tup?
I believe this is an organic chip
built out of cells.
- What's it for?
- I do not know.
Ah, thanks. I need to find out
if what was in Tup's head is in mine.
We have already done a scan and...
But it was missed in Tup, and it
could have been missed in me, too!
You have to take it out.
We cannot be 100% sure
if the chip is even there.
I know it's there.
It is a dangerous surgery...
Look, you got it out of Tup,
you can get it out of me.
He died after I removed the chip.
Maybe it is connected.
You may die, too.
It's a chance I have to take.
I trust you.
All right, I will do it.
Let us go to a sterile facility.
Hold still. This will not hurt a bit.
Ahhh!
You sure you know
what you're doing, right?
Why, yes. I have been programmed
to perform over 100...
All right, all right.
Let's do this.
You will only be unconscious
for a few minutes.
There's no sign of them, General.
They must have escaped by now.
Escape was never their intention.
They are investigating, searching.
Their appearance
in the genetics labs proves this.
But what are they searching for?
Well? Was it...
- Was it there?
- Yes.
Identical in structure.
However, it appears that the one I found
in your friend had malfunctioned,
while yours is perfectly intact.
Are you sure
his breakdown was isolated?
There is no way of knowing that.
And now that we have
removed your chip,
we do not know what will happen to you.
So, then,
I could snap, too?
Possibly. But when we removed
the chip from Tup, he...
I am afraid you may die as well.
I need to know if more clones
than just Tup and I have these,
and when we were implanted with them.
My analysis suggests
implantation took place
at the earliest stage of development,
most likely when you
and Tup were only embryos.
Then we have to start there.
Oh, great.
Try to act normal.
Normal?
Hello!
How was that? Was that normal?
For you, AZI, yeah.
We will start with the earliest stage
of development.
Nothing. I will now try a Stage 3 embryo.
- There it is!
- Ah! Try another.
Based on this data, I can calculate
how many in this tree are altered.
I can't believe it.
They all have one.
Don't move.
Why are you doing this?
I know what you've done!
What is it that you think I have done?
How do you explain this?
That is a structural inhibitor chip,
which is supposed to prevent you
from being aggressive,
like your source, Jango Fett.
Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas instructed us to
implant them during your growth cycle.
The Jedi?
The Jedi had this done to us?
It is not uncommon to have
inhibitors placed in a clone.
I have analyzed this one,
and apparently it has failed.
Up until this point,
there has never been a problem.
Well, you have got a big problem now.
Don't move!
Drop your weapon.
Master Jedi, I know what's going on.
I have the evidence.
The Jedi instructed that inhibitor chips
be implanted in us at birth,
but Tup's malfunctioned.
That's what made him lose control.
Where is the evidence?
I have it right here.
As you can see, the chip taken from
Clone Trooper Tup is black and rotting,
indicating a malfunction of some sort.
What caused the malfunction?
It doesn't matter.
The fact is Tup's chip malfunctioned
and it drove him insane.
These chips have to be removed,
otherwise the entire Republic Army
could be compromised.
There's no proof of that!
This is an isolated incident.
Besides, when you removed
Trooper Tup's chip, he died.
Well, that's not going to happen
to the rest of us.
And how do you know that?
Because I removed mine!
Here is Clone Trooper Fives' chip.
As you can see, there is no sign of
malfunction in either him or the chip.
By removing your chip, you are a threat.
Master Jedi, we must terminate
this trooper immediately.
I am not a piece of hardware!
I'm a living being.
You were
created in our laboratories.
You are Kaminoan property!
Correction, technically,
he is property of the Republic.
That does not change the fact that
he is a danger and must be terminated.
I believe that's for me to decide.
Fives, you are coming
with me to Coruscant.
I think it's time you told
your story to the Chancellor.
Master Jedi! I beg you to reconsider!
The Chancellor wanted all the data
on Tup to be sent to Coruscant.
We're sending the data, the tumor
and Fives along with it.
Then I am going with you.
As you wish, Doctor.
Thank you for believing in me, General.
It is not a matter of belief, Fives,
it is simply the right thing to do.
It looks like
you got what you wanted.
Thanks to you.
I'll see you on the other side.
The other side of what?
Ah, droids.