Warprofiteers!
In time of war, credits are
the fuel that fund all operations.
Senator Amidala is sent to Scipio
to resolve matters
between the Republic
and lnterGalactic Banking Clan.
Here she is reunited with Rush Clovis,
a once close friend,
but now known traitor to the Republic.
When Clovis reveals corruption
at the core of the Banking Clan,
Senator Amidala
helps him steal vital files
that may uncover
the full extent of the plot.
Anakin Skywalker is sent
to rescue the Senator
and escort the information
back to Coruscant,
leaving the Banking Clan in chaos.
The Jedi Anakin Skywalker
should never have been allowed
to leave with the Senator in tow.
Any future disruptions will be placed
upon your shoulders, Nix Card.
As you wish.
Sir, we have confirmed
that Rush Clovis was on the Jedi's ship.
Then there's nothing we can do.
But they have the files!
Unfortunate, yes, but they need
more than just files to incriminate us.
That will only take them time.
We will all be destroyed.
We must remain calm.
The only way
they could find our secret accounts
is if one of us told them.
I want it noted that you
and you alone allowed this to happen,
and that it has put us all at risk!
You're late! What news?
Clovis, the Senator
and the Jedi are on their way.
- With the information?
- Enough.
Good. Then we can continue
to the next stage of the proceedings.
And what about me?
You will be protected, I can assure you.
Master Yoda?
We weren't expecting
such a formal welcome, Master.
A personal request of the Chancellor's,
my escorting you was, Senator.
Adventures have you had
on Scipio, hmm?
- Have you met Rush Clovis?
- Met we have, yes.
Intrigued we are by your return
to Coruscant.
Much distrust is focused upon you.
I understand, but I hope to right
the wrongs that I have done.
Delay, we must not.
Excuse me
if I find it hard to trust you, Clovis.
You used to sit on this very Senate
even as you funneled credits
into the droid foundries of Count Dooku.
I understand all of your trepidation.
But there is corruption in the banks.
And once we find this corruption?
I believe the ones responsible
should be ousted from control
before the entire
banking infrastructure collapses.
Oh, and I suppose
you're the man to do it?
I only want the Banking Clan
to be what it once was,
a fair system of trade and commerce.
I came here to root out the criminals
and reveal the truth
behind what is happening.
Now, now, we are grateful
for you bringing us this information,
but what exactly can you prove?
These files show that huge funds
have been diverted out of the banks
and into what I believe
are private accounts.
And the veracity of this information?
I was the one who downloaded the files
from the Muuns' secure mainframe.
I believe that what Clovis is saying
is correct.
Then, Senator Amidala, I would like you
to spearhead this investigation.
Work closely with Rush Clovis and find
and expose these secret accounts.
Once we know exactly
what we are dealing with,
then we can decide
how best to handle this situation.
Why didn't you just say no?
Say no. Why?
I don't want you working with Clovis.
You don't want me working with him?
A serpent can shed its skin,
but it is still a serpent.
Well, you're just going to have
to trust my judgment here.
Like the last time, hmm?
When you almost ended up dead?
Or how about you just getting arrested,
and it was me who had to bail you out?
The Chancellor has asked me
to do this, Anakin.
But I am asking you to say no.
As your husband,
I demand that you tell the Chancellor
you are stepping down.
Demand? We've been over this before.
I'm not foolish enough to allow myself
to be deceived twice, Anakin.
My sole intentions are
to defend the Republic.
- If you can't trust me...
Uh, excuse the interruption, Padme.
Shall we begin?
Yes, of course.
General Skywalker.
Darth Tyranus,
it is time for you once again
to recruit our friend Clovis.
He appears to have lost his way.
And how would you like me to do that?
We're going to help him
take over the Banking Clan.
But first, you must entrap him,
so he has no one else to turn to.
Of course, my Lord. As you wish.
I've been looking for you.
- Something wrong?
- You tell me.
Not that I'm aware.
Master Yoda feels that yourjudgments
concerning Rush Clovis are clouded.
Hmm. I believe he can't be trusted.
Yes, but there is more, isn't there?
I sense a deep anger in you
by my simply saying his name.
He almost got Senator Amidala killed,
and I would have been responsible.
The Senator has risked her life
many times.
She's quite capable
of taking care of herself.
They had a relationship once.
I simply feel
she's vulnerable to her emotions.
She is, or you?
What are you implying?
Anakin, I understand to a degree
what is going on.
You've met Satine. You know
I once harbored feelings for her.
It's not that we are not allowed
to have these feelings. It's natural.
Senator Amidala and I
are simply friends.
And friends you must remain.
As a Jedi, it is essential you make
the right choice, Anakin, for the Order.
I understand my responsibilities.
Responsibilities that must be observed
whatever relationship develops
between Clovis and Senator Amidala.
They have no relationship.
It is simply business between them.
Then we should have
no problems, should we?
The opera was wonderful, but
I am glad we can get down to business.
If you look here,
the Separatists haven't been repaying
any interest on their loans.
But still the Banking Clan is promising
to lend credits to the Republic.
Credits they simply don't have.
But where have all the savings gone?
Each of the files that you downloaded
shows hundreds and hundreds
of small withdrawals.
Small enough to remain
undetected individually,
but as a sum total,
- a devastating theft.
Whoever is behind this is no fool.
We need to find out who's benefiting.
We're still lacking
a critical piece of information.
Whatever we find must remain
between only you and I.
This would be
highly dangerous information
- should it get into the wrong hands.
- Of course.
This reminds me
when we had three nights
to prepare for the Senate hearing
to rescue Bromlarch's
planetary aqueduct system.
And together
we saved a people
from total drought and famine.
I don't think either of us
got any sleep that whole week.
Let alone ate anything.
We're not as young
as we used to be.
- We're not that old either.
You might be right.
Perhaps we should eat something.
So, Clovis, why have you gotten
so involved with the Muuns?
I believe in the banks.
The system works.
The Muuns aren't bad people.
It's just a dishonest few
who are destroying everything
for their own gain.
You know, you've never told me
how you rose to such heights
within the Banking Clan.
It's not a happy story.
My father was personal attache
to the household
of one of head Muun families.
We were basically servants.
I had no idea.
As I grew up, the head of the family took
a personal interest in my education.
I was the same age as his children,
and so we all studied together.
When my parents and his wife
were killed in a shuttle accident,
he adopted me.
- How old were you?
- Twelve.
That must have been very hard.
I was accepted as their child
everywhere we went.
I almost forgot where I was from
until I looked in the mirror.
- They sound like good people.
- They are. Most Muuns are,
and they want this corruption ended
more than I do.
You should know my contacts
within the Muun government run deep.
I have many allies,
should I need to call on them.
I didn't appreciate
how personal this was for you.
- Now, maybe you will trust me.
- I'm here, aren't I?
I want to thank you
for everything you've done for me.
I don't think I would have had
the strength alone.
Clovis, don't.
- It's that Jedi isn't it?
- General Skywalker?
We're friends, nothing more.
Friends don't argue
the way I saw you arguing today.
You're confused.
Isn't it forbidden
for a Jedi to have romantic ties?
He would be banished from the Order,
would he not?
There is nothing romantic
between he and I.
Then there is absolutely nothing
to stop us from doing this.
Clovis! Clovis, no!
Get away from her!
Anakin! No!
Why don't you try fighting like a man
without your Jedi tricks?
Oh, it would be my pleasure.
Both of you stop this!
You don't have a say in this!
I thought you said
he didn't have feelings for you?
Ahhh! I see you for what you truly are!
You're a serpent, a traitor!
Please! Stop this! No!
Is that all you got?
You should accept
that the Senator
- has other interests than you.
Skywalker, you fool.
Stop it! Anakin, stop!
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
Senator Amidala,
is everything okay in there?
No. Come in immediately.
What has happened here?
There was an attack.
It was good fortune
to have General Skywalker here.
They escaped in a speeder
over the balcony.
Is that what happened, sir?
If that's what the man says.
A medic droid is on its way.
Please, help Clovis into the bedroom.
Padme, I'm...
Stay away from me.
- How is he?
- Nothing that won't heal.
I'm so sorry, Padme.
I don't know what came over me.
What's done is done.
It's just when I saw you
about to kiss him...
And I regret that,
but it was not what you thought.
And you must know
I don't care for Clovis.
Don't you?
I've told you why I'm doing this,
but still you refuse to accept it.
- You could have killed him, Anakin.
- I know.
This marriage is not a marriage, Anakin,
if there isn't any trust.
We said at the beginning
that this could be a terrible mistake.
What exactly are you saying?
That other people who are married
have everything that we don't,
everything that we won't.
We live in secret, Anakin.
Like it or not, our relationship is built
on lies and deception.
No relationship can survive that.
I know I went too far. It's just...
It's just something inside me snapped.
I don't know who's in there sometimes.
I just know that I'm not happy anymore.
I don't feel safe.
But, Padme...
I think it's best
if we don't see each other anymore.
At least not for a while.
I'm sorry, Anakin.
Um...
I'm sorry, too.
Everything all right, Senator?
No.
Nothing appears to be broken.
But more importantly,
someone wants to speak with you.
What are you talking about?
I am a servant of Count Dooku.
- Hello, Clovis.
- What do you want, Dooku?
It appears we have a mutual problem
that I would like to fix.
I know the Separatists have not been
repaying their loans to the banks.
Now why would we
support corruption?
You expect me to believe
that Lesser and his associates
have no ties with you?
They've allowed you to borrow credits
and not pay any interest.
What you say is correct,
but that information, if made public,
will only bring war to Scipio,
and the banks will fall.
Nobody wants that.
So in the interests of all,
I suggest we come
to some arrangement.
What are you saying?
That the banks need
new management,
and that it could be you.
That I would like help.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say you were afraid.
I prefer the term careful.
These are delicate matters.
We need funds just as the Republic
does to pay for this war.
I can give you the location
of the secret accounts
you are searching for
so you can plead your case
to the Senate.
And you won't stand in my way?
We'll even start paying the interest
on our loans
to show the Republic
our full endorsement.
What do you get out of this?
Stability in unstable times.
The location of the accounts
are on this disk.
Now, where were we?
The Muun government
has seized the accounts
and arrested the heads
of the Banking Clan.
We are indebted to Rush Clovis
for his service to our people.
Well, I have done
only what I thought was right.
Considering the information,
it appears that the Separatist
government has agreed
to allow you
to be the new head of the banks.
- And the Republic?
- I can only give you my endorsement.
Now, all that stands in your way
is the Senate.
Order! Order!
- Good luck.
- Thank you!
Rush Clovis
will now address the Senate.
Traitor!
Clovis?
I come to you today
with irrefutable evidence
that the heads of the Banking Clan
have been stealing funds
and have virtually bankrupted
the system.
What?
How dare you!
I know the Muuns to be
a good and honest people,
and that it is the actions of only these
unscrupulous few who are responsible.
I humbly ask you for your nomination
in taking over the banks.
What can you do?
I will restore order
and return the banks back to secure
and neutral negotiations
and transactions.
How can we trust you?
I vow to be impartial
and show no favor
to either side in this war.
But you have colluded
with the Separatists!
It is the Separatists' ties to Rush Clovis
that has allowed them
to accept this nomination.
He also has the full support
of the Muun people.
And what of the Chancellor?
I believe that in these dangerous times,
the bank must be protected at all costs,
and that a man
who has no allegiance to either side
and the support of the Muun people
is our best hope.
Then we shall put it to a vote.
A resounding majority
in support of the nomination.
My boy, I can tell
this has been a difficult time.
I've known you too long
not to see something is troubling you.
Your Excellency, forgive me,
but you have made a mistake
by trusting Clovis.
Have I?
Rest assured,
my public endorsement of Clovis
is not the same
as my private confidence in him.
Then what exactly is going on here?
We will watch him closely.
I don't dispute your distrust of him.
I think there is something
we haven't unearthed yet,
and I would very much like
for it to surface.
But people have been hurt,
could be hurt, in the process.
Let us make sure that doesn't happen,
shall we?