Escape from a Separatist prison!
Carrying information about secret routes
into the heart of the Republic
and Separatist home worlds,
Jedi Master Even Piell was captured,
and imprisoned in a fortress
known as the Citadel.
Leading an elite strike team,
Obi-Wan Kenobi and Anakin Skywalker
rescued Master Piell and his officers.
Now the Jedi have split up
to evade Separatist forces
as they attempt to escape the Citadel...
Artoo, are you and your battle droids
ready to go?
All right, get the ship fired up,
we'll meet you at the pipeline exit
after you've picked Obi-Wan,
assuming he's still on schedule.
This passage will
get us near the landing pad.
Artoo, send the shuttle to
the rear landing platform.
We've already been given the go-ahead
by General Skywalker, sir.
Assuming you are still on schedule.
The trick will be if
Anakin arrives on time.
A probe!
Did you get it?
Security doors!
Move or you'll be cut in half!
I can't!
We lost one.
Looks like we've got some cutting to do.
Count Dooku insists that you
speak with him, Commander.
Well, let's not keep him waiting.
He's already waiting, sir.
Count Dooku, my lord. How unexpected.
You may cease the propriety,
Commander Sobeck.
I understand there is a problem
with the Jedi prisoner.
An incursion team attempted a rescue,
but the situation is taken care of.
Are you in possession of the information
the prisoner is carrying?
Not yet. But we will soon have it.
You are aware that this information will
tip the scale of the war to
the side that controls it.
Perhaps, this is a matter that
requires my presence?
No, my lord.
Find them, Commander.
Get the information,
then kill them all.
Don't ever surprise me with
a transmission from Count Dooku!
I need time to prepare!
Yes, Commander.
I am beginning to admire
the design of this fortress.
It's rather formidable to evade.
How can you admire such a horrible place?
Ah, you reveal your short-sightedness.
This ordeal only demonstrates how
effective facilities like the Citadel are.
Pity it ended up in Separatist hands
and not ours.
He has a point.
All right, Snips,
I need you to lead the group.
Keep following the tunnel. I'll catch up.
Hey, where are you going?
Obi-Wan's not here,
so someone has to protect our flank.
I guess it's a good thing I came along
after all.
We've received a coded transmission.
Apparently they've split up
into two groups.
The rendezvous points are
the landing field behind the tower
where Artoo will pick up Obi-Wan Kenobi,
and the pipeline exit
where they'll find Anakin Skywalker.
And what if things
don't go according to plan?
Then we would have to send an entire fleet
to get them out of there.
I am concerned that the Jedi have
elected this child to lead the group.
I've served with her many times
and I trust her, Captain.
Uh-oh.
Dead end.
It looks like
there are security guards there.
Okay, boss, we'll land and wait
for General Kenobi.
Uh-oh. That doesn't look like
General Kenobi.
We'll have to improvise.
Your arrival is long overdue,
where have you been?
Even so, the odds are 3-to-1
that you are a traitor.
We will take you to interrogation below.
Yes, sir. Move it!
Don't talk back to me,
droid. I'm in charge.
We have captured the shuttle
that infiltrated our defenses.
Good, guard the shuttle
and we'll lure the Jedi into a trap.
Sorry, Commander. Just wanted to
fool them. What are your orders?
You're right! If we're not at the shuttle,
General Kenobi could be
walking into a trap!
We'll try to locate them
if they get captured.
Look out!
What happened?
Why didn't you blow the wall?
That part of the plan was your job!
I thought it was a dead end.
If Master Plo really assigned you
to this mission,
he would have briefed you on the plan.
The shuttle's there
but there's no sign of Artoo.
Something might have happened.
We'll have to make our way around to
the other side and get a different view.
This could be a trap.
Anakin?
I must commend you on
your escape tactics,
but in the end it was easy to
predict your every move.
This pipe leads up to the top of the ridge,
where Artoo will pick us up
and get us out of here.
There's the hatch.
Let's go! Let's go! Everyone in.
Don't use your lights,
and make sure your weapons are locked.
The slightest electronic pulse could
ignite this whole tube.
I hope somebody tells the droids that.
Welcome back.
I must say, you're not at all what I pictured
for someone who has such a soft voice.
I want your half
of the information.
Give it to me now,
or I'll start executing your men.
This is war, Sobeck.
They're all prepared to die
to protect that intel.
Really?
Sir, we have located the other group
and our droids are closing in on them.
Your Jedi resolve
only delays the inevitable.
Take them to Interrogation.
Torture them slowly.
So they were captured, huh?
And now they're moving them to
the prison block?
Yes, sir! We will move to intercept them.
We'll take them from here.
Uh, I think we have a...
We'll handle it.
Yes, sir!
Good to see you, Artoo.
I wondered where you've been.
The Commander is pleased to
see you as well, sir,
but would like to return to the shuttle
as soon as possible.
Yes, I couldn't agree more.
What about General Skywalker, sir?
Not to worry, he'll switch to plan B.
How much longer are we going to
wander through this tunnel in the dark?
Captain Tarkin,
haven't you learned to trust me by now?
You may have earned my trust,
General Skywalker,
but my faith in your comrades
is still lacking.
You lack faith in the Jedi.
I find their tactics ineffective.
The Jedi code prevents them from
going far enough to achieve victory.
To do whatever it takes to win.
The very reason why
peace keepers should not be leading a war.
Have I offended you?
No. I've also found that
we sometimes fall short of victory
because of our methods.
Well, I see we agree on something.
I think I found a way out.
What do you see, Snips?
The coast is clear.
Any sign of Obi-Wan and the shuttle?
No, I don't see him or Artoo anywhere.
We've got to go!
There could be
a whole battalion of droids out there!
Better than hiding in a fuel line.
The plan's been compromised.
The shuttle's not coming.
Throw me a charge!
Let's go! Time for plan B.
There's a plan B?
There's always a backup plan.
We'll meet Artoo at Obi-Wan's position.
Based on their recent position,
we believe they're traveling
along this cave system.
Uh, sir, the prisoners did not make it to
the interrogation level.
What did you just say?
Um, we think they might have...
Sir, Count Dooku commands you to
contact him immediately.
Inform Count Dooku that I am unreachable.
Send all units to the airfield.
It's their only possible way of escape.
Hold it!
Where are you going with these prisoners?
We're transferring them
aboard the shuttle.
From Citadel to Point Tarron.
Point Tarron? There's no outpost there.
Uh, it's new.
We have orders. We're coming aboard.
Wait.
The prisoners are escaping
with reprogrammed battle droids.
Let no one on board that shuttle.
Sorry I'm late.
How nice of you to join us!
The ship is surrounded!
We need to launch a full-forward assault
and take that vessel!
We may have a bigger problem.
Those turrets. If we don't take them out,
they will use them to destroy the shuttle
and prevent our escape.
Which is precisely why
we should get aboard that shuttle,
and use the weapon systems to
decimate those droids.
Whatever we're going to do,
we better do it fast.
General Skywalker,
a droid is manning one of those turrets.
They're going to blow up the shuttle, sir.
This is our only chance.
We've got to stop him.
Echo, look out!
Echo!
We have to go now!
Master Kenobi, what has happened?
I'm afraid we've had a situation
with the shuttle.
By "situation," he means big explosion.
We're going to need a rescue.
It will be done.
I'm sending our cruisers now.
We'll need to hold out
until the Council sends a ship.
Not a problem. We've beat them once,
we'll beat them again.
This landscape is
almost impossible to cross.
How are we going to get to
the rendezvous point?
That is the trap of the Citadel.
It was designed so it would be
almost impossible
for fugitives to get off the surface,
even if they escaped the tower.
Lucky we're not just any fugitives.
I hope you're right.