Mysterious deaths!
Unknown to the Jedi,
a new threat has been unleashed
on the galaxy,
Savage Opress,
a pawn in the dangerous game
between Count Dooku
and his former assassin, Ventress.
The victims of his brutal massacre
on the planet of Devaron
are being returned to the Jedi Temple
for evaluation.
It's up to the Jedi Council
to find this mysterious killer
and eradicate him.
There were no survivors on Devaron.
Everyone was killed,
including Master Halsey and his Padawan.
In the past, only Dooku's assassin
was capable of such an effort.
But she was presumed dead
at the battle of Sullust.
Not everything is what it seems.
There may be a new threat.
Someone or something has eluded us,
perhaps a newly appointed Sith Lord.
This is not the work of a Sith Lord
or a Jedi,
but a reckless, impulsive animal.
You have no technique.
Sloppy.
But with the proper training,
you could be a powerful warrior.
You have a natural ability,
but we must hone it.
Are you up for the challenge
of putting your hate to better use?
Yes, Master.
Master Yoda, you called for me?
Master Kenobi.
Show you something we must.
We have recovered surveillance footage
of the massacre on Devaron.
Darth Maul alive?
It can't be! I killed him myself!
Correct you are, Obi-Wan.
A creature of the same species he is,
from Dathomir.
Dathomir? The planet of the witches?
I was under the impression that
Darth Maul's home world was Iridonia.
Dathomir is the planet
where Maul was raised.
Iridonia is where the rest of the males
of the species dwell.
Travel to Dathomir you must.
Find the source of this threat you will.
You must strengthen your connection
with the Force, my apprentice.
Feel its power within you.
Now, lift them.
Concentrate!
What you ask is impossible!
Impossible?
The task is only impossible
because you have deemed it so!
You must connect with your hatred!
Focus on your power building.
Do not think of anyone or anything else.
That's it!
Your anger is your strength!
I hate you!
Good.
How does one defend against such power?
A wise master does not reveal
all his secrets at once.
In due time, my apprentice.
There's the village.
Be on guard.
These men are ferocious warriors
and they will show no mercy.
Don't worry! I won't start anything.
Let me handle the negotiations.
So much for not starting something.
Hey, don't look at me!
Don't harm them.
Don't tell me, tell them!
Back off!
We are not here to fight you!
We're here for information.
A man from your village
murdered two Jedi.
We need to know where he is.
What makes you think he's one of ours?
The Jedi Council knows
he's from this village.
We have seen him.
Mother Talzin should know
of his whereabouts.
One of her women took him as a mate.
I apologize for the intrusion, then.
Anakin, kindly release him, please.
Stop!
Let them go.
Who is this Mother Talzin?
She's the leader of an ancient
order of witches, the Nightsisters.
Great. Warrior-like men, witches.
This place is all kinds of fun.
I'm glad you think so.
You have completed
the first stages of your training
and I am sending you
on an assignment to Toydaria.
You will bring me King Katuunko, alive.
Kill all who might interfere.
Yes, my master. It will be done.
I don't know much of Mother Talzin,
but I don't expect to be welcome here.
You never know.
I tend to be popular with the ladies.
Too popular.
We've got company.
Jedi, come with us.
Master Kenobi.
Mother Talzin,
thank you for your hospitality.
I believe you have a question for me.
Yes, you're right.
We've had reports of a Dathomiri male
on the loose.
He's already killed two Jedi.
Perhaps you know who he is?
Master Jedi,
we have no control over the males.
Our clan has been in exile for years.
Don't play innocent with me, Mother.
Everyone in the galaxy knows
females are dominant on this planet.
I do not believe anything happens here
without your clan knowing about it.
To think that the Jedi collect their facts
from mere rumors.
Rumors? You call two dead Jedi rumors?
This thing, this animal,
is extremely dangerous.
If you have any information about
his whereabouts, you must tell us.
Savage. Savage Opress.
Mother?
He is on Toydaria.
Thank you.
The time has come, sister.
You must put your plot against Dooku
into effect now.
He isn't ready, Mother.
He needs more training.
He has to be ready.
Together, the two of you
will be able to eliminate the Count.
But you must act now.
We cannot keep your new assassin
a secret forever.
I will have my revenge.
You will, sister.
You will.
Your Highness,
there is an intruder at the door!
Stop him!
I will not be intimidated.
At last.
- I guess that's what's left of our ship.
- We'll borrow one from the Toydarians.
You ignorant beast!
I told you I wanted him alive!
Forgive me, my master.
That is not the way of the dark side.
- Ventress!
- That's no way to treat your apprentice.
I should know.
Savage, you can make amends
for your mistake
by destroying this witch.
I don't think that will be happening.
Will it, Savage?
Remember where your true loyalties lie.
With you, mistress.
Look, a Separatist Dreadnaught.
The King's murderer must have fled there.
Dooku sent his assassin to exact
his revenge on the Toydarians.
We'll make him pay for it.
Halt! You are now...
Finish him! Now!
Get up! We must defeat him!
Get up!
Kill him! Kill him, you fool!
I can't. He's too powerful.
Your weakness will not be my downfall.
A failed apprentice
makes for a foolish master.
Savage, no!
- We'll take him together.
- Right.
Leaving so soon, Master?
You are no match for me
without the aid of your monster.
Hmm...
That remains to be seen.
As you wish.
Time to end this once and for all.
Commander. Savage Opress is a traitor.
Destroy him.
Roger, roger.
They're not after us!
They're attacking that monster!
You're not supposed to be here.
No sense in hanging around here.
My thoughts exactly.
You have come home to us.
I was betrayed by Ventress.
The Jedi are after me!
I'm not nearly strong enough
to defeat them all!
Calm yourself.
You will be.
I don't understand. Who will teach me?
You have a brother.
A brother?
But all of my kin were killed!
Not all of them.
He lives in the Outer Rim, in exile.
You will find him.
He will teach you
everything you need to learn
to become even more powerful.
My brother.
How?
How will I find him?
This talisman has been imbued
with the power of our clan.
It will be your compass.
You have an important destiny to fulfill,
Savage Opress.
You and your brother.
Go. You will know where to find him.
I will return, Mother.