Clone troopers unite!
As war rages across the galaxy,
the Republic's clone army
strives for victory
against the evil forces of the Separatists.
Bravery, valor, unity,
the lifeblood of victory on the battlefield
and in space.
It all begins on the planet Kamino,
where Jedi General Shaak Ti
oversees the training of clones
with the help of
contracted bounty hunters.
Bred to be perfect soldiers,
these cadets must first be subjected
to intense physical and mental training
before heading off to war.
You're clear! You're clear!
Cover fire!
This is Command. You must break
through enemy lines and take the tower.
- Comlink just relayed orders from...
- We all heard the orders, Echo!
- Stop calling me that.
- Stop repeating every order!
Less yapping, more blasting!
Let's smoke these chrome domes
and move on to the Citadel!
CT-782! You're breaking formation!
Just follow my lead, will you?
He's clearing a path. I'm moving.
Thanks, CT-27-5555. That was close.
It's "Fives"! The name is Fives!
Yeah, five pieces
if you don't keep your head down!
How about we follow orders?
This is our last practice test!
Will you shut up with instructions?
You're not in charge.
This particular unit
seems to have some trouble.
What do you recommend?
Well, I'm no Jedi, so forgive my bluntness,
but I say they fail.
Send them down to maintenance duty
with 99 and the other rejects.
We can't fail them yet.
Remember, this is only a practice test.
And besides, the Citadel course was
constructed to be a difficult challenge.
Although I don't agree with his sentiment,
Bric isn't wrong.
These cadets are far from ready.
I can't hit anything from here.
No! We have to follow orders!
The one they call "Echo"
never adapts to the situation.
CT-782 seems to follow his own path.
He can't do it all alone.
You go, I'll cover you.
- I'm a better shot, you go.
- No, you go!
Look at those two.
Argue on the battlefield, you end up dead.
And the last one.
I surrender. I surrender!
Need I say more?
If these cadets can't get past
their shortsighted selfishness,
they will never come together.
Unity wins war, gentlemen.
Computer, end exercise for Domino Squad.
99, would you please send a cleaning crew
to the training ground?
Yes, mistress, we'll take care of the mess.
You should tell that 99 to drag away
the mess called Domino Squad.
We almost had it this time.
Yeah, and we all look nothing alike either.
Sorry about the mess, 99.
It's okay, boys. Nice try.
So I says to her,
"Baby, you and me could really..."
You've never even met a girl.
You know, you shouldn't worry
because most clones pass.
Yeah, but not all of us, right, shortie?
Guys, we've got to follow orders.
Come on!
I don't know. I think it went rather well.
Quit joking around.
Can we please stop arguing?
Can you stop being droid bait out there?
You're getting in my way.
Actually, our way.
Well, you want to be the best,
then you got to think like it.
And I'm thinking like an ARC trooper.
ARC troopers follow orders.
Care to repeat that, Echo?
Come on, get him, Hevy!
Smack that know-it-all!
Cut it out!
If you two would focus on fighting droids
as much as you do fighting each other,
you might stand a chance out there.
Sorry, Master Chief.
Well, Master Chief,
maybe our problems
come from our training.
I'd rather be taught by a Jedi
than some mercenary bounty hunter.
Jedi don't have the time
to train grunts like you,
that's why they hired me.
Listen, boys, when you were assigned
to me, I had high hopes for you.
Now we're approaching
the end of your training
and you haven't advanced nearly enough.
Even this bad batcher, 99,
has more sense than you guys do,
and he's a maintenance clone!
You... You don't give them enough credit.
You're all a waste of my time.
I understand your concerns, Master Jedi.
Ever since the unfortunate death
of Jango Fett,
we have had to stretch his DNA
to produce more clones.
A Jedi does not feel concern, Lama Su.
However, I have noticed
this unit of clones have been...
Deficient?
My only thought
is for you to search the galaxy
and find a suitable donor
for your future clones.
And what of the clones produced so far?
As you know,
there is no one way to make a clone.
Sometimes our efforts
are less than successful.
Are you suggesting
we just cast off the Domino Squad?
They're living beings, not objects.
You Jedi show too much compassion.
Nevertheless,
as General in charge of training,
the decision on what to do with them
would be yours, Master Jedi.
Gentlemen, who wants
to be an ARC Trooper?
- I do, sir!
You have to pass your final test first.
I want you to meet Commander Colt
of the rancor battalion.
I want you troopers to remember,
we're shoulder-to-shoulder
on those front lines. Brothers.
And sometimes we may quarrel,
but no matter what, we are united.
Rule one, we fight together.
So, who's ready to step up first?
Let's start with the unit
that ran the practice test in record time.
ARC trooper time.
Think he means us, boys?
Bravo Unit, step up.
Well, bravo for Bravo Squad.
Show an ARC trooper how it's done.
Come on, boys,
maybe we can learn something.
Shut up, Echo.
Start the Citadel challenge,
version THX, variable 1138.
Go right! Clankers!
We're better than these guys.
Okay, this is it. Go for it!
He's going to make it.
I'm impressed. You trained them well.
Who's next?
The Domino Squad.
And how are they?
- We can do this, guys.
- All we have to do is follow orders.
Check it out, guys.
Time to watch the Dominos fall.
- They are so much better than us.
- Knock it off.
Begin the program.
Let's not take it easy on them.
They're getting farther than normal.
Maybe so, but they're sloppy.
This is nothing.
Give them their next set of orders
and watch the chaos ensue.
I'm telling you,
these guys just aren't ready.
I flank left, you flank right!
Take it easy, I'm on your side.
Get it, your side, huh?
Pretty unorthodox.
Droid bait, behind you!
Man down!
Forget him! I'm breaking for the Citadel!
Hurry!
Guys, I think he's injured.
Leave him. Come on!
We're gonna pass this time.
Okay, I spoke too soon.
That would be putting it mildly.
Broke formation, disobeyed orders,
and you left a man behind.
You broke rule number one.
I'm sorry, Domino Squad.
This is an automatic failure.
I told you this was going to happen.
We've wasted enough time
on those losers.
Their failure is our failure.
I've made a request to General Shaak Ti
that the Domino Squad be allowed
to repeat the final test.
Why do you care about them?
- Why don't you?
- I care about getting paid.
It's a shame the bounty hunter in you
sees this only as a job.
More like an impossible task.
These cadets will be the finest troopers
we've trained. I have faith in them.
Faith? You can't be serious, El-Les.
We should treat them
as a special challenge, Bric.
We should treat them as failures.
Besides, I've already requested that they
be moved to clean up and maintenance.
That's all they're going to be good for.
Then I guess
the General has a decision to make.
General, may we have a word?
You are here to discuss your squad,
aren't you?
- How did you...
- Jedi, mate.
One doesn't need to be a Jedi
to feel the stress on your mind.
General, we would like to request
a transfer to another squad.
Bravo Squad, perhaps?
I am a Jedi, where the individual
and the group are one and the same,
much like you clones.
Which is why Fives and I
are looking out for each other.
As individuals. But not as a group.
You are where you need to be.
Solve your problems as a whole,
not as individuals.
I have decided to allow you
and the rest of your squad
to take the test again tomorrow.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Near as I can tell,
you're the reason your squad's a failure.
Uh... Well, I'll take that as a compliment.
It's all a big joke to you, right?
Like those little nicknames you and
your clone brothers give each other.
I could think of one for you right now,
sir.
Oh... Funny!
But I think it's all just a cover.
You hate me, don't you?
Oh, no. No, no, no.
How could I hate you for doing your job?
- You're just pushing me, sir.
- No, this is me pushing you.
Come on, clone. Hit me. Hit me, you joker.
Can't take anything seriously, can you?
You're a real cutup, aren't you?
Come on!
- Thank you, sir.
- For what?
For my name. "Cutup."
I like the sound of it.
Out of my sight, cadet.
One way or another,
you'll be out of this army. Count on it.
Hevy, you going somewhere?
Get out of here.
You're going AWOL, aren't you?
Just go back to sleep, 99.
This doesn't concern you.
But you can't do this to your squad.
My squad?
We're nothing but a bad batch. Failures.
Like you.
Yeah, but how can I be a failure when I...
I never even got my chance?
It's a chance you're throwing away.
You're always trying to be the anchor,
Hevy, you know, do it on your own.
Well, maybe you should embrace the fact
that you have a team.
See, I never had that.
But you need them, and they need you.
Why carry such a heavy burden
on your own,
when you have your brothers
at your side, Hevy?
Hevy? Stop calling me that!
We're just numbers, 99. Just numbers.
Not to me.
To me, you've always had a name.
Hey, where's CT-782?
Yeah, where is CT-782?
If he is not here, we will fail.
Not today, brothers.
Today, we pass.
And one more thing, the name's Hevy.
Orders came in clear, mates.
- Nothing to repeat, Echo?
- Not today.
- How's that shoulder treating you?
- I'll live.
We all know what we have to do.
That's it, boys, stay together.
Fives, on your left!
- Thanks, Cutup.
- No problem, brother.
- They seem to be working together.
- Still early. A lot can change.
Keep it up! We're doing great!
- We might actually pass!
- Not so fast, still got the Citadel!
All right. Prep the ascension cables.
Let's scale this thing.
Wait a tick. Where are the cables?
They're not on our belts!
Just when things seemed easy.
Well, we can't scale the face
without them!
We'll fail the test if we can't finish.
What's going on?
Where are their ascension cables?
Must have gotten lost.
What did you do?
I thought you had faith
they'd be the best, right?
Well, the best pass. No matter what.
General, you have to stop this.
This is unfair to the cadets.
Adversity in war is a constant, El-Les.
- But Bric has cheated.
- The enemy won't play fair either.
- So, this is it?
- No, not exactly. Those guns up there.
We can use them
as a step to the next level.
Form a chain
and use each other to scale this face.
- Use the guns? Are you crazy?
- Trust me. I know weapons.
I'm gonna draw their fire,
you guys blast them.
Well, I'll be...
Creative little clones, aren't they?
No unit has shown such ingenuity.
- We did it!
- Yeah!
- I knew we could do it, boys!
- We made it!
Bric, your actions have brought out
the best in these cadets.
Looks like they were well-trained.
Perhaps the finest soldiers I've ever seen.
Well, maybe you were right, El-Les.
Congratulations, you've graduated.
At ease.
Next stop, ARC trooper!
Yeah, how about
we face some combat first?
You were right, you know.
About everything.
I heard
you were quite the leader out there.
No leaders. We are a team.
All of us, 99.
The army's lucky
to have a clone like you, Hevy.
Not as lucky as I am
to have a brother like you.
Well, this is goodbye, I guess.
Hevy ships out and 99 stays here.
We'll see each other again.
I mean, how else am I supposed
to get this back from you?
You deserve it. You're one of us.
Today is your graduation.
From here, you ship out
to fight against the Separatists
and restore peace to the Republic.
Congratulations! You are no longer cadets.
You are troopers.
May the Force be with you.
Attention!
Helmets on!