Blinded by the dark side!
The Jedi Council
has begun to unravel the mystery
of how the clone army was created.
And now fear the Sith Lord,
Count Dooku was behind it.
Master Yoda searches for answers.
And during deep meditation,
he is able to contact
the spirit of Qui-Gon Jinn,
who reveals to Yoda that he must
manifest his consciousness after death
if he is to preserve the Jedi Order.
Now, we find Master Yoda
deep in space
searching for a path to
ones who will teach him
all he does not know of the Force.
The place Qui-Gon spoke of
I believe this is.
So, blocking our scanners the gas is.
But inside a planet may be. Hmm.
Sense it I do.
Controlling this are you?
Let the Force guide I will.
Hmm, awake again you are,
my little friend.
Where we are I'm not sure.
But strong with the Force this place is.
There you see?
From inside the planet life emanates.
Here, nothing your scanners can see?
Hmm?
Need this, I will not.
No, wait here you must.
A journey for me alone this is.
Safer here you are, my friend.
Yoda.
Who is there?
Traveled far I have,
looking for those who can teach me.
The question is,
are you worthy of being taught?
You are late.
We have been
waiting for you, Master Yoda.
Late? How did you know coming I was?
We watch and study all who are
strong with the Force in the universe.
Now come, if we are to begin.
Cousins, I have a guest.
You should not
have brought him before us!
Nonsense, he is
full of the Force. Can you not feel it?
Why is he here?
Why are you here?
Told I was to learn to from you.
That show me you could
how to manifest my life after death.
That's impossible!
He will fail the great gift.
He will disappoint us.
He will disappoint himself.
No. No, I do not see that.
His destiny is
already set. It is not for us to decide.
But why him?
He is to
teach one that will save
the universe from a great imbalance.
For this, the great gift will be his.
He has no idea
what he seeks!
The responsibility he will have!
Understand I do not.
Guide me I know you will.
And do you
realize what you must do?
What you must face?
No.
Good. Then you won't be afraid.
Do I have
our blessing that the training can begin?
It is so.
We are one and one is all.
Do you come to
us with only good intention
and light in your heart?
I do. Yes.
Then the blessing I give,
and the training will begin.
Disappoint us not, little green one.
What is this place?
All that
surrounds us is the foundation of life.
The birthplace of what your science
calls "midi-chlorians."
The foundation of what connects
the living Force and the cosmic Force.
When a living thing dies, all is renewed.
Life passes from the living Force
into the cosmic Force
and becomes one with it.
One powers the other.
One is renewed by the other.
This I know.
Come with me.
At death, in order for you to preserve
your identity,
you must know yourself, your true self,
and then let go.
On that island dwells
all that remains unconquered,
what in your existence some call evil,
otherwise known as fear.
All which must be finally overcome
before the journey can be taken.
Free yourself you must.
A Jedi Master I am.
Know all that dwells within I do.
Mastered my weaknesses
and conquered my fears I have.
Have you?
You must face your evil on that island
and defeat it.
Yoda.
Show yourself.
Yoda hates me, yes?
Yoda plays not with me anymore!
Yoda thinks me not worthy.
Yoda recognizes you not!
See not
what is inside Yoda?
I choose not to give you power.
And yet you spend
your days in the decadence of war.
And with that, I grow inside you.
Know your true self.
Face me now, or I will devour you.
Part of me you are not!
Part of you I am.
Part of all that lives.
Why do you hate
what gives you power?
Yoda thinks me not worthy.
Recognize you I do.
Huh?
Part of me you are, yes.
But power over me you have not.
Through patience and training,
it is I who control you.
Control over me you have not.
My dark side you are.
Reject you I do.
You have
conquered your hubris.
Now face the temptations you must.
Powerful the creature was.
What you faced was a reflection of
your hubris and
the shadow of your soul.
And yet, clear I thought I was.
The beast is you
and you are the beast.
To deny it simply gives it power.
Now I see.
Simple the answer was.
Deep in your core you felt that
we had nothing to teach you.
But you must trust in our teachings
if you are to succeed.
Ready I am for what comes next.
You must enter the valley of extinction.
Pass through without emotion,
without attachment.
For you will see all our faces there
and they will seduce you.
For we are Confusion.
Anger.
Sadness.
Joy.
And Serenity.
Stop! Stop!
- No! No! No!
Master Yoda. Please, help me.
I'm dying.
What has happened here, Padawan?
- Who has done this?
The Sith.
How?
You told me I would finish my training
and become a Jedi,
but the council expelled me.
Why would you do that?
Will I still become one with the Force
when I die?
Master, will I be a Jedi?
Padawan? Padawan. Ahsoka.
No! No! No!
Not strong enough I was. No!
Failed I have. Failed them all.
Master Yoda.
Let me take you away
from your confusion,
your anger, your sadness!
Come with me
and you will never know pain.
Never know sadness.
Close your eyes,
and I will guide you.
The temple is beautiful,
isn't it, Master Yoda?
Yes, so peaceful,
as it was before the war.
War? Oh, there is no war here, Master.
Only peace and tranquility.
No war?
Ah, Master Yoda.
Master Dooku was just telling us
a tale of when he was your Padawan.
Really quite a humorous story.
Count Dooku!
Yes, Master.
I was telling them the tale of when you
faced the giant terentatek on Kashyyyk.
What a terrible beast it was.
Yes, yes.
I remember.
We had wonderful adventures,
Master Yoda and I.
I'm sure we'd all love to hear more,
but it's time to join the others.
Coming, Master?
No, wrong this is.
Lies, these images are!
Lies!
Dead, I know you to be!
On Naboo, died you did, Qui-Gon.
And a traitor you are,
my old Padawan.
No! An illusion this is!
A falsehood!
You have done well.
But to succeed,
your life must be
spent learning, practicing.
Please. Show me who you are.
See your face I must.
Nowyou see.
We have achieved what you seek,
and live between the realms.
Dead you are?
Yes.
How shall I complete my training?
You must face the ultimate test.
The ultimate seduction.
The gravest ofjourneys.
You will travel to Moraband...
Moraband?
Journey through
the ancient homeworld of the Sith.
Face all that you fear.
All that haunts your soul!
- Hello, my friend.
No, no.
One more place to visit we have.
A strange place I have come from,
but finished not what I came for.
Set a course for Moraband.
Yes, brave we must be.
The worst, I fear, is yet to come.