Peace shattered.
Once promising negotiations
between the Republic and the Separatists
are now in shambles,
following a droid suicide bombing
on the capital city-planet of Coruscant.
As fear and anger prevail,
the Senate overwhelmingly passes a bill
to deregulate the banks,
opening the gateway to additional troops
and an increase in fighting.
Members of the Senate, please. Please!
How dare they!
They attack, and now they want peace?
Chancellor Palpatine,
may I remind the senators that the peace
proposal was made prior to their assault.
That only highlights its insincerity.
Chancellor Palpatine, in light of
this unprovoked attack on Coruscant,
and the vulnerabilities it raises,
I propose the Republic purchase
an additional five million clone troopers.
The Republic is already operating
in deep debt.
How do you propose
we pay for these additional troops?
My people are drafting an emergency
appropriations bill that would raise funds.
From the Banking Clan?
Yes, of course.
Do you have an alternate means of paying?
One alternative might be
to stop the war, not escalate it.
Traitor!
- Traitor!
Whoever attacked the power grid
wants us to continue the fight.
It's a calculated attempt
to destroy the peace process.
Not everyone
in the Confederacy wants this.
I know this for a fact.
You have Separatist friends, Senator?
- Whose side are you on?
- Where's your loyalty?
We will not stand for this!
Please. The young senator from Naboo
makes a point.
There is no need to...
We have just received a message
from our opponent, Count Dooku.
Your Republic forces have carried
out a barbaric attack on our people,
and among the deaths
was the very sponsor of the peace accord,
Senator Mina Bonteri.
What? No!
With her needless death,
I must formally withdraw the proposal
for peace offered by our Senate.
We must not show weakness.
Thank you, Teckla.
Yes, my lady.
I can't believe it.
I just can't believe the Republic
would target Senator Bonteri.
She was the only one
willing to stand up for peace.
You shouldn't believe it.
The Republic's spies are reporting
that Senator Bonteri
was murdered by Dooku's thugs.
That message to the Senate was a ploy
to disguise his true actions.
I am so sorry, Padmé.
If your friend met with a violent end
because of her politics,
let's make sure
her courageous effort wasn't in vain.
What can we do?
For one, defeat this bill.
Can we really win this war
with the troops that we have?
Let's hope we don't have to.
I'll start lining up support,
but I'll need ammunition.
We can't afford ammunition, remember?
I joke.
Go to the Banking Clan
and see how much interest
they're going to charge for the loan.
The more I know about what
the exact costs of this bill will be,
the better I can make my case to defeat it.
All right. Let's go, Uncle.
You know these Banking Clan people.
Plus, you owe me
for telling such a bad joke.
We will lend the Republic
at our standard interest rate
of 25%.
What?
25%?
That's outright theft.
Your previous arrangement with
the Republic was 10%.
Please, please.
That was before deregulation.
The same rules don't apply, my dear.
The Separatists don't seem to mind
a rate hike.
In fact, they just secured a loan
to fund an additional
three million battle droids.
They will wipe us out.
You would let Dooku do that?
You live on Coruscant, too.
We have no stake in this war, Senator.
You know that.
War is distasteful to all of us.
25% interest?
That's a lot of credits.
The interest alone
could completely bankrupt the Republic.
As it is, social services have suffered
because of this war.
Education, infrastructure, healthcare.
If we go deeper into debt, the basic
needs of our people will evaporate.
This is good.
It is?
Clearly, taking out a loan
on such obscene terms
would essentially destroy the Republic,
regardless of the outcome of the war.
We only need to sway
another handful of senators,
as long as they don't
buckle to the threats.
What threats?
Some members have received messages
warning them not to vote against the bill.
Considering what's happened
to your friend Bonteri,
they're frightened.
A mandatory
blackout is in progress.
All citizens report
to the designated safe area.
A mandatory blackout is in progress.
All citizens report
to the designated safe area.
No! No!
Can't you all see this
bill is shortsighted?
Millions of clones won't win this war.
The only winner will be the Banking Clan.
They want to pass this bill so badly,
they're using scare tactics to sway votes.
I am not intimidated, Senator Amidala.
Then why are you voting
for additional troops?
I happen to believe more clones
are precisely what we need.
And my caucus agrees with me.
I'm sorry.
Uncle Ono, what happened?
Two thugs jumped me, but I am fine.
This is outrageous.
Something has to be done.
Padmé, this will not change my mind.
No matter what,
I will vote against the bill.
I see Senator Amidala hasn't given up
her crusade.
She doesn't have the votes, my Lord.
We've taken care of 20 senators.
It may be time to send her a message
as well.
You want us to have a talk with her?
No.
I think something special
is called for in Senator Amidala's case.
We're all ears, boss.
Take her out of the game.
As long as senators are being threatened
and attacked,
I'm afraid we don't stand a chance.
Intimidation won't work on everyone.
Senator Farr is proof of that.
Even so, we're still at least
six votes short of a majority.
And you saw how effective
my plea was today.
Some minds can't be altered
no matter what they hear.
From my experience,
it depends a great deal
on who's sending the message.
And what are you thinking?
Bail, you're the finest public speaker
I know.
If anyone can convince the Senate
that voting for this bill
will bankrupt the Republic,
both financially and spiritually, it's you.
It will be dangerous.
I urge you to speak before the full Senate.
I'll need some time to prepare.
Good.
In the meantime, I'll pay another visit
to those still undecided.
I'll be parked just over there, my lady.
Thank you. This way, Uncle.
What does ideology matter at this point?
Is it worth being beaten to death?
Look at what they did to you.
These wounds will heal.
But what about the millions
who are dying in this war?
Who, the clones?
We created them for just that purpose.
They are people.
The people I care about
are my constituents,
the ones who put me in office.
And when was the last time
you ever spoke to your people?
Probably the same time you did.
Or you, Senator.
Senator Christo, please.
Is there anything we can do to get you
to change your mind?
Where does Senator Organa stand
on all this?
Why isn't he here?
Senator Organa is preparing
to speak before the full Senate.
Senator Organa?
Hmm.
I'll listen to what he has to say.
So you are open to voting with us?
I said I'll listen to what he has to say.
Well, it's better than a no.
I'm sure when Christo and the others hear
what Bail has to say,
they will vote our way.
Can I give you a ride?
My driver's only a block away.
I think I'd like to walk.
But Padmé.
Don't worry, Uncle Ono.
I can take care of myself.
Plus, I can use the fresh air.
Just be careful.
Oh, you're gonna love it!
Put your hands up.
Arrest these bounty hunters.
We'll take care of this, miss.
Drop your weapons
and come with us quietly.
Quietly?
Where's my driver? Where's my...
Hey, my ride!
My eye!
Land the vehicle!
That is a stolen vehicle.
Ugh!
Those bounty hunters
were trying to kill me!
I am a senator!
I demand that you arrest them.
Get your hands in the air.
Ouch!
Don't you think you should
report this to the Jedi Council?
There's nothing they can do.
I know who did it.
They were bounty hunters
paid to stop me from
voting against the troop increase.
What has happened to democracy?
And why doesn't anyone seem to care?
Well, you do.
Forgive me, my lady.
You're not like most politicians.
If only that were enough, Teckla.
Well, you actually talk to the people.
People like me.
Goodnight, my lady.
Teckla.
Tell me. How is your family?
They are fine.
How is the war affecting them?
It hasn't been easy.
And it's only getting worse.
How?
Please, tell me.
Tell me how it's getting worse.
You're not gonna get away
like your lady friend, Senator.
Senator!
Medic!
Oh! Padmé!
What is it?
You must come quickly.
You need to see something.
Bail! What happened?
Padmé.
Senator, you need to lie down.
My speech, my speech.
The Senate is expecting me.
- Is there any way...
- I'm sorry.
He's in no condition to even stand.
We need to take him to the hospital.
Of course. Take him at once.
The speech.
Padmé, you must address the Senate.
Only you can do this.
Perhaps we should
get the vote started.
I told Senator Organa
I'd allow him to speak.
We have waited long enough.
I agree with Senator Orn Free Taa.
Let's vote.
You must give the speech in his place.
But they're expecting to hear
from the great Bail Organa.
He carries a certain weight.
He's seen as a voice of reason.
You are very respected.
As a partisan.
I've been against this bill from day one.
If they didn't listen to me before,
why would they listen now?
Because you do listen.
You understand
what the people are going through.
Please.
Your people are waiting for you.
Let us now vote on Senator Burtoni's bill
to fund five million additional clones.
The opposition to this bill
must be allowed to speak first.
Unfortunately,
Senator Organa is nowhere to be found.
I will speak on his behalf.
Senator Amidala will be permitted
to speak.
Teckla Minnau...
Teckla is one of my aides.
Like so many of the people
that we tell ourselves we're here to serve,
Teckla lives in a district
that rarely has electricity and running
water as a result of the war.
Her children can now only bathe
every two weeks,
and they have no light
in which to read or study at night.
The Republic has always funded
these basic services,
but now, there are those who would divert
the money to the war,
with no thought for what
the people need to survive.
If not for people like
Teckla and her children,
who are we fighting for?
My people, your people, all of our people.
This war is meant to save them from
suffering, not increase it.
I support our brave soldiers,
whether they come from
the clone factories,
or from any of the thousands of systems
loyal to the Republic.
But if we continue
to impoverish our people,
it is not on the battlefield
where Dooku will defeat us,
but in our own homes.
Therefore, it is our duty
and our responsibility
to preserve the lives of those around us
by defeating this bill!
Well done, Padmé!
Isn't it remarkable that one can have
all the power in the galaxy,
and yet the words of a single senator
can sway the thoughts of millions?
What do you plan to do about this?
For now, we must adhere to the
principles of our democracy.
We must let the wheels of the Senate turn.