Republic forces in retreat!
While rescuing General Aayla Secura
from certain defeat,
Anakin Skywalker
has been seriously injured.
After a narrow escape,
our heroes crash-landed
on the remote world of Maridun.
Stranded, and with no way
to contact the Republic,
the Jedi receive medical aid
from the peaceful Lurmen colonists.
But even on this tiny planet,
the war threatens to follow the Jedi.
Commander Bly, we've got company.
- Friendlies?
- Negative, sir.
A droid ship...
coming straight our way.
Acknowledged.
Get back here.
- General?
- Yes, Commander?
We've got a Separatist ship
incoming.
This is neutral space.
It won't be neutral for long,
not if the Separatists have their way.
- Help me up.
- Don't struggle.
I'm sorry,
but you're still too injured to move.
What menace have you brought
to our village now, Jedi?
Father, you can't blame them.
He's right. The Separatists
don't even know we're here.
And they can't know.
We've got to hide.
Your presence here endangers us.
You must leave
before your enemies find you.
But you'll need our help.
You can't fight them alone.
We will not fight them at all.
We would rather die
than to kill others.
You're going to surrender?
- But how can you--
- Ahsoka, stop.
If the Lurmen want to remain neutral,
we won't force them into war.
See to it that they leave.
I must see
what our new visitors want.
Take it easy, sir.
We'll assist you.
I am General Lok Durd
of the Separatist alliance.
I am Tee Watt Kaa,
leader of this colony.
- What do you--
- You are now under the protection
of the Separatist alliance.
I congratulate you
on your good fortune.
Thank you, but we enjoyed good fortune
well before your arrival.
We are a peaceful people, General.
I do not condone your presence here.
Then stand aside.
I would like to inspect
my new colony.
Ransack this dung heap.
Why are they tearing apart
our homes?
We've done nothing to them!
Violence...
that's what those droids
are programmed for.
Can't we do anything?
No, and if we are discovered,
all of the Lurmen will be slaughtered.
We'll be okay
if we make it to the tall grasses.
There is no evidence of any weapons
or Republic contraband, General.
In the future, we may conduct
more periodic searches
like this one
in order to maintain security.
Because we are
such an obvious threat to you.
We'll offer no resistance.
Your species is smarter
than you appear.
Father, are you okay?
At least the Jedi escaped.
Yes, but they nearly brought harm
to our entire village.
But now, thanks to you,
we're safe to grovel before every
petty tyrant who enters our system.
You would mock our very way of life?
I have just ensured
we will have peace.
Yes, but for the moment,
and at what price?
Are you not concerned
about the Jedi at all?
I have no quarrel with the Jedi,
but we cannot help them
without being drawn into their war.
Tub, track the Jedi.
Follow them
and make sure they get off world.
You know, I can't figure those villagers
not wanting to fight.
No pride, I guess.
I call it no courage.
Sometimes it takes courage to stick
to one's beliefs, young Padawan,
as any Jedi well knows.
We need to find a ship,
and I think the only one around here
belongs to the Separatists.
We know they have a landing ship.
They might have a shuttle.
Sir, you talking about stealing
from one of the clankers?
- Count me in.
- We need to find them first.
I think we just did.
Blast it!
Jam its signal!
After it!
I'm fine. Just go!
- Which way did it go?
- This way. Hurry!
We can't catch it
if it gets out in the open.
- I wonder where it was headed.
- Maybe we can see them from up there.
I hope you're feeling better,
Master,
'cause look what we found.
I'm getting stronger
all the time, Snips.
But I'm not sure
I'm ready for that.
That shuttle is
our ticket off this rock.
It's not gonna be easy, sir.
There don't seem to be any flaws
in their security line.
Apparently,
the Separatists have a new toy.
- See if you can get a closer look.
- Yes, sir.
I'll go with you, Commander.
Is the defoliator capsule ready?
Today is a grand day
for the Separatist cause.
We test a new weapon
of my own design
which is capable
of catastrophic destruction.
A weapon which will destroy
organic matter
but leave machines
unharmed.
But first,
we need two volunteers.
The volunteers are...
...you and you.
- Me?
Go to that ridge.
- Roger, roger.
Stay down, boys.
Count Dooku,
I have located a world
in which we can test my...
Excuse me.
...our new weapon.
I hope it turns out
to be worth the expense.
You may proceed.
Yes, my Lord.
Ready?
Roger, roger.
Aim.
Fire!
Should we take cover?
No, idiot.
That is not even gonna hit us.
That's some toy.
It took out every living thing.
As you can see,
the landscape has been destroyed,
and the droids are undamaged.
Impressive.
But now, we need to know
how effective
this weapon will be against...
living creatures.
Of course.
I specifically chose this planet
because it is inhabited.
The colonists will make
excellent test subjects.
Proceed, then.
I eagerly await the results.
Prepare to move out!
Where are they off to now?
They must be going back
to the Lurmen village.
There's nothing else
in that direction.
Those villagers
won't stand a chance.
First we'll take out
the droids' communication station.
After we get a shuttle,
we'll go back and help them.
But Tee Watt Kaa said
he doesn't need our help.
There's a difference
between pulling innocents into a war
and leaving them to extinction.
Tell Wag Too
that the Separatists are returning.
Hey, what was that?
Get to the door.
I'll handle the droids.
Check the exterior.
We cannot have any surprises
for the General.
4724, how does the west end
check out?
What the...?
The Separatists are on the march.
They're returning to our village.
They did not attack us before.
There's no reason to think
they will this time.
Father, they wouldn't be
coming back here
unless they intended to do us harm.
This is war!
But not our war.
We've done nothing to provoke them,
and we will not.
That is their way.
So we will just lay down
and be slaughtered?
Father, even if we don't fight
the Separatists,
we must defend ourselves!
Mounting a defense
is still engaging in battle.
If we sacrifice our beliefs,
we're no better than they are.
Our philosophy has helped us
to survive for generations,
and we will not change
our morals now or ever.
- Shield generators, sir.
- Let's take 'em with us.
Everyone,
please, please listen.
The Separatists will be here
in moments.
What are you doing here?
I told you not to return.
I'm afraid the Separatists don't care
whether you're in the war or not.
We need to get you to safety
before they arrive.
We will not abandon our homes.
But they've got a new weapon.
It'll burn this place to a crisp.
Is this what all of you really want?
If it is our destiny to be destroyed
in your war,
so be it.
Droids inbound.
We've got eight minutes tops.
Come on, guys. Let's get
these shield generators in place!
When Count Dooku sees
how successful
my weapon is
against civilian targets,
I will no doubt be promoted
to a more...
...substantial position
within the alliance.
Right.
Well, the villagers appear
to have put some pods together
- in a barrier around the village.
- Pods?
How quaint.
Jedi?
What are they doing out here?
Halt!
Pray stop what you're doing.
Stop building that wall.
- I did not ask you to defend us.
- This battle is inevitable.
You can stand by your beliefs,
but let us stand by ours.
Thank you
for what you're trying to do.
I'm sorry, but I cannot help.
My father is very...
...strong willed and set in tradition.
Many others agree with me,
but we were raised
under a very strict code.
We must respect it,
even if we don't agree.
- They're holding position.
- They're not going to charge us,
not if they can hit us
from long range first.
But if we can withstand that weapon,
we'll draw them in.
Prepare to fire!
Good-bye, Jedi.
Fire!
Incoming!
Power the shields!
Now they'll have to get their hands
dirty and meet us face-to-face.
Squad one, prepare to charge.
Prepare to charge.
Charge!
That's a lot of clankers.
We got to stop them
before they get through that shield.
Five, four,
three,
two,
one,
zero.
Sir, the first squad
has been destroyed.
Squad two and three, attack!
- That wasn't so tough.
- That was just the first wave.
Snips, get back to the village!
I'll take care of the new weapon.
That's it. We have to retreat!
Take cover.
They've breached the shield!
They're taking out
the shield generators.
We have to do something.
Their shield is down.
Launch another shell.
Sir, there's a Jedi
heading right for us.
Then blast him, you idiot!
No survivors.
Wag Too, what are you doing?
- We're going to help.
- I forbid this.
What more would you have them do
before we are allowed
to defend ourselves?
- But--
- We have to do this.
Help!
I'll be defoliated!
There goes my promotion.
The weapon has been disabled.
Copy that, General.
- Thank you, Wag Too.
- Thank you.
Our village would certainly
have been destroyed
without your protection.
Father,
I was just offering the Jedi
our thanks.
Perhaps we do owe you thanks.
But I still wonder,
at what cost?